{
	"description": "Kanji readings for JLPT N1-5",
	"deck": [
		{ "question": "お互い", "answers": [ "おたがい" ], "comment": "(n) mutual/reciprocal/each other" },
		{ "question": "お代わり", "answers": [ "おかわり" ], "comment": "(n) second helping/another cup" },
		{ "question": "お使い", "answers": [ "おつかい" ], "comment": "errand" },
		{ "question": "お供", "answers": [ "おとも" ], "comment": "(n,vs) attendant/companion" },
		{ "question": "お兄さん", "answers": [ "おにいさん" ], "comment": "(n) (hon) older brother/(vocative) 'Mister?'" },
		{ "question": "お参り", "answers": [ "おまいり" ], "comment": "(n,vs) worship/shrine visit" },
		{ "question": "お土産", "answers": [ "おみやげ" ], "comment": "(n) present/souvenir" },
		{ "question": "お姉さん", "answers": [ "おねえさん" ], "comment": "(n) (hon) older sister/(vocative) 'Miss?'" },
		{ "question": "お嬢さん", "answers": [ "おじょうさん" ], "comment": "(n) (1) (hon) daughter/(2) young lady" },
		{ "question": "お子さん", "answers": [ "おこさん" ], "comment": "(n) (someone else's) child" },
		{ "question": "お宅", "answers": [ "おたく" ], "comment": "(n) (pol) your house/your home/you" },
		{ "question": "お宮", "answers": [ "おみや" ], "comment": "(n) Shinto shrine" },
		{ "question": "お弁当", "answers": [ "おべんとう" ], "comment": "(n) boxed lunch" },
		{ "question": "お手上げ", "answers": [ "おてあげ" ], "comment": "(n) all over/given in/given up hope/bring to knees" },
		{ "question": "お手伝いさん", "answers": [ "おてつだいさん" ], "comment": "(n) maid" },
		{ "question": "お手洗い", "answers": [ "おてあらい" ], "comment": "toilet/restroom/lavatory/bathroom (US)" },
		{ "question": "お昼", "answers": [ "おひる" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n) lunch/noon" },
		{ "question": "お母さん", "answers": [ "おかあさん" ], "comment": "(n) (hon) mother" },
		{ "question": "お父さん", "answers": [ "おとうさん" ], "comment": "(n) (hon) father" },
		{ "question": "お産", "answers": [ "おさん" ], "comment": "(n) (giving) birth" },
		{ "question": "お皿", "answers": [ "おさら" ], "comment": "(n) plate/dish" },
		{ "question": "お礼", "answers": [ "おれい" ], "comment": "(n) thanking/expression of gratitude" },
		{ "question": "お祝い", "answers": [ "おいわい" ], "comment": "(n) congratulation/celebration" },
		{ "question": "お茶", "answers": [ "おちゃ" ], "comment": "(n) tea (green)" },
		{ "question": "お菓子", "answers": [ "おかし" ], "comment": "(n) confections/sweets/candy" },
		{ "question": "お見舞い", "answers": [ "おみまい" ], "comment": "(n) calling on someone who is ill/enquiry" },
		{ "question": "お酒", "answers": [ "おさけ" ], "comment": "(n) alcohol/sake (rice wine)" },
		{ "question": "お金", "answers": [ "おかね" ], "comment": "(n) money" },
		{ "question": "ご存じ", "answers": [ "ごぞんじ" ], "comment": "(n) knowing/acquaintance" },
		{ "question": "ジェット機", "answers": [ "ジェットき" ], "comment": "(n) jet aeroplane" },
		{ "question": "一", "answers": [ "いち" ], "comment": "(num) one" },
		{ "question": "一つ", "answers": [ "ひとつ" ], "comment": "(n) one" },
		{ "question": "一人", "answers": [ "ひとり" ], "comment": "(n) one person" },
		{ "question": "一人一人", "answers": [ "ひとりひとり" ], "comment": "(n-t) one by one/each/one at a time" },
		{ "question": "一休み", "answers": [ "ひとやすみ" ], "comment": "(n) a rest" },
		{ "question": "一体", "answers": [ "いったい" ], "comment": "(adv,n) (1) one object/one body/(2) what on earth?/really?/(3) generally" },
		{ "question": "一切", "answers": [ "いっさい" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n) all/everything/without exception/the whole/entirely/absolutely" },
		{ "question": "一別", "answers": [ "いちべつ" ], "comment": "(n) parting" },
		{ "question": "一同", "answers": [ "いちどう" ], "comment": "(n) all present/all concerned/all of us" },
		{ "question": "一変", "answers": [ "いっぺん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) complete change/about-face" },
		{ "question": "一定", "answers": [ "いってい" ], "comment": "(adj-no,n,vs) fixed/settled/definite/uniform/regularized/defined/standardized/certain/prescribed" },
		{ "question": "一家", "answers": [ "いっか" ], "comment": "(n) a house/a home/a family/a household/one's family/one's folks/a style" },
		{ "question": "一層", "answers": [ "いっそう" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n) much more/still more/all the more" },
		{ "question": "一帯", "answers": [ "いったい" ], "comment": "(n) a region/a zone/the whole place" },
		{ "question": "一度", "answers": [ "いちど" ], "comment": "(n-adv) once/one time/on one occasion" },
		{ "question": "一度に", "answers": [ "いちどに" ], "comment": "(adv) all at once" },
		{ "question": "一律", "answers": [ "いちりつ" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n-adv,n) evenness/uniformity/monotony/equality" },
		{ "question": "一心", "answers": [ "いっしん" ], "comment": "(adv,n) one mind/wholeheartedness/the whole heart" },
		{ "question": "一応", "answers": [ "いちおう" ], "comment": "(adv) once/tentatively/in outline/for the time being" },
		{ "question": "一息", "answers": [ "ひといき" ], "comment": "(n) puffy/a breath/a pause/an effort" },
		{ "question": "一括", "answers": [ "いっかつ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) all together/batch/one lump/one bundle/summing up" },
		{ "question": "一挙に", "answers": [ "いっきょに" ], "comment": "(adv) at a stroke/with a single swoop" },
		{ "question": "一斉", "answers": [ "いっせい" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n) simultaneous/all at once" },
		{ "question": "一方", "answers": [ "いっぽう" ], "comment": "(conj,n-adv,n) (1) on the other hand/one side/one way/one direction/one party/the other party/(2) meanwhile/(3) only/simple/in turn" },
		{ "question": "一日", "answers": [ "いちにち","ついたち" ], "comment": "(n) (1) first of month" },
		{ "question": "一旦", "answers": [ "いったん" ], "comment": "(adv) once/for a moment/one morning/temporarily" },
		{ "question": "一昨年", "answers": [ "いっさくねん" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n-t) year before last" },
		{ "question": "一昨日", "answers": [ "いっさくじつ" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n-t) day before yesterday" },
		{ "question": "一時", "answers": [ "いちじ" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n) moment/time" },
		{ "question": "一月", "answers": [ "ひとつき" ], "comment": "one month" },
		{ "question": "一概に", "answers": [ "いちがいに" ], "comment": "(adv) unconditionally/as a rule" },
		{ "question": "一様", "answers": [ "いちよう" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) uniformity/evenness/similarity/equality/impartiality" },
		{ "question": "一段と", "answers": [ "いちだんと" ], "comment": "(adv) greater/more/further/still more" },
		{ "question": "一気", "answers": [ "いっき" ], "comment": "(n) (abbr) drink!(said repeatedly as a party cheer)" },
		{ "question": "一流", "answers": [ "いちりゅう" ], "comment": "(n) first class/top grade/school (of art)/foremost/top-notch/unique" },
		{ "question": "一生", "answers": [ "いっしょう" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n-t) whole life/a lifetime/all through life/one existence/a generation/an age/the whole world/the era" },
		{ "question": "一生懸命", "answers": [ "いっしょうけんめい" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n-adv,n) very hard/with utmost effort/with all one's might" },
		{ "question": "一目", "answers": [ "いちもく", "ひとめ" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n-t) a glance/a look/a glimpse" },
		{ "question": "一瞬", "answers": [ "いっしゅん" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n-t) a moment/an instant" },
		{ "question": "一種", "answers": [ "いっしゅ" ], "comment": "(adv,n) a species/a kind/a variety" },
		{ "question": "一筋", "answers": [ "ひとすじ" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) a line/earnestly/blindly/straightforwardly" },
		{ "question": "一緒", "answers": [ "いっしょ" ], "comment": "(adv,n) together/meeting/company" },
		{ "question": "一致", "answers": [ "いっち" ], "comment": "(n,vs) (1) coincidence/agreement/union/match/(2) conformity/consistency/(3) co-operation" },
		{ "question": "一般", "answers": [ "いっぱん" ], "comment": "(adj-no,n) general/liberal/universal/ordinary/average" },
		{ "question": "一見", "answers": [ "いっけん" ], "comment": "(adv,n,vs) (1) a look/a glimpse/glance/(2) first meeting" },
		{ "question": "一言", "answers": [ "ひとこと" ], "comment": "(n) single word" },
		{ "question": "一通り", "answers": [ "ひととおり" ], "comment": "(adj-no,n) ordinary/usual/in general/briefly" },
		{ "question": "一連", "answers": [ "いちれん" ], "comment": "(n) a series/a chain/a ream (of paper)" },
		{ "question": "一部分", "answers": [ "いちぶぶん" ], "comment": "(n) a part/a portion/a section" },
		{ "question": "一面", "answers": [ "いちめん" ], "comment": "(adv,n) one side/one phase/front page/the other hand/the whole surface" },
		{ "question": "一頃", "answers": [ "ひところ" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n-t) once/some time ago" },
		{ "question": "丁寧", "answers": [ "ていねい" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) polite/courteous/careful/care/kind/close/thorough/conscientious" },
		{ "question": "七", "answers": [ "しち","なな" ], "comment": "(num) seven" },
		{ "question": "七つ", "answers": [ "ななつ" ], "comment": "(n) seven" },
		{ "question": "七日", "answers": [ "なのか" ], "comment": "(n-adv) seven days/the seventh day (of the month)" },
		{ "question": "万", "answers": [ "まん" ], "comment": "(adv,num) 10,000/ten thousand/myriads/all/everything" },
		{ "question": "万一", "answers": [ "まんいち" ], "comment": "(adv,n) by some chance/by some possibility/if by any chance/10E4:1 odds" },
		{ "question": "万人", "answers": [ "ばんにん" ], "comment": "(n) all people/everybody/10000 people" },
		{ "question": "万年筆", "answers": [ "まんねんひつ" ], "comment": "(n) fountain pen" },
		{ "question": "万歳", "answers": [ "ばんざい" ], "comment": "strolling comic dancer" },
		{ "question": "万能", "answers": [ "ばんのう" ], "comment": "(adj-no,n) all-purpose/almighty/omnipotent" },
		{ "question": "丈", "answers": [ "たけ" ], "comment": "(prt) (uk) only/just/as" },
		{ "question": "丈夫", "answers": [ "じょうぶ" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) (1) hero/gentleman/warrior/manly person/(2) good health/robustness/strong/solid/durable" },
		{ "question": "三", "answers": [ "さん" ], "comment": "(num) three" },
		{ "question": "三つ", "answers": [ "みっつ" ], "comment": "(n) three" },
		{ "question": "三味線", "answers": [ "しゃみせん" ], "comment": "(n) three-stringed Japanese guitar/shamisen" },
		{ "question": "三日", "answers": [ "みっか" ], "comment": "(n) three days/the third day (of the month)" },
		{ "question": "三日月", "answers": [ "みかづき" ], "comment": "(n) new moon/crescent moon" },
		{ "question": "三角", "answers": [ "さんかく" ], "comment": "(n) triangle/triangular" },
		{ "question": "上", "answers": [ "うえ","うわ","かみ","じょう" ], "comment": "(n,pref,suf) (1) first volume/(2) superior quality/(3) governmental/imperial/top/best/high class/going up/presenting/showing/aboard a ship or vehicle/from the standpoint of/as a matter of (fact)" },
		{ "question": "上がり", "answers": [ "あがり" ], "comment": "(n,suf) (1) ascent/rise/slope/(2) freshly-drawn green tea (esp. in sushi shops)/(3) advance income/crop yield/(4) death/spinning/completion/stop/finish/(5) after (rain)/ex (official, etc.)" },
		{ "question": "上げる", "answers": [ "あげる" ], "comment": "(v1) to give/to raise/to elevate/to fly (kites)/to praise/to increase/to advance/to promote/to vomit/to usher in/to admit/to send (to school)/to offer/to present/to leave with/to finish/to arrange (expenses)/to observe/to perform/to quote/to mention/to bear (a child)/to improve (talents)/to do up (the hair)/to arrest/to engage/to fry/(rains) to stop" },
		{ "question": "上り", "answers": [ "のぼり" ], "comment": "(n) up-train (going to Tokyo)/ascent" },
		{ "question": "上る", "answers": [ "あがる","のぼる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to rise/to ascend/to be promoted/to go up/to climb/to go to (the capital)/to add up to/to advance (in price)/to sail up/to come up (on the agenda)" },
		{ "question": "上下", "answers": [ "じょうげ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) high and low/up and down/unloading and loading/praising and blaming" },
		{ "question": "上京", "answers": [ "じょうきょう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) proceeding to the capital (Tokyo)" },
		{ "question": "上位", "answers": [ "じょうい" ], "comment": "(n) superior (rank not class)/higher order (e.g. byte)/host computer (of connected device)" },
		{ "question": "上司", "answers": [ "じょうし" ], "comment": "(n) superior authorities/boss" },
		{ "question": "上品", "answers": [ "じょうひん" ], "comment": "(n) Buddhism's highest paradise" },
		{ "question": "上回る", "answers": [ "うわまわる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to exceed" },
		{ "question": "上手", "answers": [ "じょうず" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) skill/skillful/dexterity" },
		{ "question": "上旬", "answers": [ "じょうじゅん" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n-t) first 10 days of month" },
		{ "question": "上昇", "answers": [ "じょうしょう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) rising/ascending/climbing" },
		{ "question": "上演", "answers": [ "じょうえん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) performance (e.g. music)" },
		{ "question": "上着", "answers": [ "うわぎ" ], "comment": "(n) coat/tunic/jacket/outer garment" },
		{ "question": "上空", "answers": [ "じょうくう" ], "comment": "(n) sky/the skies/high-altitude sky/upper air" },
		{ "question": "上等", "answers": [ "じょうとう" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) superiority/first class/very good" },
		{ "question": "上級", "answers": [ "じょうきゅう" ], "comment": "(n) advanced level/high grade/senior" },
		{ "question": "上達", "answers": [ "じょうたつ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) improvement/advance/progress" },
		{ "question": "上陸", "answers": [ "じょうりく" ], "comment": "(n,vs) landing/disembarkation" },
		{ "question": "下", "answers": [ "げ","した","しも" ], "comment": "(n) under/below/beneath" },
		{ "question": "下げる", "answers": [ "さげる" ], "comment": "(v1) to hang/to lower/to move back/to wear/to dismiss/to grant" },
		{ "question": "下さる", "answers": [ "くださる" ], "comment": "(v5aru) (hon) to give/to confer" },
		{ "question": "下ろす", "answers": [ "おろす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to lower/to let go down" },
		{ "question": "下り", "answers": [ "くだり" ], "comment": "(n,n-suf) down-train (going away from Tokyo)" },
		{ "question": "下りる", "answers": [ "おりる" ], "comment": "(v1) to alight (e.g. from bus)/to get off/to descend (e.g. a mountain)" },
		{ "question": "下る", "answers": [ "くだる","さがる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to get down/to descend" },
		{ "question": "下取り", "answers": [ "したどり" ], "comment": "(n) trade in/part exchange" },
		{ "question": "下品", "answers": [ "げひん" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) vulgarity/meanness/indecency/coarseness" },
		{ "question": "下地", "answers": [ "したじ" ], "comment": "(n) groundwork/foundation/inclination/aptitude/elementary knowledge of/grounding in/prearrangement/spadework/signs/symptoms/first coat of plastering/soy" },
		{ "question": "下宿", "answers": [ "げしゅく" ], "comment": "(n,vs) boarding/lodging/boarding house" },
		{ "question": "下心", "answers": [ "したごころ" ], "comment": "(n) secret intention/motive" },
		{ "question": "下手", "answers": [ "へた" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) unskillful/poor/awkward" },
		{ "question": "下旬", "answers": [ "げじゅん" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n-t) month (last third of)" },
		{ "question": "下書き", "answers": [ "したがき" ], "comment": "(n) rough copy/draft" },
		{ "question": "下水", "answers": [ "げすい" ], "comment": "(n) drainage/sewage/ditch/gutter/sewerage" },
		{ "question": "下火", "answers": [ "したび" ], "comment": "(n) burning low/waning/declining" },
		{ "question": "下町", "answers": [ "したまち" ], "comment": "(n) Shitamachi/lower parts of town" },
		{ "question": "下痢", "answers": [ "げり" ], "comment": "(n) diarrhoea" },
		{ "question": "下着", "answers": [ "したぎ" ], "comment": "(n) underwear" },
		{ "question": "下線", "answers": [ "かせん" ], "comment": "(n) underline/underscore" },
		{ "question": "下調べ", "answers": [ "したしらべ" ], "comment": "(n) preliminary investigation/preparation" },
		{ "question": "下車", "answers": [ "げしゃ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) alighting/getting off" },
		{ "question": "下降", "answers": [ "かこう" ], "comment": "(n) downward/descent/fall/drop/subsidence" },
		{ "question": "下駄", "answers": [ "げた" ], "comment": "(n) geta (Japanese footwear)/wooden clogs" },
		{ "question": "不", "answers": [ "ふ","ぶ" ], "comment": "un/non/negative prefix" },
		{ "question": "不便", "answers": [ "ふべん" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) inconvenience/inexpediency/unhandiness" },
		{ "question": "不利", "answers": [ "ふり" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) disadvantage/handicap/unfavorable/drawback" },
		{ "question": "不動産", "answers": [ "ふどうさん" ], "comment": "(n) real estate" },
		{ "question": "不可", "answers": [ "ふか" ], "comment": "(n,n-suf) wrong/bad/improper/unjustifiable/inadvisable" },
		{ "question": "不可欠", "answers": [ "ふかけつ" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) indispensable/essential" },
		{ "question": "不吉", "answers": [ "ふきつ" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) ominous/sinister/bad luck/ill omen/inauspiciousness" },
		{ "question": "不在", "answers": [ "ふざい" ], "comment": "(n) absence" },
		{ "question": "不安", "answers": [ "ふあん" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) anxiety/uneasiness/insecurity/suspense" },
		{ "question": "不審", "answers": [ "ふしん" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) incomplete understanding/doubt/question/distrust/suspicion/strangeness/infidelity" },
		{ "question": "不平", "answers": [ "ふへい" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) complaint/discontent/dissatisfaction" },
		{ "question": "不幸", "answers": [ "ふこう" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) unhappiness/sorrow/misfortune/disaster/accident/death" },
		{ "question": "不当", "answers": [ "ふとう" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) injustice/impropriety/unreasonableness/undeservedness/unfair/invalid" },
		{ "question": "不思議", "answers": [ "ふしぎ" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) wonder/miracle/strange/mystery/marvel/curiosity" },
		{ "question": "不意", "answers": [ "ふい" ], "comment": "(adj-na,adj-no,n) sudden/abrupt/unexpected/unforeseen" },
		{ "question": "不振", "answers": [ "ふしん" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) dullness/depression/slump/stagnation" },
		{ "question": "不明", "answers": [ "ふめい" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) unknown/obscure/indistinct/uncertain/ambiguous/ignorant/lack of wisdom/anonymous/unidentified" },
		{ "question": "不景気", "answers": [ "ふけいき" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) business recession/hard times/depression/gloom/sullenness/cheerlessness" },
		{ "question": "不服", "answers": [ "ふふく" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) dissatisfaction/discontent/disapproval/objection/complaint/protest/disagreement" },
		{ "question": "不正", "answers": [ "ふせい" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) injustice/unfairness/iniquity/impropriety/irregularity/dishonesty/illegality" },
		{ "question": "不況", "answers": [ "ふきょう" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) recession/depression/slump" },
		{ "question": "不満", "answers": [ "ふまん" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) dissatisfaction/displeasure/discontent/complaints/unhappiness" },
		{ "question": "不潔", "answers": [ "ふけつ" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) unclean/dirty/filthy/impure" },
		{ "question": "不自由", "answers": [ "ふじゆう" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) discomfort/disability/inconvenience/destitution" },
		{ "question": "不良", "answers": [ "ふりょう" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) badness/delinquent/inferiority/failure" },
		{ "question": "不規則", "answers": [ "ふきそく" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) irregularity/unsteadiness/disorderly" },
		{ "question": "不評", "answers": [ "ふひょう" ], "comment": "(n) bad reputation/disgrace/unpopularity" },
		{ "question": "不調", "answers": [ "ふちょう" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) bad condition/not to work out (ie a deal)/disagreement/break-off/disorder/slump/out of form" },
		{ "question": "不足", "answers": [ "ふそく" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) insufficiency/shortage/deficiency/lack/dearth" },
		{ "question": "不通", "answers": [ "ふつう" ], "comment": "(n) suspension/interruption/stoppage/tie-up/cessation" },
		{ "question": "不運", "answers": [ "ふうん" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) unlucky/misfortune/bad luck/fate" },
		{ "question": "不順", "answers": [ "ふじゅん" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) irregularity/unseasonableness" },
		{ "question": "与える", "answers": [ "あたえる" ], "comment": "(v1) to give/to present/to award" },
		{ "question": "与党", "answers": [ "よとう" ], "comment": "(n) government party/(ruling) party in power/government" },
		{ "question": "且つ", "answers": [ "かつ" ], "comment": "(adv,conj) yet/and" },
		{ "question": "世", "answers": [ "よ" ], "comment": "(n) world/society/age/generation" },
		{ "question": "世の中", "answers": [ "よのなか" ], "comment": "(n) society/the world/the times" },
		{ "question": "世代", "answers": [ "せだい" ], "comment": "(n) generation/the world/the age" },
		{ "question": "世帯", "answers": [ "せたい" ], "comment": "(n) household" },
		{ "question": "世界", "answers": [ "せかい" ], "comment": "(n) the world/society/the universe" },
		{ "question": "世紀", "answers": [ "せいき" ], "comment": "(n) century/era" },
		{ "question": "世話", "answers": [ "せわ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) looking after/help/aid/assistance" },
		{ "question": "世論", "answers": [ "せろん","よろん" ], "comment": "(n) public opinion" },
		{ "question": "世辞", "answers": [ "せじ" ], "comment": "(n) flattery/compliment" },
		{ "question": "世間", "answers": [ "せけん" ], "comment": "(n) world/society" },
		{ "question": "丘", "answers": [ "おか" ], "comment": "(n) hill/height/knoll/rising ground" },
		{ "question": "丘陵", "answers": [ "きゅうりょう" ], "comment": "(n) hill" },
		{ "question": "両側", "answers": [ "りょうがわ" ], "comment": "(n) both sides" },
		{ "question": "両方", "answers": [ "りょうほう" ], "comment": "(n) both sides/both parties" },
		{ "question": "両替", "answers": [ "りょうがえ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) change/money exchange" },
		{ "question": "両極", "answers": [ "りょうきょく" ], "comment": "(n) both extremities/north and south poles/positive and negative poles" },
		{ "question": "両立", "answers": [ "りょうりつ" ], "comment": "(n) compatibility/coexistence/standing together" },
		{ "question": "両親", "answers": [ "りょうしん" ], "comment": "(n) parents/both parents" },
		{ "question": "並", "answers": [ "なみ" ], "comment": "line up/be in a row/rank with/rival/equal" },
		{ "question": "並びに", "answers": [ "ならびに" ], "comment": "(conj) and" },
		{ "question": "並ぶ", "answers": [ "ならぶ" ], "comment": "(v5b,vi) to line up/to stand in a line" },
		{ "question": "並べる", "answers": [ "ならべる" ], "comment": "(v1,vt) to line up/to set up" },
		{ "question": "並列", "answers": [ "へいれつ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) arrangement/parallel/abreast" },
		{ "question": "並木", "answers": [ "なみき" ], "comment": "(n) roadside tree/row of trees" },
		{ "question": "並行", "answers": [ "へいこう" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n,vs) (going) side by side/concurrent/abreast/at the same time/occurring together/parallel/parallelism" },
		{ "question": "中", "answers": [ "ちゅう","なか" ], "comment": "(n) inside/middle/among" },
		{ "question": "中世", "answers": [ "ちゅうせい" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n-t) Middle Ages/mediaeval times" },
		{ "question": "中傷", "answers": [ "ちゅうしょう" ], "comment": "(n) slander/libel/defamation" },
		{ "question": "中古", "answers": [ "ちゅうこ" ], "comment": "(n-t) (1) used/second-hand/old" },
		{ "question": "中味", "answers": [ "なかみ" ], "comment": "(n) contents/interior/substance/filling/(sword) blade" },
		{ "question": "中和", "answers": [ "ちゅうわ" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n,vs) neutralize/counteract" },
		{ "question": "中央", "answers": [ "ちゅうおう" ], "comment": "(n) centre/central/center/middle" },
		{ "question": "中学", "answers": [ "ちゅうがく" ], "comment": "(n) middle school/junior high school" },
		{ "question": "中学校", "answers": [ "ちゅうがっこう" ], "comment": "(n) junior high school/middle school pupil" },
		{ "question": "中年", "answers": [ "ちゅうねん" ], "comment": "(n) middle-aged" },
		{ "question": "中心", "answers": [ "ちゅうしん" ], "comment": "(n) center/core/heart/pivot/emphasis/balance" },
		{ "question": "中性", "answers": [ "ちゅうせい" ], "comment": "(n) neuter gender/neutral (chem.)/indifference/sterility" },
		{ "question": "中指", "answers": [ "なかゆび" ], "comment": "(n) middle finger" },
		{ "question": "中断", "answers": [ "ちゅうだん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) interruption/suspension/break" },
		{ "question": "中旬", "answers": [ "ちゅうじゅん" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n-t) second third of a month" },
		{ "question": "中枢", "answers": [ "ちゅうすう" ], "comment": "(n) centre/pivot/mainstay/nucleus/backbone/central figure/pillar/key man" },
		{ "question": "中止", "answers": [ "ちゅうし" ], "comment": "(n,vs) suspension/stoppage/discontinuance/interruption" },
		{ "question": "中毒", "answers": [ "ちゅうどく" ], "comment": "(n) poisoning" },
		{ "question": "中程", "answers": [ "なかほど" ], "comment": "(n) middle/midway" },
		{ "question": "中立", "answers": [ "ちゅうりつ" ], "comment": "(n) neutrality" },
		{ "question": "中継", "answers": [ "ちゅうけい" ], "comment": "(n) relay/hook-up" },
		{ "question": "中腹", "answers": [ "ちゅうふく" ], "comment": "(n) mountain side/halfway up" },
		{ "question": "中身", "answers": [ "なかみ" ], "comment": "(n) contents/interior/substance/filling/(sword) blade" },
		{ "question": "中途", "answers": [ "ちゅうと" ], "comment": "(n) in the middle/half-way" },
		{ "question": "中間", "answers": [ "ちゅうかん" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n) middle/midway/interim" },
		{ "question": "丸", "answers": [ "まる" ], "comment": "(n) circle/full (month)/perfection/purity/suffix for ship names" },
		{ "question": "丸々", "answers": [ "まるまる" ], "comment": "(adv,n) completely" },
		{ "question": "丸い", "answers": [ "まるい" ], "comment": "(adj) round/circular/spherical" },
		{ "question": "丸ごと", "answers": [ "まるごと" ], "comment": "(adv) in its entirety/whole/wholly" },
		{ "question": "丸める", "answers": [ "まるめる" ], "comment": "(v1) to make round/to round off/to roll up/to curl up/to seduce/to cajole/to explain away" },
		{ "question": "主", "answers": [ "しゅ","ぬし","あるじ" ], "comment": "(n) owner/master/lover/god" },
		{ "question": "主に", "answers": [ "おもに" ], "comment": "(adv) mainly/primarily" },
		{ "question": "主人", "answers": [ "しゅじん" ], "comment": "(n) master/head (of a household)/landlord/one's husband/employer/host" },
		{ "question": "主人公", "answers": [ "しゅじんこう" ], "comment": "(n) (1) protagonist/main character/hero(ine) (of a story)/(2) head of household" },
		{ "question": "主任", "answers": [ "しゅにん" ], "comment": "(n) person in charge/responsible official" },
		{ "question": "主体", "answers": [ "しゅたい" ], "comment": "(n) subject/main constituent" },
		{ "question": "主催", "answers": [ "しゅさい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) organization/sponsorship" },
		{ "question": "主婦", "answers": [ "しゅふ" ], "comment": "(n) housewife/mistress" },
		{ "question": "主導", "answers": [ "しゅどう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) main leadership" },
		{ "question": "主張", "answers": [ "しゅちょう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) claim/request/insistence/assertion/advocacy/emphasis/contention/opinion/tenet" },
		{ "question": "主役", "answers": [ "しゅやく" ], "comment": "(n) leading part/leading actor (actress)" },
		{ "question": "主権", "answers": [ "しゅけん" ], "comment": "(n) sovereignty/supremacy/dominion" },
		{ "question": "主演", "answers": [ "しゅえん" ], "comment": "(n) starring/playing the leading part" },
		{ "question": "主義", "answers": [ "しゅぎ" ], "comment": "(n) doctrine/rule/principle" },
		{ "question": "主要", "answers": [ "しゅよう" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) chief/main/principal/major" },
		{ "question": "主観", "answers": [ "しゅかん" ], "comment": "(n) subjectivity/subject/ego" },
		{ "question": "主語", "answers": [ "しゅご" ], "comment": "(n) (gram) subject" },
		{ "question": "主題", "answers": [ "しゅだい" ], "comment": "(n) subject/theme/motif" },
		{ "question": "主食", "answers": [ "しゅしょく" ], "comment": "(n) staple food" },
		{ "question": "丼", "answers": [ "どんぶり" ], "comment": "(n) porcelain bowl/bowl of rice with food on top" },
		{ "question": "乃至", "answers": [ "ないし" ], "comment": "(conj) from...to/between...and/or" },
		{ "question": "久しい", "answers": [ "ひさしい" ], "comment": "(adj) long/long-continued/old (story)" },
		{ "question": "久しぶり", "answers": [ "ひさしぶり" ], "comment": "(exp) after a long time" },
		{ "question": "乏しい", "answers": [ "とぼしい" ], "comment": "(adj) meagre/scarce/limited/destitute/hard up/scanty/poor" },
		{ "question": "乗せる", "answers": [ "のせる" ], "comment": "(v1) to place on (something)/to take on board/to give a ride/to let (one) take part/to impose on/to record/to mention/to load (luggage)/to publish/to run (an ad)" },
		{ "question": "乗っ取る", "answers": [ "のっとる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to capture/to occupy/to usurp" },
		{ "question": "乗り換える", "answers": [ "のりかえる" ], "comment": "(v1) to transfer (trains)/to change (bus, train)" },
		{ "question": "乗り物", "answers": [ "のりもの" ], "comment": "(n) vehicle" },
		{ "question": "乗り越し", "answers": [ "のりこし" ], "comment": "(n) riding past (one's station)" },
		{ "question": "乗り込む", "answers": [ "のりこむ" ], "comment": "(v5m) (1) to board/to embark on/to get into (a car)/to ship (passengers)/to man (a ship)/to help (someone) into/(2) to march into/to enter" },
		{ "question": "乗る", "answers": [ "のる" ], "comment": "(v5r) (1) to get on/to ride in/to board/to mount/to get up on/to spread (paints)/to be taken in/(2) to share in/to join/to be found in (a dictionary)/to feel like doing/to be mentioned in/to be in harmony with" },
		{ "question": "乗客", "answers": [ "じょうきゃく" ], "comment": "(n) passenger" },
		{ "question": "乗換", "answers": [ "のりかえ" ], "comment": "(io) (n) transfer (trains, buses, etc.)" },
		{ "question": "乗車", "answers": [ "じょうしゃ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) taking a train/entraining" },
		{ "question": "乙", "answers": [ "おつ" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) 2nd in rank/second sign of the Chinese calendar" },
		{ "question": "九", "answers": [ "きゅう","く" ], "comment": "(num) nine" },
		{ "question": "九つ", "answers": [ "ここのつ" ], "comment": "(n) nine" },
		{ "question": "九日", "answers": [ "ここのか" ], "comment": "nine days/the ninth day (of the month)" },
		{ "question": "乱す", "answers": [ "みだす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to throw out of order/to disarrange/to disturb" },
		{ "question": "乱れる", "answers": [ "みだれる" ], "comment": "(v1) to get confused/to be disordered/to be disturbed" },
		{ "question": "乱暴", "answers": [ "らんぼう" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n,vs) rude/violent/rough/lawless/unreasonable/reckless" },
		{ "question": "乳", "answers": [ "ちち" ], "comment": "(n) milk/breast/loop" },
		{ "question": "乾かす", "answers": [ "かわかす" ], "comment": "(v5s,vt) to dry (clothes, etc.)/to desiccate" },
		{ "question": "乾く", "answers": [ "かわく" ], "comment": "(v5k,vi) to get dry" },
		{ "question": "乾杯", "answers": [ "かんぱい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) toast (drink)" },
		{ "question": "乾燥", "answers": [ "かんそう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) dry/arid/insipid/dehydrated" },
		{ "question": "乾電池", "answers": [ "かんでんち" ], "comment": "(n) dry cell/battery" },
		{ "question": "了承", "answers": [ "りょうしょう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) acknowledgement/understanding (e.g. 'please be understanding of the mess during our renovation')" },
		{ "question": "了解", "answers": [ "りょうかい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) comprehension/consent/understanding/roger (on the radio)" },
		{ "question": "予て", "answers": [ "かねて" ], "comment": "(adv) previously/already/lately" },
		{ "question": "予め", "answers": [ "あらかじめ" ], "comment": "(adv) beforehand/in advance/previously" },
		{ "question": "予備", "answers": [ "よび" ], "comment": "(n) preparation/preliminaries/reserve/spare" },
		{ "question": "予報", "answers": [ "よほう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) forecast/prediction" },
		{ "question": "予定", "answers": [ "よてい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) plans/arrangement/schedule/program/expectation/estimate" },
		{ "question": "予想", "answers": [ "よそう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) expectation/anticipation/prediction/forecast" },
		{ "question": "予感", "answers": [ "よかん" ], "comment": "(n) presentiment/premonition" },
		{ "question": "予期", "answers": [ "よき" ], "comment": "(n,vs) expectation/assume will happen/forecast" },
		{ "question": "予測", "answers": [ "よそく" ], "comment": "(n,vs) prediction/estimation" },
		{ "question": "予算", "answers": [ "よさん" ], "comment": "(n) estimate/budget" },
		{ "question": "予約", "answers": [ "よやく" ], "comment": "(n,vs) reservation/contract/subscription/booking/pledge/advance order" },
		{ "question": "予習", "answers": [ "よしゅう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) preparation for a lesson" },
		{ "question": "予言", "answers": [ "よげん" ], "comment": "(n) prediction/promise/prognostication" },
		{ "question": "予防", "answers": [ "よぼう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) prevention/precaution/protection against" },
		{ "question": "争い", "answers": [ "あらそい" ], "comment": "(n) dispute/strife/quarrel/dissension/conflict/rivalry/contest" },
		{ "question": "争う", "answers": [ "あらそう" ], "comment": "(v5u) to dispute/to argue/to be at variance/to compete" },
		{ "question": "事", "answers": [ "こと" ], "comment": "(n) thing/matter/fact/circumstances/business/reason/experience" },
		{ "question": "事件", "answers": [ "じけん" ], "comment": "(n) event/affair/incident/case/plot/trouble/scandal" },
		{ "question": "事前", "answers": [ "じぜん" ], "comment": "(adj-no,n) prior/beforehand/in advance" },
		{ "question": "事務", "answers": [ "じむ" ], "comment": "(n) business/office work" },
		{ "question": "事務所", "answers": [ "じむしょ" ], "comment": "(n) office" },
		{ "question": "事実", "answers": [ "じじつ" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n) fact/truth/reality" },
		{ "question": "事情", "answers": [ "じじょう" ], "comment": "(n) circumstances/consideration/conditions/situation/reasons" },
		{ "question": "事態", "answers": [ "じたい" ], "comment": "(n) situation/present state of affairs/circumstances" },
		{ "question": "事故", "answers": [ "じこ" ], "comment": "(n) accident/incident/trouble/circumstances/reasons" },
		{ "question": "事柄", "answers": [ "ことがら" ], "comment": "(n) matter/thing/affair/circumstance" },
		{ "question": "事業", "answers": [ "じぎょう" ], "comment": "(n) project/enterprise/business/industry/operations" },
		{ "question": "事項", "answers": [ "じこう" ], "comment": "(n) matter/item/facts" },
		{ "question": "二", "answers": [ "に" ], "comment": "(num) two" },
		{ "question": "二つ", "answers": [ "ふたつ" ], "comment": "(n) two" },
		{ "question": "二人", "answers": [ "ふたり" ], "comment": "(n) two persons/two people/pair/couple" },
		{ "question": "二十", "answers": [ "はたち" ], "comment": "(n) 20 years old/20th year" },
		{ "question": "二十日", "answers": [ "はつか" ], "comment": "(n) twenty days/twentieth (day of the month)" },
		{ "question": "二十歳", "answers": [ "はたち" ], "comment": "(n) 20 years old/20th year" },
		{ "question": "二日", "answers": [ "ふつか" ], "comment": "(n) second day of the month/two days" },
		{ "question": "云々", "answers": [ "うんぬん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) and so on/and so forth/comment" },
		{ "question": "互い", "answers": [ "たがい" ], "comment": "(n) mutual/reciprocal" },
		{ "question": "五", "answers": [ "ご" ], "comment": "(num) five" },
		{ "question": "五つ", "answers": [ "いつつ" ], "comment": "(n) five" },
		{ "question": "五十音", "answers": [ "ごじゅうおん" ], "comment": "(n) the Japanese syllabary" },
		{ "question": "五日", "answers": [ "いつか" ], "comment": "(n) five days/the fifth day (of the month)" },
		{ "question": "井戸", "answers": [ "いど" ], "comment": "(n) water well" },
		{ "question": "亜", "answers": [ "あ" ], "comment": "(pref) ① sub-. ② -ous (indicating a low oxidation state); -ite." },
		{ "question": "亡くす", "answers": [ "なくす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to lose someone, wife, child, etc" },
		{ "question": "亡くなる", "answers": [ "なくなる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to die" },
		{ "question": "交える", "answers": [ "まじえる" ], "comment": "(v1) to mix/to converse with/to cross (swords)" },
		{ "question": "交ざる", "answers": [ "まざる" ], "comment": "(v5r,vi) to be mixed/to be blended with/to associate with/to mingle with/to join" },
		{ "question": "交じる", "answers": [ "まじる" ], "comment": "(v5r,vi) to be mixed/to be blended with/to associate with/to mingle with/to interest/to join" },
		{ "question": "交わす", "answers": [ "かわす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to exchange (messages)/to dodge/to parry/to avoid/to turn aside" },
		{ "question": "交ぜる", "answers": [ "まぜる" ], "comment": "(v1,vi) to be mixed/to be blended with" },
		{ "question": "交わる", "answers": [ "まじわる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to cross/to intersect/to associate with/to mingle with/to interest/to join" },
		{ "question": "交互", "answers": [ "こうご" ], "comment": "(adj-no,n) mutual/reciprocal/alternate" },
		{ "question": "交付", "answers": [ "こうふ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) delivering/furnishing (with copies)" },
		{ "question": "交差", "answers": [ "こうさ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) cross" },
		{ "question": "交差点", "answers": [ "こうさてん" ], "comment": "(n) crossing/intersection" },
		{ "question": "交換", "answers": [ "こうかん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) exchange/interchange/reciprocity/barter/substitution/clearing (of checks)" },
		{ "question": "交替", "answers": [ "こうたい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) alternation/change/relief/relay/shift" },
		{ "question": "交流", "answers": [ "こうりゅう" ], "comment": "(n) alternating current/intercourse/(cultural) exchange/intermingling" },
		{ "question": "交渉", "answers": [ "こうしょう" ], "comment": "(n) negotiations/discussions/connection" },
		{ "question": "交番", "answers": [ "こうばん" ], "comment": "(n) police box" },
		{ "question": "交通", "answers": [ "こうつう" ], "comment": "(n) communication/transportation/traffic/intercourse" },
		{ "question": "交通機関", "answers": [ "こうつうきかん" ], "comment": "(n) transportation facilities" },
		{ "question": "交際", "answers": [ "こうさい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) company/friendship/association/society/acquaintance" },
		{ "question": "享受", "answers": [ "きょうじゅ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) reception/acceptance/enjoyment/being given" },
		{ "question": "人", "answers": [ "ひと" ], "comment": "(n) man/person/human being/mankind/people/character/personality/true man/man of talent/adult/other people/messenger/visitor" },
		{ "question": "人事", "answers": [ "じんじ" ], "comment": "(n) other's affairs" },
		{ "question": "人体", "answers": [ "じんたい" ], "comment": "(n) personal appearance/looks" },
		{ "question": "人口", "answers": [ "じんこう" ], "comment": "(n) (1) population/(2) common talk" },
		{ "question": "人命", "answers": [ "じんめい" ], "comment": "(n) (human) life" },
		{ "question": "人工", "answers": [ "じんこう" ], "comment": "(n) artificial/manmade/human work/human skill/artificiality" },
		{ "question": "人差指", "answers": [ "ひとさしゆび" ], "comment": "(n) index finger" },
		{ "question": "人形", "answers": [ "にんぎょう" ], "comment": "(n) doll/puppet/figure" },
		{ "question": "人影", "answers": [ "ひとかげ" ], "comment": "(n) man's shadow/soul" },
		{ "question": "人文科学", "answers": [ "じんぶんかがく" ], "comment": "social sciences/humanities" },
		{ "question": "人材", "answers": [ "じんざい" ], "comment": "(n) man of talent" },
		{ "question": "人柄", "answers": [ "ひとがら" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) personality/character/personal appearance/gentility" },
		{ "question": "人格", "answers": [ "じんかく" ], "comment": "(n) personality/character/individuality" },
		{ "question": "人民", "answers": [ "じんみん" ], "comment": "(n) people/public" },
		{ "question": "人気", "answers": [ "にんき","ひとけ" ], "comment": "(n) sign of life" },
		{ "question": "人物", "answers": [ "じんぶつ" ], "comment": "(n) character/personality/person/man/personage/talented man" },
		{ "question": "人生", "answers": [ "じんせい" ], "comment": "(n) (human) life (i.e. conception to death)" },
		{ "question": "人目", "answers": [ "ひとめ" ], "comment": "(n) glimpse/public gaze" },
		{ "question": "人種", "answers": [ "じんしゅ" ], "comment": "(n) race (of people)" },
		{ "question": "人質", "answers": [ "ひとじち" ], "comment": "(n) hostage/prisoner" },
		{ "question": "人込み", "answers": [ "ひとごみ" ], "comment": "(n) crowd of people" },
		{ "question": "人通り", "answers": [ "ひとどおり" ], "comment": "(n) pedestrian traffic" },
		{ "question": "人造", "answers": [ "じんぞう" ], "comment": "(n) man-made/synthetic/artificial" },
		{ "question": "人間", "answers": [ "にんげん" ], "comment": "(n) human being/man/person" },
		{ "question": "人類", "answers": [ "じんるい" ], "comment": "(n) mankind/humanity" },
		{ "question": "今", "answers": [ "いま" ], "comment": "this/now" },
		{ "question": "今に", "answers": [ "いまに" ], "comment": "(adv) before long/even now" },
		{ "question": "今にも", "answers": [ "いまにも" ], "comment": "(adv) at any time/soon" },
		{ "question": "今回", "answers": [ "こんかい" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n-t) now/this time/lately" },
		{ "question": "今夜", "answers": [ "こんや" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n-t) this evening/tonight" },
		{ "question": "今年", "answers": [ "ことし" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n-t) this year" },
		{ "question": "今度", "answers": [ "こんど" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n-t) now/this time/next time/another time" },
		{ "question": "今後", "answers": [ "こんご" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n-t) from now on/hereafter" },
		{ "question": "今日", "answers": [ "きょう","こんにち" ], "comment": "(n-t) today/this day" },
		{ "question": "今晩", "answers": [ "こんばん" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n-t) tonight/this evening" },
		{ "question": "今月", "answers": [ "こんげつ" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n-t) this month" },
		{ "question": "今朝", "answers": [ "けさ" ], "comment": "(ik) (n-t) this morning" },
		{ "question": "今週", "answers": [ "こんしゅう" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n-t) this week" },
		{ "question": "介入", "answers": [ "かいにゅう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) intervention" },
		{ "question": "介抱", "answers": [ "かいほう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) nursing/looking after" },
		{ "question": "介護", "answers": [ "かいご" ], "comment": "(n,vs) nursing" },
		{ "question": "仏", "answers": [ "ほとけ" ], "comment": "(n) Buddha/merciful person/Buddhist image/the dead" },
		{ "question": "仏像", "answers": [ "ぶつぞう" ], "comment": "(n) Buddhist image (statue)" },
		{ "question": "仕える", "answers": [ "つかえる" ], "comment": "(v1) to serve/to work for" },
		{ "question": "仕上", "answers": [ "しあげ" ], "comment": "(n) end/finishing touches/being finished" },
		{ "question": "仕上がり", "answers": [ "しあがり" ], "comment": "(n) finish/end/completion" },
		{ "question": "仕上がる", "answers": [ "しあがる" ], "comment": "(v5r,vi) to be finished" },
		{ "question": "仕上げる", "answers": [ "しあげる" ], "comment": "(v1,vt) to finish up/to complete" },
		{ "question": "仕事", "answers": [ "しごと" ], "comment": "(adj-no,n) work/occupation/employment" },
		{ "question": "仕入れる", "answers": [ "しいれる" ], "comment": "(v1) to lay in stock/to replenish stock/to procure" },
		{ "question": "仕切る", "answers": [ "しきる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to partition/to divide/to mark off/to settle accounts/to toe the mark" },
		{ "question": "仕掛", "answers": [ "しかけ" ], "comment": "(n) device/trick/mechanism/gadget/(small) scale/half finished/commencement/set up/challenge" },
		{ "question": "仕掛ける", "answers": [ "しかける" ], "comment": "(v1) to commence/to lay (mines)/to set (traps)/to wage (war)/to challenge" },
		{ "question": "仕方", "answers": [ "しかた" ], "comment": "(n) way/method/means/resource/course" },
		{ "question": "仕様", "answers": [ "しよう" ], "comment": "(n) way/method/resource/remedy/(technical) specification" },
		{ "question": "仕立てる", "answers": [ "したてる" ], "comment": "(v1) to tailor/to make/to prepare/to train/to send (a messenger)" },
		{ "question": "仕組", "answers": [ "しくみ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) (1) structure/construction/arrangement/contrivance/(2) plan/plot/contrivance" },
		{ "question": "他", "answers": [ "た","ほか" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n) other (esp. places and things)" },
		{ "question": "他人", "answers": [ "たにん" ], "comment": "(n) another person/unrelated person/outsider/stranger" },
		{ "question": "他動詞", "answers": [ "たどうし" ], "comment": "(n) transitive verb (direct obj)" },
		{ "question": "他方", "answers": [ "たほう" ], "comment": "(adv,n) another side/different direction/(on) the other hand" },
		{ "question": "付き合い", "answers": [ "つきあい" ], "comment": "(n) association/socializing/fellowship" },
		{ "question": "付く", "answers": [ "つく" ], "comment": "(v5k,vi) to adjoin/to be attached/to adhere/to be connected with/to be dyed/to be stained/to be scarred/to be recorded/to start (fires)/to follow/to become allied to/to accompany/to study with/to increase/to be added to" },
		{ "question": "付ける", "answers": [ "つける" ], "comment": "(v1,vt) (1) to attach/to join/to add/to append/to affix/to stick/to glue/to fasten/to sew on/to apply (ointment)/(2) to furnish (a house with)/(3) to wear/to put on/(4) to keep a diary/to make an entry/(5) to appraise/to set (a price)/(6) to bring alongside/(7) to place (under guard or doctor)/(8) to follow/to shadow/(9) to load/to give (courage to)/(10) to keep (an eye on)/(11) to establish (relations or understanding)" },
		{ "question": "付け加える", "answers": [ "つけくわえる" ], "comment": "(v1) to add one thing to another" },
		{ "question": "付合う", "answers": [ "つきあう" ], "comment": "(v5u) to associate with/to keep company with/to get on with" },
		{ "question": "付近", "answers": [ "ふきん" ], "comment": "(n,n-suf) neighbourhood/vicinity/environs" },
		{ "question": "付録", "answers": [ "ふろく" ], "comment": "(n) appendix/supplement" },
		{ "question": "代える", "answers": [ "かえる" ], "comment": "(v1) to exchange/to interchange/to substitute/to replace" },
		{ "question": "代る", "answers": [ "かわる" ], "comment": "(io) (v5r,vi) to take the place of/to relieve/to be substituted for/to be exchanged/to change places with/to take turns/to be replaced" },
		{ "question": "代る代る", "answers": [ "かわるがわる" ], "comment": "(adv) alternately" },
		{ "question": "代わり", "answers": [ "かわり" ], "comment": "(n) substitute/deputy/proxy/alternate/relief/compensation/second helping" },
		{ "question": "代名詞", "answers": [ "だいめいし" ], "comment": "(n) pronoun" },
		{ "question": "代弁", "answers": [ "だいべん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) pay by proxy/act for another/speak for another" },
		{ "question": "代理", "answers": [ "だいり" ], "comment": "(n) representation/agency/proxy/deputy/agent/attorney/substitute/alternate/acting (principal, etc.)" },
		{ "question": "代用", "answers": [ "だいよう" ], "comment": "(n) substitution" },
		{ "question": "代表", "answers": [ "だいひょう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) representative/representation/delegation/type/example/model" },
		{ "question": "代金", "answers": [ "だいきん" ], "comment": "(n) price/payment/cost/charge/the money/the bill" },
		{ "question": "以上", "answers": [ "いじょう" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n-t) more than/exceeding/greater than/this is all/over/above/and up/beyond/the above-mentioned/since/as long as/the end" },
		{ "question": "以下", "answers": [ "いか" ], "comment": "(n) less than/up to/below/under/and downward/not exceeding/the following/the rest" },
		{ "question": "以内", "answers": [ "いない" ], "comment": "(n,n-suf) within/inside of/less than" },
		{ "question": "以前", "answers": [ "いぜん" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n-t) ago/since/before/previous" },
		{ "question": "以外", "answers": [ "いがい" ], "comment": "(n-adv) with the exception of/excepting" },
		{ "question": "以後", "answers": [ "いご" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n-t) after this/from now on/hereafter/thereafter" },
		{ "question": "以来", "answers": [ "いらい" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n-t) since/henceforth" },
		{ "question": "以降", "answers": [ "いこう" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n-t) on and after/hereafter/thereafter" },
		{ "question": "仮名", "answers": [ "かな" ], "comment": "(ok) (n) alias/pseudonym/pen name/nom de plume/(NB the karina reading is the origin of the word `kana')" },
		{ "question": "仮名遣い", "answers": [ "かなづかい" ], "comment": "(n) kana orthography/syllabary spelling" },
		{ "question": "仮定", "answers": [ "かてい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) assumption/supposition/hypothesis" },
		{ "question": "仰ぐ", "answers": [ "あおぐ" ], "comment": "(v5g) to look up (to)/to respect/to depend on/to ask for/to seek/to revere/to drink/to take" },
		{ "question": "仲", "answers": [ "なか" ], "comment": "(n) relation/relationship" },
		{ "question": "仲人", "answers": [ "なこうど" ], "comment": "(n) go-between/matchmaker" },
		{ "question": "仲直り", "answers": [ "なかなおり" ], "comment": "(n,vs) reconciliation/make peace with" },
		{ "question": "仲良し", "answers": [ "なかよし" ], "comment": "(n) intimate friend/bosom buddy/chum" },
		{ "question": "仲間", "answers": [ "なかま" ], "comment": "(n) company/fellow/colleague/associate/comrade/mate/group/circle of friends/partner" },
		{ "question": "件", "answers": [ "けん" ], "comment": "(n) matter/case/item" },
		{ "question": "任す", "answers": [ "まかす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to entrust/to leave to a person" },
		{ "question": "任せる", "answers": [ "まかせる" ], "comment": "(v1) (1) to entrust to another/to leave to/(2) to do something at one's leisure" },
		{ "question": "任務", "answers": [ "にんむ" ], "comment": "(n) duty/function/office/mission/task" },
		{ "question": "任命", "answers": [ "にんめい" ], "comment": "(n) appointment/nomination/ordination/commission/designation" },
		{ "question": "企業", "answers": [ "きぎょう" ], "comment": "(n) enterprise/undertaking" },
		{ "question": "企画", "answers": [ "きかく" ], "comment": "(n,vs) planning/project" },
		{ "question": "休み", "answers": [ "やすみ" ], "comment": "(n) (1) rest/recess/respite/(2) vacation/holiday/absence/suspension/(3) moulting" },
		{ "question": "休む", "answers": [ "やすむ" ], "comment": "(v5m,vi) to rest/to have a break/to take a day off/to be finished/to be absent/to retire/to sleep" },
		{ "question": "休める", "answers": [ "やすめる" ], "comment": "(v1) to rest/to suspend/to give relief" },
		{ "question": "休学", "answers": [ "きゅうがく" ], "comment": "(n) temporary absence from school/suspension" },
		{ "question": "休息", "answers": [ "きゅうそく" ], "comment": "(n) rest/relief/relaxation" },
		{ "question": "休憩", "answers": [ "きゅうけい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) rest/break/recess/intermission" },
		{ "question": "休戦", "answers": [ "きゅうせん" ], "comment": "(n) truce/armistice" },
		{ "question": "休暇", "answers": [ "きゅうか" ], "comment": "(n) holiday/day off/furlough" },
		{ "question": "休業", "answers": [ "きゅうぎょう" ], "comment": "(n) closed (e.g. store)/business suspended/shutdown/holiday" },
		{ "question": "休講", "answers": [ "きゅうこう" ], "comment": "(n) lecture cancelled" },
		{ "question": "休養", "answers": [ "きゅうよう" ], "comment": "(n) rest/break/recreation" },
		{ "question": "会", "answers": [ "かい" ], "comment": "(n,n-suf,vs) meeting/assembly/party/association/club" },
		{ "question": "会う", "answers": [ "あう" ], "comment": "(v5u) to meet/to interview" },
		{ "question": "会合", "answers": [ "かいごう" ], "comment": "(n) meeting/assembly" },
		{ "question": "会員", "answers": [ "かいいん" ], "comment": "(n) member/the membership" },
		{ "question": "会場", "answers": [ "かいじょう" ], "comment": "(n) assembly hall/meeting place/the grounds" },
		{ "question": "会社", "answers": [ "かいしゃ" ], "comment": "(n) company/corporation" },
		{ "question": "会見", "answers": [ "かいけん" ], "comment": "(n) interview/audience" },
		{ "question": "会計", "answers": [ "かいけい" ], "comment": "(n) account/finance/accountant/treasurer/paymaster/reckoning/bill" },
		{ "question": "会話", "answers": [ "かいわ" ], "comment": "(n) conversation" },
		{ "question": "会談", "answers": [ "かいだん" ], "comment": "(n) conversation/conference/discussion/interview" },
		{ "question": "会議", "answers": [ "かいぎ" ], "comment": "(n) meeting/conference/session/assembly/council/convention/congress" },
		{ "question": "会館", "answers": [ "かいかん" ], "comment": "(n) meeting hall/assembly hall" },
		{ "question": "伝える", "answers": [ "つたえる" ], "comment": "(v1) to convey/to report/to transmit/to communicate/to tell/to impart/to propagate/to teach/to bequeath" },
		{ "question": "伝わる", "answers": [ "つたわる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to be handed down/to be introduced/to be transmitted/to be circulated/to go along/to walk along" },
		{ "question": "伝来", "answers": [ "でんらい" ], "comment": "(adj-no,n) ancestral/hereditary/imported/transmitted/handed down" },
		{ "question": "伝染", "answers": [ "でんせん" ], "comment": "(n) contagion" },
		{ "question": "伝統", "answers": [ "でんとう" ], "comment": "(n) tradition/convention" },
		{ "question": "伝言", "answers": [ "でんごん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) verbal message/rumor/word" },
		{ "question": "伝記", "answers": [ "でんき" ], "comment": "(n) biography/life story" },
		{ "question": "伝説", "answers": [ "でんせつ" ], "comment": "(n) tradition/legend/folklore" },
		{ "question": "伝達", "answers": [ "でんたつ" ], "comment": "(n) transmission (e.g. news)/communication/delivery" },
		{ "question": "伯母", "answers": [ "おば" ], "comment": "(n) (hum) aunt (older than one's parent)" },
		{ "question": "伯母さん", "answers": [ "おばさん" ], "comment": "(n) (hon) aunt" },
		{ "question": "伯父", "answers": [ "おじ" ], "comment": "(n) (hum) uncle (older than one's parent)" },
		{ "question": "伯父さん", "answers": [ "おじさん" ], "comment": "(n) (hon) (uk) middle-aged gentleman/uncle" },
		{ "question": "伴う", "answers": [ "ともなう" ], "comment": "(v5u) to accompany/to bring with/to be accompanied by/to be involved in" },
		{ "question": "伸ばす", "answers": [ "のばす" ], "comment": "(v5s,vt) to lengthen/to stretch/to reach out/to postpone/to prolong/to extend/to grow (beard)" },
		{ "question": "伸びる", "answers": [ "のびる" ], "comment": "(v1,vi) to stretch/to extend/to make progress/to grow (beard, body height)/to grow stale (soba)/to lengthen/to spread/to be postponed/to be straightened/to be flattened/to be smoothed/to be exhausted" },
		{ "question": "伺う", "answers": [ "うかがう" ], "comment": "(v5u,vi,vt) (hon) to visit/to ask/to inquire/to hear/to be told/to implore (a god for an oracle)" },
		{ "question": "似る", "answers": [ "にる" ], "comment": "(v1) to resemble/to be similar" },
		{ "question": "似合う", "answers": [ "にあう" ], "comment": "(v5u) to suit/to match/to become/to be like" },
		{ "question": "似通う", "answers": [ "にかよう" ], "comment": "(v5u) to resemble closely" },
		{ "question": "但し", "answers": [ "ただし" ], "comment": "(conj) but/however/provided that" },
		{ "question": "位", "answers": [ "くらい" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n,suf,vs) grade/rank/court order/dignity/nobility/situation/throne/crown/occupying a position/about/almost/as/rather/at least/enough to" },
		{ "question": "位置", "answers": [ "いち" ], "comment": "(n,vs) place/situation/position/location" },
		{ "question": "低い", "answers": [ "ひくい" ], "comment": "(adj) short/low/humble/low (voice)" },
		{ "question": "低下", "answers": [ "ていか" ], "comment": "(n,vs) fall/decline/lowering/deterioration" },
		{ "question": "住", "answers": [ "じゅう" ], "comment": "(n) dwelling/living" },
		{ "question": "住まい", "answers": [ "すまい" ], "comment": "(n) dwelling/house/residence/address" },
		{ "question": "住む", "answers": [ "すむ" ], "comment": "(v5m) to abide/to reside/to live in/to inhabit/to dwell" },
		{ "question": "住宅", "answers": [ "じゅうたく" ], "comment": "(n) resident/housing" },
		{ "question": "住居", "answers": [ "じゅうきょ" ], "comment": "(n) dwelling/house/residence/address" },
		{ "question": "住所", "answers": [ "じゅうしょ" ], "comment": "(n) address (e.g. of house)/residence/domicile" },
		{ "question": "住民", "answers": [ "じゅうみん" ], "comment": "(n) citizens/inhabitants/residents/population" },
		{ "question": "体", "answers": [ "からだ" ], "comment": "(n) appearance/air/condition/state/form" },
		{ "question": "体付き", "answers": [ "からだつき" ], "comment": "(n) body build/figure" },
		{ "question": "体制", "answers": [ "たいせい" ], "comment": "(n) order/system/structure/set-up/organization" },
		{ "question": "体力", "answers": [ "たいりょく" ], "comment": "(n) physical strength" },
		{ "question": "体操", "answers": [ "たいそう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) gymnastics/physical exercises/calisthenics" },
		{ "question": "体格", "answers": [ "たいかく" ], "comment": "(n) physique/constitution" },
		{ "question": "体温", "answers": [ "たいおん" ], "comment": "(n) temperature (body)" },
		{ "question": "体積", "answers": [ "たいせき" ], "comment": "(n) capacity/volume" },
		{ "question": "体系", "answers": [ "たいけい" ], "comment": "(n) system/organization" },
		{ "question": "体育", "answers": [ "たいいく" ], "comment": "(n) physical education/gymnastics/athletics" },
		{ "question": "体裁", "answers": [ "ていさい" ], "comment": "(n) decency/style/form/appearance/show/get-up/format" },
		{ "question": "体重", "answers": [ "たいじゅう" ], "comment": "(n) one's body weight" },
		{ "question": "体験", "answers": [ "たいけん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) personal experience" },
		{ "question": "何", "answers": [ "なに","なん" ], "comment": "(int,n) what" },
		{ "question": "何々", "answers": [ "なになに" ], "comment": "(int,n) such and such/What?/What is the matter?/What are the items?" },
		{ "question": "何か", "answers": [ "なにか" ], "comment": "(exp) something" },
		{ "question": "何だか", "answers": [ "なんだか" ], "comment": "(adv) a little/somewhat/somehow" },
		{ "question": "何で", "answers": [ "なんで" ], "comment": "(adv) Why?/What for?" },
		{ "question": "何でも", "answers": [ "なんでも" ], "comment": "(adv,exp) by all means/everything" },
		{ "question": "何とか", "answers": [ "なんとか" ], "comment": "(adv,exp,n) somehow/anyhow/one way or another" },
		{ "question": "何分", "answers": [ "なにぶん" ], "comment": "(n) what minute?/how many minutes?" },
		{ "question": "何時か", "answers": [ "いつか" ], "comment": "(adv) (uk) sometime/someday/one day/some time or other/the other day/in due course/in time" },
		{ "question": "何気ない", "answers": [ "なにげない" ], "comment": "(adj) casual/unconcerned" },
		{ "question": "余り", "answers": [ "あまり" ], "comment": "(adj-na,adv,n,n-suf) (uk) not very (this form only used as adverb)/not much/remainder/rest/remnant/surplus/balance/excess/remains/scraps/residue/fullness/other/too much" },
		{ "question": "余る", "answers": [ "あまる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to remain/to be left over/to be in excess/to be too many" },
		{ "question": "余分", "answers": [ "よぶん" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) extra/excess/surplus" },
		{ "question": "余地", "answers": [ "よち" ], "comment": "(n) place/room/margin/scope" },
		{ "question": "余所", "answers": [ "よそ" ], "comment": "(n) another place/somewhere else/strange parts" },
		{ "question": "余所見", "answers": [ "よそみ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) looking away/looking aside" },
		{ "question": "余暇", "answers": [ "よか" ], "comment": "(n) leisure/leisure time/spare time" },
		{ "question": "余程", "answers": [ "よほど" ], "comment": "(adv) very/greatly/much/to a large extent/quite" },
		{ "question": "余興", "answers": [ "よきょう" ], "comment": "(n) side show/entertainment" },
		{ "question": "余裕", "answers": [ "よゆう" ], "comment": "(n) surplus/composure/margin/room/time/allowance/scope/rope" },
		{ "question": "余計", "answers": [ "よけい" ], "comment": "(adj-na,adv,n) too much/unnecessary/abundance/surplus/excess/superfluity" },
		{ "question": "作", "answers": [ "さく" ], "comment": "(n,n-suf) a work/a harvest" },
		{ "question": "作り", "answers": [ "つくり" ], "comment": "(n) make-up/sliced raw fish" },
		{ "question": "作る", "answers": [ "つくる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to make/to create/to manufacture/to draw up/to write/to compose/to build/to coin/to cultivate/to organize/to establish/to make up (a face)/to trim (a tree)/to fabricate/to prepare (food)/to commit (sin)/to construct" },
		{ "question": "作品", "answers": [ "さくひん" ], "comment": "(n) work/opus/performance/production" },
		{ "question": "作家", "answers": [ "さっか" ], "comment": "(n) author/writer/novelist/artist" },
		{ "question": "作成", "answers": [ "さくせい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) frame/draw up/make/producing/creating/preparing/writing" },
		{ "question": "作戦", "answers": [ "さくせん" ], "comment": "(n) military or naval operations/tactics/strategy" },
		{ "question": "作文", "answers": [ "さくぶん" ], "comment": "(n) composition/writing" },
		{ "question": "作曲", "answers": [ "さっきょく" ], "comment": "(n,vs) composition/setting (of music)" },
		{ "question": "作業", "answers": [ "さぎょう" ], "comment": "(n) work/operation/manufacturing/fatigue duty" },
		{ "question": "作法", "answers": [ "さほう" ], "comment": "(n) manners/etiquette/propriety" },
		{ "question": "作物", "answers": [ "さくもつ" ], "comment": "(n) produce (e.g. agricultural)/crops" },
		{ "question": "作用", "answers": [ "さよう" ], "comment": "(n) action/operation/effect/function" },
		{ "question": "作者", "answers": [ "さくしゃ" ], "comment": "(n) author/authoress" },
		{ "question": "作製", "answers": [ "さくせい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) manufacture" },
		{ "question": "使い道", "answers": [ "つかいみち" ], "comment": "(n) use" },
		{ "question": "使う", "answers": [ "つかう" ], "comment": "(v5u) to use/to handle/to manipulate/to employ/to need/to want/to spend/to consume/to speak (English)/to practise (fencing)/to take (one's lunch)/to circulate (bad money)" },
		{ "question": "使命", "answers": [ "しめい" ], "comment": "(n) mission/errand/message" },
		{ "question": "使用", "answers": [ "しよう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) use/application/employment/utilization" },
		{ "question": "使用人", "answers": [ "しようにん" ], "comment": "(n) employee/servant" },
		{ "question": "例", "answers": [ "れい" ], "comment": "(n) instance/example/case/precedent/experience/custom/usage/parallel/illustration" },
		{ "question": "例え", "answers": [ "たとえ" ], "comment": "(adv,n) example/even if/if/though/although" },
		{ "question": "例えば", "answers": [ "たとえば" ], "comment": "(adv) for example/e.g." },
		{ "question": "例える", "answers": [ "たとえる" ], "comment": "(v1) to compare/to liken/to speak figuratively/to illustrate/to use a simile" },
		{ "question": "例外", "answers": [ "れいがい" ], "comment": "(adj-no,n) exception" },
		{ "question": "侍", "answers": [ "さむらい" ], "comment": "(n) Samurai/warrior" },
		{ "question": "供", "answers": [ "とも" ], "comment": "(n,vs) accompanying/attendant/companion/retinue" },
		{ "question": "供給", "answers": [ "きょうきゅう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) supply/provision" },
		{ "question": "依存", "answers": [ "いそん", "いぞん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) dependence/dependent/reliance" },
		{ "question": "依然", "answers": [ "いぜん" ], "comment": "(adv,n) still/as yet" },
		{ "question": "依頼", "answers": [ "いらい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) (1) request/commission/dispatch/(2) dependence/trust" },
		{ "question": "価値", "answers": [ "かち" ], "comment": "(n) value/worth/merit" },
		{ "question": "価格", "answers": [ "かかく" ], "comment": "(n) price/value/cost" },
		{ "question": "侮辱", "answers": [ "ぶじょく" ], "comment": "(n) insult/contempt/slight" },
		{ "question": "侵す", "answers": [ "おかす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to invade/to raid/to trespass/to violate/to intrude on" },
		{ "question": "侵入", "answers": [ "しんにゅう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) penetration/invasion/raid/aggression/trespass" },
		{ "question": "侵略", "answers": [ "しんりゃく" ], "comment": "(n) aggression/invasion/raid" },
		{ "question": "便", "answers": [ "びん" ], "comment": "way/means" },
		{ "question": "便り", "answers": [ "たより" ], "comment": "(n) news/tidings/information/correspondence/letter" },
		{ "question": "便利", "answers": [ "べんり" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) convenient/handy/useful" },
		{ "question": "便宜", "answers": [ "べんぎ" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) convenience/accommodation/advantage/expedience" },
		{ "question": "便所", "answers": [ "べんじょ" ], "comment": "(n) toilet/lavatory/rest room/latrine/comfort station" },
		{ "question": "便箋", "answers": [ "びんせん" ], "comment": "(n) writing paper/stationery" },
		{ "question": "係", "answers": [ "かかり" ], "comment": "(n) official/duty/person in charge" },
		{ "question": "係わる", "answers": [ "かかわる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to concern oneself in/to have to do with/to affect/to influence/to stick to (opinions)" },
		{ "question": "促す", "answers": [ "うながす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to urge/to press/to suggest/to demand/to stimulate/to quicken/to incite/to invite (attention to)" },
		{ "question": "促進", "answers": [ "そくしん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) promotion/acceleration/encouragement/facilitation/spurring on" },
		{ "question": "俄", "answers": [ "にわか" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) sudden/abrupt/unexpected/improvised/offhand" },
		{ "question": "保つ", "answers": [ "たもつ" ], "comment": "(v5t) to keep/to preserve/to hold/to retain/to maintain/to support/to sustain/to last/to endure/to keep well (food)/to wear well/to be durable" },
		{ "question": "保健", "answers": [ "ほけん" ], "comment": "(n) health preservation/hygiene/sanitation" },
		{ "question": "保存", "answers": [ "ほぞん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) preservation/conservation/storage/maintenance" },
		{ "question": "保守", "answers": [ "ほしゅ" ], "comment": "(n) conservative/maintaining" },
		{ "question": "保温", "answers": [ "ほおん" ], "comment": "(n) retaining warmth/keeping heat in/heat insulation" },
		{ "question": "保管", "answers": [ "ほかん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) charge/custody/safekeeping/deposit/storage" },
		{ "question": "保育", "answers": [ "ほいく" ], "comment": "(n,vs) nursing/nurturing/rearing/lactation/suckling" },
		{ "question": "保証", "answers": [ "ほしょう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) guarantee/security/assurance/pledge/warranty" },
		{ "question": "保護", "answers": [ "ほご" ], "comment": "(n) care/protection/shelter/guardianship/favor/patronage" },
		{ "question": "保険", "answers": [ "ほけん" ], "comment": "(n) insurance/guarantee" },
		{ "question": "保障", "answers": [ "ほしょう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) guarantee/security/assurance/pledge/warranty" },
		{ "question": "保養", "answers": [ "ほよう" ], "comment": "(n) health preservation/recuperation/recreation" },
		{ "question": "信じる", "answers": [ "しんじる" ], "comment": "(v1) to believe/to believe in/to place trust in/to confide in/to have faith in" },
		{ "question": "信ずる", "answers": [ "しんずる" ], "comment": "(v5z) to believe/to believe in/to place trust in/to confide in/to have faith in" },
		{ "question": "信仰", "answers": [ "しんこう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) (religious) faith/belief/creed" },
		{ "question": "信任", "answers": [ "しんにん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) trust/confidence/credence" },
		{ "question": "信号", "answers": [ "しんごう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) traffic lights/signal/semaphore" },
		{ "question": "信用", "answers": [ "しんよう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) confidence/dependence/credit/faith/reliance/belief/credence" },
		{ "question": "信者", "answers": [ "しんじゃ" ], "comment": "(n) believer/adherent/devotee/Christian" },
		{ "question": "信頼", "answers": [ "しんらい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) reliance/trust/confidence" },
		{ "question": "修士", "answers": [ "しゅうし" ], "comment": "(n) Masters degree program" },
		{ "question": "修学", "answers": [ "しゅうがく" ], "comment": "(n) learning" },
		{ "question": "修正", "answers": [ "しゅうせい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) amendment/correction/revision/modification/alteration/retouching/update" },
		{ "question": "修理", "answers": [ "しゅうり" ], "comment": "(n,vs) repairing/mending" },
		{ "question": "修繕", "answers": [ "しゅうぜん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) repair/mending" },
		{ "question": "修行", "answers": [ "しゅぎょう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) pursuit of knowledge/studying/learning/training/ascetic practice/discipline" },
		{ "question": "修飾", "answers": [ "しゅうしょく" ], "comment": "(n,vs) (1) ornamentation/embellishment/decoration/adornment/polish up (writing)/(2) modification (gram)" },
		{ "question": "俳優", "answers": [ "はいゆう" ], "comment": "(n) actor/actress/player/performer" },
		{ "question": "俳句", "answers": [ "はいく" ], "comment": "(n) haiku poetry (17-syllable poem usually in 3 lines of 5, 7 and 5 syllables)" },
		{ "question": "俺", "answers": [ "おれ" ], "comment": "(n) I (ego) (boastful first-person pronoun)" },
		{ "question": "倉庫", "answers": [ "そうこ" ], "comment": "(n) storehouse/warehouse/godown" },
		{ "question": "個々", "answers": [ "ここ" ], "comment": "(n) individual/one by one" },
		{ "question": "個人", "answers": [ "こじん" ], "comment": "(adj-no,n) individual/private person/personal/private" },
		{ "question": "個体", "answers": [ "こたい" ], "comment": "(n) an individual" },
		{ "question": "個別", "answers": [ "こべつ" ], "comment": "(n) particular case" },
		{ "question": "個性", "answers": [ "こせい" ], "comment": "(n) individuality/personality/idiosyncrasy" },
		{ "question": "個所", "answers": [ "かしょ" ], "comment": "(n) passage/place/point/part" },
		{ "question": "倍", "answers": [ "ばい" ], "comment": "(n,vi,vs,vt) twice/times/-fold/double/be doubled/increase" },
		{ "question": "倍率", "answers": [ "ばいりつ" ], "comment": "(n) diameter/magnification" },
		{ "question": "倒す", "answers": [ "たおす" ], "comment": "(v5s,vt) to throw down/to beat/to bring down/to blow down/to fell/to knock down/to trip up/to defeat/to ruin/to overthrow/to kill/to leave unpaid/to cheat" },
		{ "question": "倒れる", "answers": [ "たおれる" ], "comment": "(v1,vi) to collapse/to break down/to go bankrupt/to fall/to drop/to die/to succumb to/to fall senseless/to be ruined/to have a bad debt" },
		{ "question": "倒産", "answers": [ "とうさん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) (corporate) bankruptcy/insolvency" },
		{ "question": "候補", "answers": [ "こうほ" ], "comment": "(n) candidacy" },
		{ "question": "借り", "answers": [ "かり" ], "comment": "(n) borrowing/debt/loan" },
		{ "question": "借りる", "answers": [ "かりる" ], "comment": "(v1) to borrow/to have a loan/to hire/to rent/to buy on credit" },
		{ "question": "借金", "answers": [ "しゃっきん" ], "comment": "(n) debt/loan/liabilities" },
		{ "question": "倣う", "answers": [ "ならう" ], "comment": "(ok) (v5u) (uk) to imitate/to follow/to emulate" },
		{ "question": "値", "answers": [ "あたい","ね" ], "comment": "(adj-no,n,vs) value/price/cost/worth/merit" },
		{ "question": "値する", "answers": [ "あたいする" ], "comment": "(vs-s) to be worth/to deserve/to merit" },
		{ "question": "値引き", "answers": [ "ねびき" ], "comment": "(n) price reduction/discount" },
		{ "question": "値打ち", "answers": [ "ねうち" ], "comment": "(n) value/worth/price/dignity" },
		{ "question": "値段", "answers": [ "ねだん" ], "comment": "(n) price/cost" },
		{ "question": "倹約", "answers": [ "けんやく" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n,vs) thrift/economy/frugality" },
		{ "question": "偉い", "answers": [ "えらい" ], "comment": "(adj) great/celebrated/eminent/terrible/awful/famous/remarkable/excellent" },
		{ "question": "偉大", "answers": [ "いだい" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) greatness" },
		{ "question": "偏見", "answers": [ "へんけん" ], "comment": "(n) prejudice/narrow view" },
		{ "question": "停止", "answers": [ "ていし" ], "comment": "(n,vs) suspension/interruption/stoppage/ban/standstill/deadlock/stalemate/abeyance" },
		{ "question": "停滞", "answers": [ "ていたい" ], "comment": "(n) stagnation/tie-up/congestion/retention/accumulation/falling into arrears" },
		{ "question": "停留所", "answers": [ "ていりゅうじょ" ], "comment": "(n) bus or tram stop" },
		{ "question": "停車", "answers": [ "ていしゃ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) stopping (e.g. train)" },
		{ "question": "停電", "answers": [ "ていでん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) failure of electricity" },
		{ "question": "健やか", "answers": [ "すこやか" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) vigorous/healthy/sound" },
		{ "question": "健全", "answers": [ "けんぜん" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) health/soundness/wholesome" },
		{ "question": "健在", "answers": [ "けんざい" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) in good health/well" },
		{ "question": "健康", "answers": [ "けんこう" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) health/sound/wholesome" },
		{ "question": "側", "answers": [ "そば" ], "comment": "(n) side/edge/third person" },
		{ "question": "側面", "answers": [ "そくめん" ], "comment": "(n) side/flank/sidelight/lateral" },
		{ "question": "偶", "answers": [ "たま" ], "comment": "(adj-no,n) even number/couple/man and wife/friend/same kind/doll/occasional/rare" },
		{ "question": "偶々", "answers": [ "たまたま" ], "comment": "(adv) casually/unexpectedly/accidentally/by chance" },
		{ "question": "偶数", "answers": [ "ぐうすう" ], "comment": "(n) even number" },
		{ "question": "偶然", "answers": [ "ぐうぜん" ], "comment": "(adj-na,adj-no,n-adv,n) (by) chance/unexpectedly/suddenly/accident/fortuity" },
		{ "question": "偽造", "answers": [ "ぎぞう" ], "comment": "(n) forgery/falsification/fabrication/counterfeiting" },
		{ "question": "傍ら", "answers": [ "かたわら" ], "comment": "(adj-no,n-adv,n-t) beside(s)/while/nearby" },
		{ "question": "傑作", "answers": [ "けっさく" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) masterpiece/best work/boner/blunder" },
		{ "question": "傘", "answers": [ "かさ" ], "comment": "(n) umbrella/parasol" },
		{ "question": "備える", "answers": [ "そなえる" ], "comment": "(v1) to furnish/to provide for/to equip/to install/to have ready/to prepare for/to possess/to have/to be endowed with/to be armed with" },
		{ "question": "備え付ける", "answers": [ "そなえつける" ], "comment": "(v1) to provide/to furnish/to equip/to install" },
		{ "question": "備わる", "answers": [ "そなわる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to be furnished with/to be endowed with/to possess/to be among/to be one of/to be possessed of" },
		{ "question": "催し", "answers": [ "もよおし" ], "comment": "(n) event/festivities/function/social gathering/auspices/opening/holding (a meeting)" },
		{ "question": "催す", "answers": [ "もよおす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to hold (a meeting)/to give (a dinner)/to feel/to show signs of/to develop symptoms of/to feel (sick)" },
		{ "question": "催促", "answers": [ "さいそく" ], "comment": "(n,vs) request/demand/claim/urge (action)/press for" },
		{ "question": "傷", "answers": [ "きず" ], "comment": "(n) wound/injury/hurt/cut/gash/bruise/scratch/scar/weak point" },
		{ "question": "傷める", "answers": [ "いためる" ], "comment": "(v1) to damage/to impair/to spoil" },
		{ "question": "傷付く", "answers": [ "きずつく" ], "comment": "(v5k) to be hurt/to be wounded/to get injured" },
		{ "question": "傷付ける", "answers": [ "きずつける" ], "comment": "(v1) to wound/to hurt someone's feelings" },
		{ "question": "傾く", "answers": [ "かたむく" ], "comment": "(v5k) to incline toward/to slant/to lurch/to heel over/to be disposed to/to trend toward/to be prone to/to go down (sun)/to wane/to sink/to decline" },
		{ "question": "傾ける", "answers": [ "かたむける" ], "comment": "(v1,vt) to incline/to list/to bend/to lean/to tip/to tilt/to slant/to concentrate on/to ruin (a country)/to squander/to empty" },
		{ "question": "傾向", "answers": [ "けいこう" ], "comment": "(n) tendency/trend/inclination" },
		{ "question": "傾斜", "answers": [ "けいしゃ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) inclination/slant/slope/bevel/list/dip" },
		{ "question": "僅か", "answers": [ "わずか" ], "comment": "(adj-na,adv,n) only/merely/a little/small quantity" },
		{ "question": "働き", "answers": [ "はたらき" ], "comment": "(n) work/workings/activity/ability/talent/function/labor/action/operation/movement/motion/conjugation/inflection/achievement" },
		{ "question": "働く", "answers": [ "はたらく" ], "comment": "(v5k) to work/to labor/to do/to act/to commit/to practise/to work on/to come into play/to be conjugated/to reduce the price" },
		{ "question": "像", "answers": [ "ぞう" ], "comment": "(n,n-suf) statue/image/figure/picture/portrait" },
		{ "question": "僕", "answers": [ "ぼく" ], "comment": "(n) (male) I/manservant" },
		{ "question": "僧", "answers": [ "そう" ], "comment": "(n) monk/priest" },
		{ "question": "儀式", "answers": [ "ぎしき" ], "comment": "(n) ceremony/rite/ritual/service" },
		{ "question": "億", "answers": [ "おく" ], "comment": "(num) 100,000,000/hundred million" },
		{ "question": "優", "answers": [ "ゆう" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) actor/superiority/gentleness" },
		{ "question": "優しい", "answers": [ "やさしい" ], "comment": "(adj) tender/kind/gentle/graceful/affectionate/amiable/suave" },
		{ "question": "優れる", "answers": [ "すぐれる" ], "comment": "(v1) to surpass/to outstrip/to excel" },
		{ "question": "優位", "answers": [ "ゆうい" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) predominance/ascendancy/superiority" },
		{ "question": "優先", "answers": [ "ゆうせん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) preference/priority" },
		{ "question": "優勝", "answers": [ "ゆうしょう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) overall victory/championship" },
		{ "question": "優勢", "answers": [ "ゆうせい" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) superiority/superior power/predominance/preponderance" },
		{ "question": "優秀", "answers": [ "ゆうしゅう" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) superiority/excellence" },
		{ "question": "優美", "answers": [ "ゆうび" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) grace/refinement/elegance" },
		{ "question": "優越", "answers": [ "ゆうえつ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) supremacy/predominance/being superior to" },
		{ "question": "儲かる", "answers": [ "もうかる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to be profitable/to yield a profit" },
		{ "question": "儲ける", "answers": [ "もうける" ], "comment": "(v1) to get/to earn/to gain/to have (bear, beget) a child" },
		{ "question": "元", "answers": [ "もと" ], "comment": "(n,n-suf,n-t) (1) origin/original/(2) former" },
		{ "question": "元々", "answers": [ "もともと" ], "comment": "(adv,adj-no) originally/by nature/from the start" },
		{ "question": "元年", "answers": [ "がんねん" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n-t) first year (of a specific reign)" },
		{ "question": "元日", "answers": [ "がんじつ" ], "comment": "(n) New Year's Day" },
		{ "question": "元来", "answers": [ "がんらい" ], "comment": "(n-adv) originally/primarily/essentially/logically/naturally" },
		{ "question": "元気", "answers": [ "げんき" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) health(y)/robust/vigor/energy/vitality/vim/stamina/spirit/courage/pep" },
		{ "question": "元素", "answers": [ "げんそ" ], "comment": "(n) chemical element" },
		{ "question": "元首", "answers": [ "げんしゅ" ], "comment": "(n) ruler/sovereign" },
		{ "question": "兄", "answers": [ "あに" ], "comment": "(n) (hum) older brother" },
		{ "question": "兄弟", "answers": [ "きょうだい" ], "comment": "(n) (hum) siblings" },
		{ "question": "充実", "answers": [ "じゅうじつ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) fullness/completion/perfection/substantiality/enrichment" },
		{ "question": "兆", "answers": [ "きざし" ], "comment": "(num) sign/omen/indication/portent/1,000,000,000,000/trillion (American)/billion (British)" },
		{ "question": "先", "answers": [ "さき","せん" ], "comment": "(adj-no,n) the future/priority/precedence/former/previous/old/late" },
		{ "question": "先々月", "answers": [ "せんせんげつ" ], "comment": "(n-t) month before last" },
		{ "question": "先ず", "answers": [ "まず" ], "comment": "(adv) first (of all)/to start with/about/almost/hardly (with neg. verb)/anyway/well/now" },
		{ "question": "先だって", "answers": [ "せんだって" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n-t) recently/the other day" },
		{ "question": "先代", "answers": [ "せんだい" ], "comment": "(n) family predecessor/previous age/previous generation" },
		{ "question": "先天的", "answers": [ "せんてんてき" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) a priori/inborn/innate/inherent/congenital/hereditary" },
		{ "question": "先日", "answers": [ "せんじつ" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n-t) the other day/a few days ago" },
		{ "question": "先月", "answers": [ "せんげつ" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n-t) last month" },
		{ "question": "先生", "answers": [ "せんせい" ], "comment": "(n) teacher/master/doctor" },
		{ "question": "先着", "answers": [ "せんちゃく" ], "comment": "(n) first arrival" },
		{ "question": "先祖", "answers": [ "せんぞ" ], "comment": "(n) ancestor" },
		{ "question": "先程", "answers": [ "さきほど" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n-t) some time ago" },
		{ "question": "先端", "answers": [ "せんたん" ], "comment": "(n) pointed end/tip/fine point/spearhead/cusp/vanguard/advanced/leading edge" },
		{ "question": "先行", "answers": [ "せんこう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) preceding/going first" },
		{ "question": "先輩", "answers": [ "せんぱい" ], "comment": "(n) senior (at work or school)/superior/elder/older graduate/progenitor/old-timer" },
		{ "question": "先週", "answers": [ "せんしゅう" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n-t) last week/the week before" },
		{ "question": "先頭", "answers": [ "せんとう" ], "comment": "(n) head/lead/vanguard/first" },
		{ "question": "光", "answers": [ "ひかり" ], "comment": "(n) light" },
		{ "question": "光る", "answers": [ "ひかる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to shine/to glitter/to be bright" },
		{ "question": "光景", "answers": [ "こうけい" ], "comment": "(n) scene/spectacle" },
		{ "question": "光沢", "answers": [ "こうたく" ], "comment": "(n) brilliance/polish/lustre/glossy finish (of photographs)" },
		{ "question": "光熱費", "answers": [ "こうねつひ" ], "comment": "(n) cost of fuel and light" },
		{ "question": "光線", "answers": [ "こうせん" ], "comment": "(n) beam/light ray" },
		{ "question": "克服", "answers": [ "こくふく" ], "comment": "(n) subjugation/conquest" },
		{ "question": "免れる", "answers": [ "まぬがれる" ], "comment": "(v1) to escape from/to be rescued from/to avoid/to evade/to avert/to elude/to be exempted/to be relieved from pain/to get rid of" },
		{ "question": "免税", "answers": [ "めんぜい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) tax exemption/duty exemption" },
		{ "question": "免許", "answers": [ "めんきょ" ], "comment": "(n) license/permit/licence/certificate" },
		{ "question": "免除", "answers": [ "めんじょ" ], "comment": "(n) exemption/exoneration/discharge" },
		{ "question": "兎", "answers": [ "うさぎ" ], "comment": "(n) rabbit/hare/cony" },
		{ "question": "児童", "answers": [ "じどう" ], "comment": "(n) children/juvenile" },
		{ "question": "党", "answers": [ "とう" ], "comment": "(n,n-suf) party (political)" },
		{ "question": "入る", "answers": [ "はいる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to enter/to break into/to join/to enroll/to contain/to hold/to accommodate/to have (an income of)" },
		{ "question": "入れる", "answers": [ "いれる" ], "comment": "(v1) to put in/to take in/to bring in/to let in/to admit/to introduce/to commit (to prison)/to usher in/to insert/to set (jewels)/to employ/to listen to/to tolerate/to comprehend/to include/to pay (interest)/to cast (votes)" },
		{ "question": "入れ物", "answers": [ "いれもの" ], "comment": "(n) container/case/receptacle" },
		{ "question": "入口", "answers": [ "いりぐち" ], "comment": "(n) entrance/gate/approach/mouth" },
		{ "question": "入場", "answers": [ "にゅうじょう" ], "comment": "(n) entrance/admission/entering" },
		{ "question": "入学", "answers": [ "にゅうがく" ], "comment": "(n) entry to school or university/matriculation" },
		{ "question": "入手", "answers": [ "にゅうしゅ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) obtaining/coming to hand" },
		{ "question": "入浴", "answers": [ "にゅうよく" ], "comment": "(n,vs) bathe/bathing" },
		{ "question": "入社", "answers": [ "にゅうしゃ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) entry to a company" },
		{ "question": "入賞", "answers": [ "にゅうしょう" ], "comment": "(n) winning a prize or place (in a contest)" },
		{ "question": "入院", "answers": [ "にゅういん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) hospitalization" },
		{ "question": "全", "answers": [ "ぜん" ], "comment": "(n,pref) all/whole/entire/complete/overall/pan" },
		{ "question": "全く", "answers": [ "まったく" ], "comment": "(adv) really/truly/entirely/completely/wholly/perfectly/indeed" },
		{ "question": "全て", "answers": [ "すべて" ], "comment": "(adj-no,n-adv,n) all/the whole/entirely/in general/wholly" },
		{ "question": "全体", "answers": [ "ぜんたい" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n-t) whole/entirety/whatever (is the matter)" },
		{ "question": "全力", "answers": [ "ぜんりょく" ], "comment": "(n) all one's power/whole energy" },
		{ "question": "全員", "answers": [ "ぜんいん" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n) all members (unanimity)/all hands/the whole crew" },
		{ "question": "全国", "answers": [ "ぜんこく" ], "comment": "(n) country-wide/nation-wide/whole country/national" },
		{ "question": "全快", "answers": [ "ぜんかい" ], "comment": "(n) complete recovery of health" },
		{ "question": "全滅", "answers": [ "ぜんめつ" ], "comment": "(n) annihilation" },
		{ "question": "全然", "answers": [ "ぜんぜん" ], "comment": "(adv) (1) wholly/entirely/completely/(2) not at all (with neg. verb)" },
		{ "question": "全盛", "answers": [ "ぜんせい" ], "comment": "(n) height of prosperity" },
		{ "question": "全般", "answers": [ "ぜんぱん" ], "comment": "(adj-no,n) (the) whole/universal/wholly/general" },
		{ "question": "全身", "answers": [ "ぜんしん" ], "comment": "(n) the whole body/full-length (portrait)" },
		{ "question": "全部", "answers": [ "ぜんぶ" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n-t) all/entire/whole/altogether" },
		{ "question": "全集", "answers": [ "ぜんしゅう" ], "comment": "(n) complete works" },
		{ "question": "八", "answers": [ "はち" ], "comment": "(num) eight" },
		{ "question": "八つ", "answers": [ "やっつ" ], "comment": "(num) eight" },
		{ "question": "八日", "answers": [ "ようか" ], "comment": "(n) eight days/the eighth (day of the month)" },
		{ "question": "八百屋", "answers": [ "やおや" ], "comment": "(n) greengrocer" },
		{ "question": "公", "answers": [ "おおやけ" ], "comment": "(n,suf) prince/lord/duke/public/daimyo/companion/subordinate" },
		{ "question": "公共", "answers": [ "こうきょう" ], "comment": "(adj-no,n) public/community/public service/society/communal" },
		{ "question": "公務", "answers": [ "こうむ" ], "comment": "(n) official business/public business" },
		{ "question": "公務員", "answers": [ "こうむいん" ], "comment": "(n) government worker/public (civil) servant" },
		{ "question": "公募", "answers": [ "こうぼ" ], "comment": "(n) public appeal/public contribution" },
		{ "question": "公団", "answers": [ "こうだん" ], "comment": "(n) public corporation" },
		{ "question": "公園", "answers": [ "こうえん" ], "comment": "(n) (public) park" },
		{ "question": "公害", "answers": [ "こうがい" ], "comment": "(n) public nuisance/pollution" },
		{ "question": "公平", "answers": [ "こうへい" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) fairness/impartial/justice" },
		{ "question": "公式", "answers": [ "こうしき" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) formula/formality/official" },
		{ "question": "公正", "answers": [ "こうせい" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) justice/fairness/impartiality" },
		{ "question": "公演", "answers": [ "こうえん" ], "comment": "(n) public performance" },
		{ "question": "公然", "answers": [ "こうぜん" ], "comment": "(adj-na,adj-no,n) open (e.g. secret)/public/official" },
		{ "question": "公用", "answers": [ "こうよう" ], "comment": "(n) government business/public use/public expense" },
		{ "question": "公立", "answers": [ "こうりつ" ], "comment": "(n) public (institution)" },
		{ "question": "公衆", "answers": [ "こうしゅう" ], "comment": "(n) the public" },
		{ "question": "公表", "answers": [ "こうひょう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) official announcement/proclamation" },
		{ "question": "公認", "answers": [ "こうにん" ], "comment": "(n) official recognition/authorization/licence/accreditation" },
		{ "question": "六", "answers": [ "ろく" ], "comment": "(num) six" },
		{ "question": "六つ", "answers": [ "むっつ" ], "comment": "(num) six" },
		{ "question": "六日", "answers": [ "むいか" ], "comment": "six days/sixth (day of month)" },
		{ "question": "共に", "answers": [ "ともに" ], "comment": "(adv,vs) sharing with/participate in/both/alike/together/along with/with/including" },
		{ "question": "共働き", "answers": [ "ともばたらき" ], "comment": "(n) dual income" },
		{ "question": "共同", "answers": [ "きょうどう" ], "comment": "(n) cooperation/association/collaboration/joint" },
		{ "question": "共和", "answers": [ "きょうわ" ], "comment": "(n) republicanism/cooperation" },
		{ "question": "共存", "answers": [ "きょうぞん" ], "comment": "(n) coexistence" },
		{ "question": "共学", "answers": [ "きょうがく" ], "comment": "(n) coeducation" },
		{ "question": "共感", "answers": [ "きょうかん" ], "comment": "(n) sympathy/response" },
		{ "question": "共稼ぎ", "answers": [ "ともかせぎ" ], "comment": "(n) working together/(husband and wife) earning a living together" },
		{ "question": "共通", "answers": [ "きょうつう" ], "comment": "(adj-na,adj-no,n,vs) commonness/community" },
		{ "question": "共鳴", "answers": [ "きょうめい" ], "comment": "(n) resonance/sympathy" },
		{ "question": "兵器", "answers": [ "へいき" ], "comment": "(n) arms/weapons/ordinance" },
		{ "question": "兵士", "answers": [ "へいし" ], "comment": "(n) soldier" },
		{ "question": "兵隊", "answers": [ "へいたい" ], "comment": "(n) soldier/sailor" },
		{ "question": "具える", "answers": [ "そなえる" ], "comment": "(v1) to be furnished with" },
		{ "question": "具わる", "answers": [ "そなわる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to be furnished with/to be endowed with/to possess/to be among/to be one of/to be possessed of" },
		{ "question": "具体", "answers": [ "ぐたい" ], "comment": "(n) concrete/tangible/material" },
		{ "question": "具合", "answers": [ "ぐあい" ], "comment": "(n) condition/state/manner/health" },
		{ "question": "典型", "answers": [ "てんけい" ], "comment": "(adj-no,n) type/pattern/archetypal" },
		{ "question": "兼ねる", "answers": [ "かねる" ], "comment": "(suf,v1) to hold (position)/to serve/to be unable/to be beyond one's ability/to combine with/to use with/cannot/to hesitate to/to be impatient" },
		{ "question": "兼業", "answers": [ "けんぎょう" ], "comment": "(n) side line/second business" },
		{ "question": "兼用", "answers": [ "けんよう" ], "comment": "(n) multi-use/combined use/combination/serving two purposes" },
		{ "question": "内", "answers": [ "うち" ], "comment": "(n) inside" },
		{ "question": "内乱", "answers": [ "ないらん" ], "comment": "(n) civil war/insurrection/rebellion/domestic conflict" },
		{ "question": "内容", "answers": [ "ないよう" ], "comment": "(n) subject/contents/matter/substance/detail/import" },
		{ "question": "内心", "answers": [ "ないしん" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n-t) innermost thoughts/real intention/inmost heart/one's mind/in the heart" },
		{ "question": "内科", "answers": [ "ないか" ], "comment": "(n) internist clinic/internal medicine" },
		{ "question": "内緒", "answers": [ "ないしょ" ], "comment": "(adj-no,n) secrecy/privacy/secret/internal evidence/one's circumstances" },
		{ "question": "内線", "answers": [ "ないせん" ], "comment": "(n) phone extension/indoor wiring/inner line" },
		{ "question": "内蔵", "answers": [ "ないぞう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) involvement/internal (e.g. disk)" },
		{ "question": "内訳", "answers": [ "うちわけ" ], "comment": "(n) the items/breakdown/classification" },
		{ "question": "内部", "answers": [ "ないぶ" ], "comment": "(adj-no,n) interior/inside/internal" },
		{ "question": "内閣", "answers": [ "ないかく" ], "comment": "(n) cabinet/(government) ministry" },
		{ "question": "内陸", "answers": [ "ないりく" ], "comment": "(n) inland" },
		{ "question": "円", "answers": [ "えん","まる" ], "comment": "(n) circle/money" },
		{ "question": "円い", "answers": [ "まるい" ], "comment": "(adj) round/circular/spherical" },
		{ "question": "円周", "answers": [ "えんしゅう" ], "comment": "(n) circumference" },
		{ "question": "円満", "answers": [ "えんまん" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) perfection/harmony/peace/smoothness/completeness/satisfaction/integrity" },
		{ "question": "円滑", "answers": [ "えんかつ" ], "comment": "(ik) (adj-na,n) harmony/smoothness" },
		{ "question": "再び", "answers": [ "ふたたび" ], "comment": "(adv) again/once more/a second time" },
		{ "question": "再三", "answers": [ "さいさん" ], "comment": "(adv,n) again and again/repeatedly" },
		{ "question": "再会", "answers": [ "さいかい" ], "comment": "(n) another meeting/meeting again/reunion" },
		{ "question": "再建", "answers": [ "さいけん" ], "comment": "(n) (temple or shrine) rebuilding" },
		{ "question": "再来年", "answers": [ "さらいねん" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n-t) year after next" },
		{ "question": "再来月", "answers": [ "さらいげつ" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n-t) month after next" },
		{ "question": "再来週", "answers": [ "さらいしゅう" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n-t) week after next" },
		{ "question": "再現", "answers": [ "さいげん" ], "comment": "(n) reappearance/reproduction/return/revival" },
		{ "question": "再生", "answers": [ "さいせい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) playback/regeneration/resuscitation/return to life/rebirth/reincarnation/narrow escape/reclamation/regrowth" },
		{ "question": "再発", "answers": [ "さいはつ" ], "comment": "(n) return/relapse/reoccurrence" },
		{ "question": "冒険", "answers": [ "ぼうけん" ], "comment": "(n) risk/venture/adventure" },
		{ "question": "冒頭", "answers": [ "ぼうとう" ], "comment": "(adv,n) beginning/start/outset" },
		{ "question": "冗談", "answers": [ "じょうだん" ], "comment": "(n) jest/joke" },
		{ "question": "写し", "answers": [ "うつし" ], "comment": "(n) copy/duplicate/facsimile/transcript" },
		{ "question": "写す", "answers": [ "うつす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to film/to transcribe/to duplicate/to reproduce/to trace/to describe/to picture/to photograph/to imitate" },
		{ "question": "写る", "answers": [ "うつる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to be photographed/to be projected" },
		{ "question": "写生", "answers": [ "しゃせい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) sketching/drawing from nature/portrayal/description" },
		{ "question": "写真", "answers": [ "しゃしん" ], "comment": "(n) photograph" },
		{ "question": "冠", "answers": [ "かんむり" ], "comment": "(n,vs) crown/diadem/first/best/peerless/cap/naming/designating/initiating on coming of age/top character radical" },
		{ "question": "冬", "answers": [ "ふゆ" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n-t) winter" },
		{ "question": "冬眠", "answers": [ "とうみん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) hibernation/winter sleep" },
		{ "question": "冴える", "answers": [ "さえる" ], "comment": "(v1) to be clear/to be serene/to be cold/to be skillful" },
		{ "question": "冷える", "answers": [ "ひえる" ], "comment": "(v1,vi) to grow cold/to get chilly/to cool down" },
		{ "question": "冷たい", "answers": [ "つめたい" ], "comment": "(adj) cold (to the touch)/chilly/icy/freezing/coldhearted" },
		{ "question": "冷ます", "answers": [ "さます" ], "comment": "(v5s,vt) to cool/to dampen/to let cool/to throw a damper on/to spoil" },
		{ "question": "冷める", "answers": [ "さめる" ], "comment": "(v1) to become cool/to wear off/to abate/to subside/to dampen/to cool down (interest)/to come down (fever)" },
		{ "question": "冷やかす", "answers": [ "ひやかす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to banter/to make fun of/to jeer at/to cool/to refrigerate" },
		{ "question": "冷やす", "answers": [ "ひやす" ], "comment": "(v5s,vt) to cool/to refrigerate" },
		{ "question": "冷凍", "answers": [ "れいとう" ], "comment": "(n) freezing/cold storage/refrigeration" },
		{ "question": "冷房", "answers": [ "れいぼう" ], "comment": "(n) cooling/air-conditioning" },
		{ "question": "冷淡", "answers": [ "れいたん" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) coolness/indifference" },
		{ "question": "冷蔵", "answers": [ "れいぞう" ], "comment": "(n) cold storage/refrigeration" },
		{ "question": "冷蔵庫", "answers": [ "れいぞうこ" ], "comment": "(n) refrigerator" },
		{ "question": "冷酷", "answers": [ "れいこく" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) cruelty/coldheartedness/relentless/ruthless" },
		{ "question": "冷静", "answers": [ "れいせい" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) calm/composure/coolness/serenity" },
		{ "question": "凌ぐ", "answers": [ "しのぐ" ], "comment": "(v5g) to outdo/to surpass/to endure/to keep out (rain)/to stave off/to tide over/to pull through/to defy/to slight/to excel/to eclipse" },
		{ "question": "凍える", "answers": [ "こごえる" ], "comment": "(v1) to freeze/to be chilled/to be frozen" },
		{ "question": "凍る", "answers": [ "こおる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to freeze/to be frozen over/to congeal" },
		{ "question": "凝らす", "answers": [ "こらす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to concentrate/to devote/to apply/to strain/to rack" },
		{ "question": "凝る", "answers": [ "こる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to stiffen/to harden" },
		{ "question": "几帳面", "answers": [ "きちょうめん" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n,vs) methodical/punctual/steady" },
		{ "question": "処分", "answers": [ "しょぶん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) disposal/dealing/punishment" },
		{ "question": "処理", "answers": [ "しょり" ], "comment": "(n,vs) processing/dealing with/treatment/disposition/disposal" },
		{ "question": "処置", "answers": [ "しょち" ], "comment": "(n,vs) treatment" },
		{ "question": "処罰", "answers": [ "しょばつ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) punishment" },
		{ "question": "凶作", "answers": [ "きょうさく" ], "comment": "(n) bad harvest/poor crop" },
		{ "question": "凸凹", "answers": [ "でこぼこ" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) unevenness/roughness/ruggedness" },
		{ "question": "凹む", "answers": [ "へこむ" ], "comment": "(v5m) to be dented/to be indented/to yield to/to give/to sink/to collapse/to cave in/to be snubbed" },
		{ "question": "出かける", "answers": [ "でかける" ], "comment": "(v1) to depart/to go out (e.g. on an excursion or outing)/to set out/to start/to be going out" },
		{ "question": "出くわす", "answers": [ "でくわす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to happen to meet/to come across" },
		{ "question": "出す", "answers": [ "だす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to put out/to send" },
		{ "question": "出る", "answers": [ "でる" ], "comment": "(v1) to appear/to come forth/to leave" },
		{ "question": "出世", "answers": [ "しゅっせ" ], "comment": "(n) promotion/successful career/eminence" },
		{ "question": "出会い", "answers": [ "であい" ], "comment": "(n) meeting/rendezvous/encounter" },
		{ "question": "出会う", "answers": [ "であう" ], "comment": "(v5u) to meet by chance/to come across/to happen to encounter/to hold a rendezvous/to have a date" },
		{ "question": "出入り", "answers": [ "でいり" ], "comment": "(n) in and out/coming and going/free association/income and expenditure/debits and credit" },
		{ "question": "出入口", "answers": [ "でいりぐち" ], "comment": "(n) exit and entrance" },
		{ "question": "出動", "answers": [ "しゅつどう" ], "comment": "(n) sailing/marching/going out" },
		{ "question": "出勤", "answers": [ "しゅっきん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) going to work/at work" },
		{ "question": "出口", "answers": [ "でぐち" ], "comment": "(n) exit/gateway/way out/outlet/leak/vent" },
		{ "question": "出合い", "answers": [ "であい" ], "comment": "(n) an encounter" },
		{ "question": "出合う", "answers": [ "であう" ], "comment": "(v5u) to meet by chance/to come across/to happen to encounter/to hold a rendezvous/to have a date" },
		{ "question": "出品", "answers": [ "しゅっぴん" ], "comment": "(n) exhibit/display" },
		{ "question": "出場", "answers": [ "しゅつじょう" ], "comment": "(n) one's turn/place of projection/production center" },
		{ "question": "出席", "answers": [ "しゅっせき" ], "comment": "(n,vs) attendance/presence" },
		{ "question": "出張", "answers": [ "しゅっちょう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) official tour/business trip" },
		{ "question": "出掛ける", "answers": [ "でかける" ], "comment": "(v1) to depart/to go out (e.g. on an excursion or outing)/to set out/to start/to be going out" },
		{ "question": "出来るだけ", "answers": [ "できるだけ" ], "comment": "if at all possible" },
		{ "question": "出来上がり", "answers": [ "できあがり" ], "comment": "(n) be finished/ready/made for/cut out" },
		{ "question": "出来上がる", "answers": [ "できあがる" ], "comment": "(v5r) (1) to be finished/to be ready/by definition/(2) to be very drunk" },
		{ "question": "出来事", "answers": [ "できごと" ], "comment": "(n) incident/affair/happening/event" },
		{ "question": "出演", "answers": [ "しゅつえん" ], "comment": "(n) performance/stage appearance" },
		{ "question": "出版", "answers": [ "しゅっぱん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) publication" },
		{ "question": "出現", "answers": [ "しゅつげん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) appearance/arrival/make one's appearance" },
		{ "question": "出生", "answers": [ "しゅっしょう","しゅっせい" ], "comment": "(n) birth" },
		{ "question": "出産", "answers": [ "しゅっさん" ], "comment": "(n) (child)birth/delivery/production (of goods)" },
		{ "question": "出発", "answers": [ "しゅっぱつ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) departure" },
		{ "question": "出直し", "answers": [ "でなおし" ], "comment": "(n) adjustment/touch up" },
		{ "question": "出社", "answers": [ "しゅっしゃ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) arrival (in a country, at work, etc.)" },
		{ "question": "出血", "answers": [ "しゅっけつ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) bleeding/haemorrhage" },
		{ "question": "出費", "answers": [ "しゅっぴ" ], "comment": "(n) expenses/disbursements" },
		{ "question": "出身", "answers": [ "しゅっしん" ], "comment": "(n) graduate from/come from" },
		{ "question": "出迎え", "answers": [ "でむかえ" ], "comment": "(n) meeting/reception" },
		{ "question": "出迎える", "answers": [ "でむかえる" ], "comment": "(v1) to meet/to greet" },
		{ "question": "出題", "answers": [ "しゅつだい" ], "comment": "(n) proposing a question" },
		{ "question": "刀", "answers": [ "かたな" ], "comment": "(n) sword/saber/knife/engraving tool" },
		{ "question": "刃", "answers": [ "は" ], "comment": "(n) blade/sword" },
		{ "question": "分", "answers": [ "ぶ","ぶん" ], "comment": "(n,n-suf,pref) dividing/part/segment/share/ration/rate/degree/one's lot/one's status/relation/duty/kind/lot/branch/detached" },
		{ "question": "分かれる", "answers": [ "わかれる" ], "comment": "(v1) to branch off/to diverge from/to fork/to split/to dispense/to scatter/to divide into" },
		{ "question": "分ける", "answers": [ "わける" ], "comment": "(v1) to divide/to separate" },
		{ "question": "分かる", "answers": [ "わかる" ], "comment": "(io) (v5r) to be understood" },
		{ "question": "分子", "answers": [ "ぶんし" ], "comment": "(n) numerator/molecule" },
		{ "question": "分布", "answers": [ "ぶんぷ" ], "comment": "(n) distribution" },
		{ "question": "分担", "answers": [ "ぶんたん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) apportionment/sharing" },
		{ "question": "分散", "answers": [ "ぶんさん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) dispersion/decentralization/variance (statistics)" },
		{ "question": "分数", "answers": [ "ぶんすう" ], "comment": "(n) fraction (in math)" },
		{ "question": "分析", "answers": [ "ぶんせき" ], "comment": "(n,vs) analysis" },
		{ "question": "分業", "answers": [ "ぶんぎょう" ], "comment": "(n) division of labor/specialization/assembly-line production" },
		{ "question": "分母", "answers": [ "ぶんぼ" ], "comment": "(n) denominator" },
		{ "question": "分裂", "answers": [ "ぶんれつ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) split/division/break up" },
		{ "question": "分解", "answers": [ "ぶんかい" ], "comment": "(n) analysis/disassembly" },
		{ "question": "分配", "answers": [ "ぶんぱい" ], "comment": "(n) division/sharing" },
		{ "question": "分野", "answers": [ "ぶんや" ], "comment": "(n) field/sphere/realm/division/branch" },
		{ "question": "分量", "answers": [ "ぶんりょう" ], "comment": "(n) amount/quantity" },
		{ "question": "分離", "answers": [ "ぶんり" ], "comment": "(n) separation/detachment/segregation/isolation" },
		{ "question": "分類", "answers": [ "ぶんるい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) classification" },
		{ "question": "切ない", "answers": [ "せつない" ], "comment": "(adj) painful/trying/oppressive/suffocating" },
		{ "question": "切り", "answers": [ "きり" ], "comment": "(n,suf) limits/end/bounds/period/place to leave off/closing sentence/all there is/only/since" },
		{ "question": "切る", "answers": [ "きる" ], "comment": "(suf,v5r) to cut/to chop/to hash/to carve/to saw/to clip/to shear/to slice/to strip/to fell/to cut down/to punch/to sever (connections)/to pause/to break off/to disconnect/to turn off/to hang up/to cross (a street)/to discount/to sell below cost/to shake (water) off/to finish/to be through/to complete" },
		{ "question": "切れ", "answers": [ "きれ" ], "comment": "(n) cloth/piece/cut/chop/strip/slice/scrap/counter for such" },
		{ "question": "切れる", "answers": [ "きれる" ], "comment": "(v1) (1) to cut well/to be sharp/(2) to break (off)/to snap/to wear out/(3) to be injured/(4) to burst/to collapse/(5) to be disconnected/to be out of/to expire/to sever (connections) with/(6) to be shrewd/to have a sharp mind" },
		{ "question": "切れ目", "answers": [ "きれめ" ], "comment": "(n) break/pause/gap/end/rift/interruption/cut/section/notch/incision/end (of a task)" },
		{ "question": "切実", "answers": [ "せつじつ" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) compelling/serious/severe/acute/earnest/pressing/urgent" },
		{ "question": "切手", "answers": [ "きって" ], "comment": "man of ability" },
		{ "question": "切替", "answers": [ "きりかえ" ], "comment": "(n) exchange/conversion/replacement/switching (to)/switchover" },
		{ "question": "切符", "answers": [ "きっぷ" ], "comment": "(n) ticket" },
		{ "question": "切開", "answers": [ "せっかい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) clearing (land)/opening up/cutting through" },
		{ "question": "刈る", "answers": [ "かる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to cut (hair)/to mow (grass)/to harvest/to clip/to shear/to reap/to trim/to prune" },
		{ "question": "刊行", "answers": [ "かんこう" ], "comment": "(n) publication/issue" },
		{ "question": "刑", "answers": [ "けい" ], "comment": "(n,n-suf,vs) penalty/sentence/punishment" },
		{ "question": "刑事", "answers": [ "けいじ" ], "comment": "(n) criminal case/(police) detective" },
		{ "question": "刑罰", "answers": [ "けいばつ" ], "comment": "(n) judgement/penalty/punishment" },
		{ "question": "列", "answers": [ "れつ" ], "comment": "(n) queue/line/row" },
		{ "question": "列島", "answers": [ "れっとう" ], "comment": "(n) chain of islands" },
		{ "question": "列車", "answers": [ "れっしゃ" ], "comment": "(n) train (ordinary)" },
		{ "question": "初めて", "answers": [ "はじめて" ], "comment": "(adv,n) for the first time" },
		{ "question": "初めに", "answers": [ "はじめに" ], "comment": "(expr) to begin with/first of all" },
		{ "question": "初旬", "answers": [ "しょじゅん" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n) first 10 days of the month" },
		{ "question": "初歩", "answers": [ "しょほ" ], "comment": "(adj-no,n) elements/rudiments/ABC's of.." },
		{ "question": "初版", "answers": [ "しょはん" ], "comment": "(n) first edition" },
		{ "question": "初級", "answers": [ "しょきゅう" ], "comment": "(n) elementary level" },
		{ "question": "初耳", "answers": [ "はつみみ" ], "comment": "(n) something heard for the first time" },
		{ "question": "判", "answers": [ "はん" ], "comment": "(n,n-suf) size (of paper or books)" },
		{ "question": "判事", "answers": [ "はんじ" ], "comment": "(n) judge/judiciary" },
		{ "question": "判子", "answers": [ "はんこ" ], "comment": "(n) seal (used for signature)" },
		{ "question": "判定", "answers": [ "はんてい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) judgement/decision/award/verdict" },
		{ "question": "判断", "answers": [ "はんだん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) judgement/decision/adjudication/conclusion/decipherment/divination" },
		{ "question": "判決", "answers": [ "はんけつ" ], "comment": "(n) judicial decision/judgement/sentence/decree" },
		{ "question": "別", "answers": [ "べつ" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n,n-suf) distinction/difference/different/another/particular/separate/extra/exception" },
		{ "question": "別々", "answers": [ "べつべつ" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) separately/individually" },
		{ "question": "別に", "answers": [ "べつに" ], "comment": "(adv) (not) particularly/nothing" },
		{ "question": "別れ", "answers": [ "わかれ" ], "comment": "(n) parting/separation/farewell/(lateral) branch/fork/offshoot/division/section" },
		{ "question": "別れる", "answers": [ "わかれる" ], "comment": "(v1) to be divided/to part from/to separate/to bid farewell" },
		{ "question": "別荘", "answers": [ "べっそう" ], "comment": "(n) holiday house/villa" },
		{ "question": "利口", "answers": [ "りこう" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) clever/shrewd/bright/sharp/wise/intelligent" },
		{ "question": "利子", "answers": [ "りし" ], "comment": "(n) interest (bank)" },
		{ "question": "利害", "answers": [ "りがい" ], "comment": "(n) advantages and disadvantages/interest" },
		{ "question": "利息", "answers": [ "りそく" ], "comment": "(n) interest (bank)" },
		{ "question": "利潤", "answers": [ "りじゅん" ], "comment": "(n) profit/returns" },
		{ "question": "利点", "answers": [ "りてん" ], "comment": "(n) advantage/point in favor" },
		{ "question": "利用", "answers": [ "りよう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) use/utilization/application" },
		{ "question": "利益", "answers": [ "りえき" ], "comment": "(n) profits/gains/(political, economic) interest" },
		{ "question": "到底", "answers": [ "とうてい" ], "comment": "(adv) (cannot) possibly" },
		{ "question": "到着", "answers": [ "とうちゃく" ], "comment": "(n,vs) arrival" },
		{ "question": "到達", "answers": [ "とうたつ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) reaching/attaining/arrival" },
		{ "question": "制する", "answers": [ "せいする" ], "comment": "(vs-s) to control/to command/to get the better of" },
		{ "question": "制作", "answers": [ "せいさく" ], "comment": "(n,vs) work (film, book)" },
		{ "question": "制定", "answers": [ "せいてい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) enactment/establishment/creation" },
		{ "question": "制度", "answers": [ "せいど" ], "comment": "(n) system/institution/organization" },
		{ "question": "制服", "answers": [ "せいふく" ], "comment": "(n) uniform" },
		{ "question": "制約", "answers": [ "せいやく" ], "comment": "(n,vs) limitation/restriction/condition/constraints" },
		{ "question": "制裁", "answers": [ "せいさい" ], "comment": "(n) restraint/sanctions/punishment" },
		{ "question": "制限", "answers": [ "せいげん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) restriction/restraint/limitation" },
		{ "question": "刷る", "answers": [ "する" ], "comment": "(v5r) to print" },
		{ "question": "券", "answers": [ "けん" ], "comment": "(n,n-suf) ticket/coupon/bond/certificate" },
		{ "question": "刺さる", "answers": [ "ささる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to stick/to be stuck" },
		{ "question": "刺す", "answers": [ "さす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to pierce/to stab/to prick/to thrust/to bite/to sting/to pin down/to stitch/to put (a runner) out/to pole (a boat)/to catch (with a line)/to stick" },
		{ "question": "刺激", "answers": [ "しげき" ], "comment": "(n,vs) stimulus/impetus/incentive/excitement/irritation/encouragement/motivation" },
		{ "question": "刺繍", "answers": [ "ししゅう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) embroidery" },
		{ "question": "刺身", "answers": [ "さしみ" ], "comment": "(n) sliced raw fish" },
		{ "question": "刻む", "answers": [ "きざむ" ], "comment": "(v5m) to mince/to carve/to engrave/to cut fine/to chop up/to hash/to chisel/to notch" },
		{ "question": "剃る", "answers": [ "そる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to shave" },
		{ "question": "剃刀", "answers": [ "かみそり" ], "comment": "(n) razor" },
		{ "question": "削る", "answers": [ "けずる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to cut down little by little/to take a percentage" },
		{ "question": "削減", "answers": [ "さくげん" ], "comment": "(n) cut/reduction/curtailment" },
		{ "question": "削除", "answers": [ "さくじょ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) elimination/cancellation/deletion/erasure" },
		{ "question": "前", "answers": [ "まえ" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n-t,suf) (1) before/in front/fore part/ago/previously/(2) head (of a line)/(3) in the presence of/lady (so-and-so)/(4) (five minutes) to/(5) helping/portion" },
		{ "question": "前もって", "answers": [ "まえもって" ], "comment": "(adv) in advance/beforehand/previously" },
		{ "question": "前例", "answers": [ "ぜんれい" ], "comment": "(n) precedent" },
		{ "question": "前売", "answers": [ "まえうり" ], "comment": "(n) advance sale/booking" },
		{ "question": "前後", "answers": [ "ぜんご" ], "comment": "(n-adv,suf) around/throughout/front and back/before and behind/before and after/about that (time)/longitudinal/context/nearly/approximately" },
		{ "question": "前提", "answers": [ "ぜんてい" ], "comment": "(n) preamble/premise/reason/prerequisite" },
		{ "question": "前置き", "answers": [ "まえおき" ], "comment": "(n) preface/introduction" },
		{ "question": "前者", "answers": [ "ぜんしゃ" ], "comment": "(n) the former" },
		{ "question": "前途", "answers": [ "ぜんと" ], "comment": "(n) future prospects/outlook/the journey ahead" },
		{ "question": "前進", "answers": [ "ぜんしん" ], "comment": "(n) advance/drive/progress" },
		{ "question": "剥く", "answers": [ "むく" ], "comment": "(v5k) to peel/to skin/to pare/to hull" },
		{ "question": "剥ぐ", "answers": [ "はぐ" ], "comment": "(v5g) to tear off/to peel off/to rip off/to strip off/to skin/to flay/to disrobe/to deprive of" },
		{ "question": "剥げる", "answers": [ "はげる" ], "comment": "(v1) to come off/to be worn off/to fade/to discolor" },
		{ "question": "剥がす", "answers": [ "はがす" ], "comment": "(io) (v5s) to tear off/to peel off/to rip off/to strip off/to skin/to flay/to disrobe/to deprive of/to detach/to disconnect" },
		{ "question": "副詞", "answers": [ "ふくし" ], "comment": "(n) adverb" },
		{ "question": "割る", "answers": [ "わる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to divide/to cut/to break/to halve/to separate/to split/to rip/to crack/to smash/to dilute" },
		{ "question": "割れる", "answers": [ "われる" ], "comment": "(v1,vi) to break/to split/to cleave/to fissure/to be smashed/to crack/to be torn" },
		{ "question": "割合", "answers": [ "わりあい" ], "comment": "(adv,n) (1) rate/ratio/percentage/proportion/(2) comparatively/(3) contrary to expectations" },
		{ "question": "割引", "answers": [ "わりびき" ], "comment": "(n,suf) discount/reduction/rebate/tenths discounted" },
		{ "question": "割当", "answers": [ "わりあて" ], "comment": "(n) allotment/assignment/allocation/quota/rationing" },
		{ "question": "割算", "answers": [ "わりざん" ], "comment": "(n) division (math)" },
		{ "question": "割込む", "answers": [ "わりこむ" ], "comment": "(v5m) to cut in/to thrust oneself into/to wedge oneself in/to muscle in on/to interrupt/to disturb" },
		{ "question": "創作", "answers": [ "そうさく" ], "comment": "(n) production/literary creation/work" },
		{ "question": "創刊", "answers": [ "そうかん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) launching (e.g. newspaper)/first issue" },
		{ "question": "創立", "answers": [ "そうりつ" ], "comment": "(n) establishment/founding/organization" },
		{ "question": "創造", "answers": [ "そうぞう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) creation" },
		{ "question": "劇", "answers": [ "げき" ], "comment": "(n) drama/play" },
		{ "question": "劇団", "answers": [ "げきだん" ], "comment": "(n) troupe/theatrical company" },
		{ "question": "劇場", "answers": [ "げきじょう" ], "comment": "(n) theatre/playhouse" },
		{ "question": "力", "answers": [ "ちから" ], "comment": "(n-suf) strength/power" },
		{ "question": "力強い", "answers": [ "ちからづよい" ], "comment": "(adj) reassuring/emboldened" },
		{ "question": "功績", "answers": [ "こうせき" ], "comment": "(n) achievements/merit/meritorious service/meritorious deed" },
		{ "question": "加える", "answers": [ "くわえる" ], "comment": "(v1) to append/to sum up/to add (up)/to include/to increase/to inflict" },
		{ "question": "加わる", "answers": [ "くわわる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to join in/to accede to/to increase/to gain in (influence)" },
		{ "question": "加入", "answers": [ "かにゅう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) becoming a member/joining/entry/admission/subscription/affiliation/adherence/signing" },
		{ "question": "加味", "answers": [ "かみ" ], "comment": "(n) seasoning/flavoring" },
		{ "question": "加工", "answers": [ "かこう" ], "comment": "(n) manufacturing/processing/treatment" },
		{ "question": "加減", "answers": [ "かげん" ], "comment": "(n) addition and subtraction/allowance for/degree/extent/measure/condition/seasoning/flavor/moderation/adjustment/influence (of the weather)/state of health/chance" },
		{ "question": "加熱", "answers": [ "かねつ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) heating" },
		{ "question": "加速", "answers": [ "かそく" ], "comment": "(n,vs) acceleration" },
		{ "question": "加速度", "answers": [ "かそくど" ], "comment": "(n) acceleration" },
		{ "question": "劣る", "answers": [ "おとる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to fall behind/to be inferior to" },
		{ "question": "助かる", "answers": [ "たすかる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to be saved/to be rescued/to survive/to be helpful" },
		{ "question": "助け", "answers": [ "たすけ" ], "comment": "(n) assistance" },
		{ "question": "助ける", "answers": [ "たすける" ], "comment": "(v1) to help/to save/to rescue/to give relief to/to spare (life)/to reinforce/to promote/to abet" },
		{ "question": "助動詞", "answers": [ "じょどうし" ], "comment": "(n) auxiliary verb" },
		{ "question": "助手", "answers": [ "じょしゅ" ], "comment": "(n) helper/helpmeet/assistant/tutor" },
		{ "question": "助教授", "answers": [ "じょきょうじゅ" ], "comment": "(n) assistant professor" },
		{ "question": "助言", "answers": [ "じょげん" ], "comment": "(n) advice/suggestion" },
		{ "question": "助詞", "answers": [ "じょし" ], "comment": "(n) (gram) particle/postposition" },
		{ "question": "努めて", "answers": [ "つとめて" ], "comment": "(adv,exp) make an effort!/work hard!" },
		{ "question": "努める", "answers": [ "つとめる" ], "comment": "(v1) (1) to serve/to fill a post/to serve under/to work (for)/(2) to exert oneself/to endeavor/to be diligent/(3) to play (the part of)" },
		{ "question": "努力", "answers": [ "どりょく" ], "comment": "(n,vs) great effort/exertion/endeavour/effort" },
		{ "question": "励ます", "answers": [ "はげます" ], "comment": "(v5s) to encourage/to cheer/to raise (the voice)" },
		{ "question": "励む", "answers": [ "はげむ" ], "comment": "(v5m) to be zealous/to brace oneself/to endeavour/to strive/to make an effort" },
		{ "question": "労働", "answers": [ "ろうどう" ], "comment": "(n) manual labor/toil/work" },
		{ "question": "労力", "answers": [ "ろうりょく" ], "comment": "(n) labour/effort/toil/trouble" },
		{ "question": "効き目", "answers": [ "ききめ" ], "comment": "(n) effect/virtue/efficacy/impression" },
		{ "question": "効く", "answers": [ "きく" ], "comment": "(v5k) to be effective" },
		{ "question": "効力", "answers": [ "こうりょく" ], "comment": "(n) effect/efficacy/validity/potency" },
		{ "question": "効果", "answers": [ "こうか" ], "comment": "(n,adj-no) effect/effectiveness/efficacy/result" },
		{ "question": "効率", "answers": [ "こうりつ" ], "comment": "(n) efficiency" },
		{ "question": "勇ましい", "answers": [ "いさましい" ], "comment": "(adj) brave/valiant/gallant/courageous" },
		{ "question": "勇敢", "answers": [ "ゆうかん" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) bravery/heroism/gallantry" },
		{ "question": "勇気", "answers": [ "ゆうき" ], "comment": "(n) courage/bravery/valour/nerve/boldness" },
		{ "question": "勉強", "answers": [ "べんきょう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) study/diligence/discount/reduction" },
		{ "question": "動かす", "answers": [ "うごかす" ], "comment": "(v5s,vt) to move/to shift/to set in motion/to operate/to inspire/to rouse/to influence/to mobilize/to deny/to change" },
		{ "question": "動き", "answers": [ "うごき" ], "comment": "(n) movement/activity/trend/development/change" },
		{ "question": "動く", "answers": [ "うごく" ], "comment": "(v5k,vi) to move/to stir/to shift/to shake/to swing/to operate/to run/to go/to work/to be touched/to be influenced/to waver/to fluctuate/to vary/to change/to be transferred" },
		{ "question": "動作", "answers": [ "どうさ" ], "comment": "(n) action/movements/motions/bearing/behaviour/manners" },
		{ "question": "動力", "answers": [ "どうりょく" ], "comment": "(n) power/motive power/dynamic force" },
		{ "question": "動向", "answers": [ "どうこう" ], "comment": "(n) trend/tendency/movement/attitude" },
		{ "question": "動員", "answers": [ "どういん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) mobilization" },
		{ "question": "動揺", "answers": [ "どうよう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) disturbance/unrest/shaking/trembling/pitching/rolling/oscillation/agitation/excitement/commotion" },
		{ "question": "動機", "answers": [ "どうき" ], "comment": "(n) motive/incentive" },
		{ "question": "動物", "answers": [ "どうぶつ" ], "comment": "(n) animal" },
		{ "question": "動物園", "answers": [ "どうぶつえん" ], "comment": "(n) zoo/zoological gardens" },
		{ "question": "動的", "answers": [ "どうてき" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) dynamic/kinetic" },
		{ "question": "動詞", "answers": [ "どうし" ], "comment": "(n) verb" },
		{ "question": "勘", "answers": [ "かん" ], "comment": "(n) perception/intuition/the sixth sense" },
		{ "question": "勘定", "answers": [ "かんじょう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) calculation/counting/consideration/reckoning/settlement of an account/allowance" },
		{ "question": "勘弁", "answers": [ "かんべん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) pardon/forgiveness/forbearance" },
		{ "question": "勘違い", "answers": [ "かんちがい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) misunderstanding/wrong guess" },
		{ "question": "務め", "answers": [ "つとめ" ], "comment": "(n) (1) service/duty/business/responsibility/task/(2) Buddhist religious services" },
		{ "question": "務める", "answers": [ "つとめる" ], "comment": "(v1) (1) to serve/to fill a post/to serve under/to work (for)/(2) to exert oneself/to endeavor/to be diligent/(3) to play (the part of)" },
		{ "question": "勝ち", "answers": [ "かち" ], "comment": "(n) win/victory" },
		{ "question": "勝つ", "answers": [ "かつ" ], "comment": "(v5t) to win/to gain victory" },
		{ "question": "勝る", "answers": [ "まさる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to excel/to surpass/to outrival" },
		{ "question": "勝利", "answers": [ "しょうり" ], "comment": "(n) victory/triumph/conquest/success/win" },
		{ "question": "勝手", "answers": [ "かって" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) kitchen/one's own convenience/one's way/selfishness" },
		{ "question": "勝手に", "answers": [ "かってに" ], "comment": "arbitrarily/of it's own accord/involuntarily/wilfully/as one pleases" },
		{ "question": "勝敗", "answers": [ "しょうはい" ], "comment": "(n) victory or defeat/issue (of battle)" },
		{ "question": "勝負", "answers": [ "しょうぶ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) victory or defeat/match/contest/game/bout" },
		{ "question": "募る", "answers": [ "つのる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to invite/to solicit help, participation, etc" },
		{ "question": "募金", "answers": [ "ぼきん" ], "comment": "(n) fund-raising/collection of funds" },
		{ "question": "募集", "answers": [ "ぼしゅう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) recruiting/taking applications" },
		{ "question": "勢い", "answers": [ "いきおい" ], "comment": "(adv,n) force/vigor/energy/spirit/life/authority/influence/power/might/impetus/course (of events)/tendency/necessarily" },
		{ "question": "勢力", "answers": [ "せいりょく" ], "comment": "(n) influence/power/might/strength/potency/force/energy" },
		{ "question": "勤め", "answers": [ "つとめ" ], "comment": "(n) (1) service/duty/business/responsibility/task/(2) Buddhist religious services" },
		{ "question": "勤める", "answers": [ "つとめる" ], "comment": "(v1) (1) to serve/to fill a post/to serve under/to work (for)/(2) to exert oneself/to endeavor/to be diligent/(3) to play (the part of)" },
		{ "question": "勤め先", "answers": [ "つとめさき" ], "comment": "(n) place of work" },
		{ "question": "勤労", "answers": [ "きんろう" ], "comment": "(n) labor/exertion/diligent service" },
		{ "question": "勤勉", "answers": [ "きんべん" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) industry/diligence" },
		{ "question": "勤務", "answers": [ "きんむ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) service/duty/work" },
		{ "question": "勧める", "answers": [ "すすめる" ], "comment": "(v1) to recommend/to advise/to encourage/to offer (wine)" },
		{ "question": "勧告", "answers": [ "かんこく" ], "comment": "(n,vs) advice/counsel/remonstrance/recommendation" },
		{ "question": "勧誘", "answers": [ "かんゆう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) invitation/solicitation/canvassing/inducement/persuasion/encouragement" },
		{ "question": "勿論", "answers": [ "もちろん" ], "comment": "(adv) (uk) of course/certainly/naturally" },
		{ "question": "匂い", "answers": [ "におい" ], "comment": "(n) odour/scent/smell/stench/fragrance/aroma/perfume" },
		{ "question": "匂う", "answers": [ "におう" ], "comment": "(v5u,vi) to be fragrant/to smell/to stink/to glow/to be bright" },
		{ "question": "包み", "answers": [ "つつみ" ], "comment": "(n) bundle/package/parcel/bale" },
		{ "question": "包む", "answers": [ "つつむ", "くるむ" ], "comment": "(v5m) to be engulfed in/to be enveloped by/to wrap up/to tuck in/to pack/to do up/to cover with/to dress in/to conceal" },
		{ "question": "包帯", "answers": [ "ほうたい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) bandage/dressing" },
		{ "question": "包装", "answers": [ "ほうそう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) packing/wrapping" },
		{ "question": "化ける", "answers": [ "ばける" ], "comment": "(v1) to change with age/to spoil from weathering" },
		{ "question": "化合", "answers": [ "かごう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) chemical combination" },
		{ "question": "化学", "answers": [ "かがく" ], "comment": "(n) chemistry" },
		{ "question": "化石", "answers": [ "かせき" ], "comment": "(n) fossil/petrifaction/fossilization" },
		{ "question": "化粧", "answers": [ "けしょう" ], "comment": "(n) make-up (cosmetic)" },
		{ "question": "化繊", "answers": [ "かせん" ], "comment": "(n) synthetic fibres" },
		{ "question": "北", "answers": [ "きた" ], "comment": "north" },
		{ "question": "北極", "answers": [ "ほっきょく" ], "comment": "(n) North Pole" },
		{ "question": "匙", "answers": [ "さじ" ], "comment": "(n) spoon" },
		{ "question": "匹敵", "answers": [ "ひってき" ], "comment": "(n,vs) comparing with/match/rival/equal" },
		{ "question": "区分", "answers": [ "くぶん" ], "comment": "(n) division/section/demarcation/(traffic) lane/compartment/classification/sorting" },
		{ "question": "区切り", "answers": [ "くぎり" ], "comment": "(n) an end/a stop/punctuation" },
		{ "question": "区切る", "answers": [ "くぎる" ], "comment": "(v5r,vt) to punctuate/to cut off/to mark off/to stop/to put an end to" },
		{ "question": "区別", "answers": [ "くべつ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) distinction/differentiation/classification" },
		{ "question": "区域", "answers": [ "くいき" ], "comment": "(n) limits/boundary/domain/zone/sphere/territory" },
		{ "question": "区画", "answers": [ "くかく" ], "comment": "(n) division/section/compartment/boundary/area/block" },
		{ "question": "区間", "answers": [ "くかん" ], "comment": "(n,n-suf) section (of track, etc)" },
		{ "question": "医学", "answers": [ "いがく" ], "comment": "(n) medical science/medicine" },
		{ "question": "医師", "answers": [ "いし" ], "comment": "(n) doctor/physician" },
		{ "question": "医療", "answers": [ "いりょう" ], "comment": "(n) medical care/medical treatment" },
		{ "question": "医者", "answers": [ "いしゃ" ], "comment": "(n) doctor (medical)" },
		{ "question": "医院", "answers": [ "いいん" ], "comment": "(n) doctor's office (surgery)/clinic/dispensary" },
		{ "question": "十", "answers": [ "じゅう","とお" ], "comment": "(num) 10/ten" },
		{ "question": "十分", "answers": [ "じゅうぶん" ], "comment": "10 minutes" },
		{ "question": "十字路", "answers": [ "じゅうじろ" ], "comment": "(n) crossroads" },
		{ "question": "十日", "answers": [ "とおか" ], "comment": "ten days/the tenth (day of the month)" },
		{ "question": "千", "answers": [ "せん" ], "comment": "thousand/many" },
		{ "question": "午前", "answers": [ "ごぜん" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n-t) morning/A.M./am" },
		{ "question": "午後", "answers": [ "ごご" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n-t) afternoon/p.m./pm" },
		{ "question": "半", "answers": [ "はん" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n,n-suf) half" },
		{ "question": "半ば", "answers": [ "なかば" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n) middle/half/semi/halfway/partly" },
		{ "question": "半分", "answers": [ "はんぶん" ], "comment": "half minute" },
		{ "question": "半島", "answers": [ "はんとう" ], "comment": "(n) peninsula" },
		{ "question": "半径", "answers": [ "はんけい" ], "comment": "(n) radius" },
		{ "question": "半端", "answers": [ "はんぱ" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) remnant/fragment/incomplete set/fraction/odd sum/incompleteness" },
		{ "question": "卑しい", "answers": [ "いやしい" ], "comment": "(adj) greedy/vulgar/shabby/humble/base/mean/vile" },
		{ "question": "卑怯", "answers": [ "ひきょう" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) cowardice/meanness/unfairness" },
		{ "question": "卒業", "answers": [ "そつぎょう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) graduation" },
		{ "question": "卒直", "answers": [ "そっちょく" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) frankness/candour/openheartedness" },
		{ "question": "協会", "answers": [ "きょうかい" ], "comment": "(n) association/society/organization" },
		{ "question": "協力", "answers": [ "きょうりょく" ], "comment": "(n,vs) cooperation/collaboration" },
		{ "question": "協定", "answers": [ "きょうてい" ], "comment": "(n) arrangement/pact/agreement" },
		{ "question": "協調", "answers": [ "きょうちょう" ], "comment": "(n) co-operation/conciliation/harmony/firm (market) tone" },
		{ "question": "協議", "answers": [ "きょうぎ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) conference/consultation/discussion/negotiation" },
		{ "question": "南", "answers": [ "みなみ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) South/proceeding south" },
		{ "question": "南北", "answers": [ "なんぼく" ], "comment": "(n) south and north" },
		{ "question": "南極", "answers": [ "なんきょく" ], "comment": "(n) south pole/Antarctic" },
		{ "question": "南米", "answers": [ "なんべい" ], "comment": "(n) South America" },
		{ "question": "単なる", "answers": [ "たんなる" ], "comment": "(adj-pn) mere/simple/sheer" },
		{ "question": "単に", "answers": [ "たんに" ], "comment": "(adv,n) simply/merely/only/solely" },
		{ "question": "単一", "answers": [ "たんいつ" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) single/simple/sole/individual/unitory" },
		{ "question": "単位", "answers": [ "たんい" ], "comment": "(n) unit/denomination/credit (in school)" },
		{ "question": "単数", "answers": [ "たんすう" ], "comment": "(n) singular (number)" },
		{ "question": "単独", "answers": [ "たんどく" ], "comment": "(adj-no,n) sole/independence/single/solo (flight)" },
		{ "question": "単純", "answers": [ "たんじゅん" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) simplicity" },
		{ "question": "単語", "answers": [ "たんご" ], "comment": "(n) word/vocabulary/(usually) single-character word" },
		{ "question": "単調", "answers": [ "たんちょう" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) monotony/monotone/dullness" },
		{ "question": "博士", "answers": [ "はかせ" ], "comment": "(n) doctorate/PhD" },
		{ "question": "博物館", "answers": [ "はくぶつかん" ], "comment": "(n) museum" },
		{ "question": "占う", "answers": [ "うらなう" ], "comment": "(v5u) to forecast/to predict" },
		{ "question": "占める", "answers": [ "しめる" ], "comment": "(v1) (1) to comprise/to account for/to make up (of)/(2) to hold/to occupy" },
		{ "question": "占領", "answers": [ "せんりょう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) occupation/capture/possession/have a room to oneself" },
		{ "question": "印", "answers": [ "しるし" ], "comment": "(n) (1) mark/(2) symbol/(3) evidence" },
		{ "question": "印刷", "answers": [ "いんさつ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) printing" },
		{ "question": "印象", "answers": [ "いんしょう" ], "comment": "(n) impression" },
		{ "question": "印鑑", "answers": [ "いんかん" ], "comment": "(n) stamp/seal" },
		{ "question": "危うい", "answers": [ "あやうい" ], "comment": "(adj) dangerous/critical/grave/uncertain/unreliable/limping/narrow/close/watch out!" },
		{ "question": "危ない", "answers": [ "あぶない" ], "comment": "(adj) dangerous/critical/grave/uncertain/unreliable/limping/narrow/close/watch out!" },
		{ "question": "危ぶむ", "answers": [ "あやぶむ" ], "comment": "(v5m) to fear/to have misgivings/to be doubtful/to mistrust" },
		{ "question": "危害", "answers": [ "きがい" ], "comment": "(n) injury/harm/danger" },
		{ "question": "危機", "answers": [ "きき" ], "comment": "(n) crisis" },
		{ "question": "危険", "answers": [ "きけん" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) danger/peril/hazard" },
		{ "question": "即する", "answers": [ "そくする" ], "comment": "(vs-s) to conform to/to agree with/to be adapted to/to be based on" },
		{ "question": "即座に", "answers": [ "そくざに" ], "comment": "immediately/right away" },
		{ "question": "却って", "answers": [ "かえって" ], "comment": "(adv) on the contrary/rather/all the more/instead" },
		{ "question": "卵", "answers": [ "たまご" ], "comment": "(n) (1) egg(s)/spawn/roe/(2) (an expert) in the making" },
		{ "question": "卸す", "answers": [ "おろす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to sell wholesale/grated (vegetables)" },
		{ "question": "厄介", "answers": [ "やっかい" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) trouble/burden/care/bother/worry/dependence/support/kindness/obligation" },
		{ "question": "厚い", "answers": [ "あつい" ], "comment": "(adj) cordial/kind/warm(hearted)/thick/deep" },
		{ "question": "厚かましい", "answers": [ "あつかましい" ], "comment": "(adj) impudent/shameless/brazen" },
		{ "question": "原", "answers": [ "はら" ], "comment": "(n) field/plain/prairie/tundra/moor/wilderness" },
		{ "question": "原っぱ", "answers": [ "はらっぱ" ], "comment": "(n) open field/empty lot/plain" },
		{ "question": "原作", "answers": [ "げんさく" ], "comment": "(n) original work" },
		{ "question": "原典", "answers": [ "げんてん" ], "comment": "(n) original (text)" },
		{ "question": "原則", "answers": [ "げんそく" ], "comment": "(n) principle/general rule" },
		{ "question": "原因", "answers": [ "げんいん" ], "comment": "(n) cause/origin/source" },
		{ "question": "原型", "answers": [ "げんけい" ], "comment": "(adj-no,n) prototype/model/pattern/archetypal" },
		{ "question": "原始", "answers": [ "げんし" ], "comment": "(n) origin/primeval" },
		{ "question": "原子", "answers": [ "げんし" ], "comment": "(n) atom" },
		{ "question": "原形", "answers": [ "げんけい" ], "comment": "(n) original form/base form" },
		{ "question": "原文", "answers": [ "げんぶん" ], "comment": "(n) the text/original" },
		{ "question": "原料", "answers": [ "げんりょう" ], "comment": "(n) raw materials" },
		{ "question": "原書", "answers": [ "げんしょ" ], "comment": "(n) original document" },
		{ "question": "原油", "answers": [ "げんゆ" ], "comment": "(n) crude oil" },
		{ "question": "原点", "answers": [ "げんてん" ], "comment": "(n) origin (coordinates)/starting point" },
		{ "question": "原爆", "answers": [ "げんばく" ], "comment": "(n) atomic bomb" },
		{ "question": "原理", "answers": [ "げんり" ], "comment": "(n) principle/theory/fundamental truth" },
		{ "question": "原産", "answers": [ "げんさん" ], "comment": "(n) place of origin/habitat" },
		{ "question": "原稿", "answers": [ "げんこう" ], "comment": "(n) manuscript/copy" },
		{ "question": "厳か", "answers": [ "おごそか" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) austere/majestic/dignified/stately/awful/impressive" },
		{ "question": "厳しい", "answers": [ "きびしい" ], "comment": "(adj) severe/strict/stern/austere/grave/solemn/majestic/intense (cold)" },
		{ "question": "厳密", "answers": [ "げんみつ" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) strict/close" },
		{ "question": "厳重", "answers": [ "げんじゅう" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) strict/rigour/severe/firm/strong/secure" },
		{ "question": "去る", "answers": [ "さる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to leave/to go away" },
		{ "question": "去年", "answers": [ "きょねん" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n-t) last year" },
		{ "question": "参る", "answers": [ "まいる" ], "comment": "(v5r) (1) (hum) to go/to come/to call/(2) to be defeated/to collapse/to die/(3) to be annoyed/to be nonplussed/(4) to be madly in love/(5) to visit (shrine, grave)" },
		{ "question": "参上", "answers": [ "さんじょう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) calling on/visiting" },
		{ "question": "参加", "answers": [ "さんか" ], "comment": "(n,vs) participation" },
		{ "question": "参照", "answers": [ "さんしょう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) reference/consultation/consultation" },
		{ "question": "参考", "answers": [ "さんこう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) reference/consultation" },
		{ "question": "参議院", "answers": [ "さんぎいん" ], "comment": "(n) House of Councillors" },
		{ "question": "又", "answers": [ "また" ], "comment": "(adv,conj,n) again/and" },
		{ "question": "又は", "answers": [ "または" ], "comment": "(conj,exp) or/otherwise" },
		{ "question": "及び", "answers": [ "および" ], "comment": "(conj) and/as well as" },
		{ "question": "及ぶ", "answers": [ "およぶ" ], "comment": "(v5b) to reach/to come up to/to amount to/to befall/to happen to/to extend/to match/to equal" },
		{ "question": "及ぼす", "answers": [ "およぼす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to exert/to cause/to exercise" },
		{ "question": "友", "answers": [ "とも" ], "comment": "(n) friend/companion/pal" },
		{ "question": "友人", "answers": [ "ゆうじん" ], "comment": "(n) friend" },
		{ "question": "友好", "answers": [ "ゆうこう" ], "comment": "(n) friendship" },
		{ "question": "友情", "answers": [ "ゆうじょう" ], "comment": "(n) friendship/fellowship" },
		{ "question": "友達", "answers": [ "ともだち" ], "comment": "(n) friend" },
		{ "question": "双子", "answers": [ "ふたご" ], "comment": "(n) twins/a twin" },
		{ "question": "反する", "answers": [ "はんする" ], "comment": "(vs-s) to be inconsistent with/to oppose/to contradict/to transgress/to rebel" },
		{ "question": "反る", "answers": [ "かえる","そる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to warp/to be warped/to curve/to be curved/to be arched/to bend (backward)" },
		{ "question": "反乱", "answers": [ "はんらん" ], "comment": "(n) insurrection/mutiny/rebellion/revolt/uprising" },
		{ "question": "反対", "answers": [ "はんたい" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n,vs) opposition/resistance/antagonism/hostility/contrast/objection/dissension/reverse/opposite/vice versa" },
		{ "question": "反射", "answers": [ "はんしゃ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) reflection/reverberation" },
		{ "question": "反応", "answers": [ "はんのう" ], "comment": "(n) reaction/response" },
		{ "question": "反感", "answers": [ "はんかん" ], "comment": "(n) antipathy/revolt/animosity" },
		{ "question": "反抗", "answers": [ "はんこう" ], "comment": "(n) opposition/resistance/insubordination/defiance/hostility/rebellion" },
		{ "question": "反撃", "answers": [ "はんげき" ], "comment": "(n,vs) counterattack/counteroffensive/counterblow" },
		{ "question": "反映", "answers": [ "はんえい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) reflection/influence" },
		{ "question": "反発", "answers": [ "はんぱつ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) repelling/rebound/recover/oppose" },
		{ "question": "反省", "answers": [ "はんせい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) reflection/reconsideration/introspection/meditation/contemplation" },
		{ "question": "反響", "answers": [ "はんきょう" ], "comment": "(n) echo/reverberation/repercussion/reaction/influence" },
		{ "question": "収まる", "answers": [ "おさまる" ], "comment": "(v5r) (1) to be in one's place/to be installed/to settle into/(2) to be obtained/to be settled/to be paid/to be delivered" },
		{ "question": "収める", "answers": [ "おさめる" ], "comment": "(v1) to obtain/to reap/to pay/to supply/to accept" },
		{ "question": "収入", "answers": [ "しゅうにゅう" ], "comment": "(n) income/receipts/revenue" },
		{ "question": "収容", "answers": [ "しゅうよう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) (1) accommodation/reception/housing/(2) seating/(3) custody/(4) admission/(5) entering (in a dictionary)" },
		{ "question": "収支", "answers": [ "しゅうし" ], "comment": "(n) income and expenditure" },
		{ "question": "収益", "answers": [ "しゅうえき" ], "comment": "(n) earnings/proceeds/returns" },
		{ "question": "収穫", "answers": [ "しゅうかく" ], "comment": "(n,vs) harvest/crop/ingathering" },
		{ "question": "収集", "answers": [ "しゅうしゅう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) gathering up/collection/accumulation" },
		{ "question": "叔母", "answers": [ "おば" ], "comment": "(n) aunt (younger than one's parent)" },
		{ "question": "叔母さん", "answers": [ "おばさん" ], "comment": "(n) (1) aunt/(2) middle-aged lady" },
		{ "question": "叔父", "answers": [ "おじ" ], "comment": "(n) uncle (younger than one's parent)" },
		{ "question": "叔父さん", "answers": [ "おじさん" ], "comment": "(n) (hon) (uk) middle-aged gentleman/uncle" },
		{ "question": "取り上げる", "answers": [ "とりあげる" ], "comment": "(v1) to take up/to pick up/to disqualify/to confiscate/to deprive" },
		{ "question": "取り付ける", "answers": [ "とりつける" ], "comment": "(v1) to furnish/to install/to get someone's agreement" },
		{ "question": "取り入れる", "answers": [ "とりいれる" ], "comment": "(v1) to harvest/to take in/to adopt" },
		{ "question": "取り出す", "answers": [ "とりだす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to take out/to produce/to pick out" },
		{ "question": "取り寄せる", "answers": [ "とりよせる" ], "comment": "(v1) to order/to send away for" },
		{ "question": "取り巻く", "answers": [ "とりまく" ], "comment": "(v5k) to surround/to circle/to enclose" },
		{ "question": "取り戻す", "answers": [ "とりもどす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to take back/to regain" },
		{ "question": "取り扱う", "answers": [ "とりあつかう" ], "comment": "(v5u) to treat/to handle/to deal in" },
		{ "question": "取り替え", "answers": [ "とりかえ" ], "comment": "(n) swap/exchange" },
		{ "question": "取り替える", "answers": [ "とりかえる" ], "comment": "(v1) to exchange/to replace" },
		{ "question": "取り次ぐ", "answers": [ "とりつぐ" ], "comment": "(v5g) to act as an agent for/to announce (someone)/to convey (a message)" },
		{ "question": "取り消す", "answers": [ "とりけす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to cancel" },
		{ "question": "取り混ぜる", "answers": [ "とりまぜる" ], "comment": "(v1) to mix/to put together" },
		{ "question": "取り立てる", "answers": [ "とりたてる" ], "comment": "(v1) to collect/to extort/to appoint/to promote" },
		{ "question": "取り組む", "answers": [ "とりくむ" ], "comment": "(v5m) to tackle/to wrestle with/to engage in a bout/to come to grips with" },
		{ "question": "取り締まる", "answers": [ "とりしまる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to manage/to control/to supervise" },
		{ "question": "取り調べる", "answers": [ "とりしらべる" ], "comment": "(v1) to investigate/to examine" },
		{ "question": "取り除く", "answers": [ "とりのぞく" ], "comment": "(v5k) to remove/to take away/to set apart" },
		{ "question": "取る", "answers": [ "とる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to take/to pick up/to harvest/to earn/to choose" },
		{ "question": "取れる", "answers": [ "とれる" ], "comment": "(v1) to come off/to be taken off/to be removed/to be obtained/to leave/to come out (e.g. photo)/to be interpreted" },
		{ "question": "取引", "answers": [ "とりひき" ], "comment": "(n) transactions/dealings/business" },
		{ "question": "取扱", "answers": [ "とりあつかい" ], "comment": "(n) treatment/service/handling/management" },
		{ "question": "取材", "answers": [ "しゅざい" ], "comment": "(n) choice of subject/collecting data" },
		{ "question": "取締り", "answers": [ "とりしまり" ], "comment": "(n) control/management/supervision" },
		{ "question": "受かる", "answers": [ "うかる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to pass (examination)" },
		{ "question": "受ける", "answers": [ "うける" ], "comment": "(v1) to undertake/to accept/to take (lesson, test, damage)/to undergo/to experience/to catch (e.g. a ball)/to become popular" },
		{ "question": "受け付ける", "answers": [ "うけつける" ], "comment": "(v1) to be accepted/to receive (an application)" },
		{ "question": "受け入れ", "answers": [ "うけいれ" ], "comment": "(n) receiving/acceptance" },
		{ "question": "受け入れる", "answers": [ "うけいれる" ], "comment": "(v1) to accept/to receive" },
		{ "question": "受け取る", "answers": [ "うけとる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to receive/to get/to accept/to take/to interpret/to understand" },
		{ "question": "受け持つ", "answers": [ "うけもつ" ], "comment": "(v5t) to take (be in) charge of" },
		{ "question": "受け止める", "answers": [ "うけとめる" ], "comment": "(v1) to catch/to stop the blow/to react to/to take" },
		{ "question": "受け継ぐ", "answers": [ "うけつぐ" ], "comment": "(v5g) to inherit/to succeed/to take over" },
		{ "question": "受付", "answers": [ "うけつけ" ], "comment": "(n) receipt/acceptance/reception (desk)/information desk" },
		{ "question": "受取", "answers": [ "うけとり" ], "comment": "(n) receipt" },
		{ "question": "受持ち", "answers": [ "うけもち" ], "comment": "(n) charge (of something)/matter in one's charge" },
		{ "question": "受話器", "answers": [ "じゅわき" ], "comment": "(n) (telephone) receiver" },
		{ "question": "受身", "answers": [ "うけみ" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) passive/passive voice" },
		{ "question": "受験", "answers": [ "じゅけん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) taking an examination" },
		{ "question": "口", "answers": [ "くち" ], "comment": "(n) mouth/orifice/opening" },
		{ "question": "口実", "answers": [ "こうじつ" ], "comment": "(n) excuse" },
		{ "question": "口紅", "answers": [ "くちべに" ], "comment": "(n) lipstick" },
		{ "question": "口述", "answers": [ "こうじゅつ" ], "comment": "(n) verbal statement" },
		{ "question": "口頭", "answers": [ "こうとう" ], "comment": "(n) oral" },
		{ "question": "古い", "answers": [ "ふるい" ], "comment": "(adj) old (not person)/aged/ancient/antiquated/stale/threadbare/outmoded/obsolete article" },
		{ "question": "古代", "answers": [ "こだい" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n-adv,n-t) ancient times" },
		{ "question": "古典", "answers": [ "こてん" ], "comment": "(n) old book/classics/classic" },
		{ "question": "古里", "answers": [ "ふるさと" ], "comment": "(n) home town/birthplace/old village/historic village/native place/one's old home" },
		{ "question": "句", "answers": [ "く" ], "comment": "sentence" },
		{ "question": "句読点", "answers": [ "くとうてん" ], "comment": "(n) punctuation marks" },
		{ "question": "叩く", "answers": [ "たたく","はたく" ], "comment": "(v5k) to strike/to clap/to dust/to beat" },
		{ "question": "只", "answers": [ "ただ" ], "comment": "(adj-pn,adv,conj) free of charge/mere/sole/only/usual/common" },
		{ "question": "叫び", "answers": [ "さけび" ], "comment": "(n) shout/scream/outcry" },
		{ "question": "叫ぶ", "answers": [ "さけぶ" ], "comment": "(v5b) to shout/to cry" },
		{ "question": "召し上がる", "answers": [ "めしあがる" ], "comment": "(v5r) (pol) to eat" },
		{ "question": "召す", "answers": [ "めす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to call/to send for/to put on/to wear/to take (a bath)/to ride in/to buy/to eat/to drink/to catch (a cold)" },
		{ "question": "可", "answers": [ "か" ], "comment": "(n,n-suf) passable" },
		{ "question": "可決", "answers": [ "かけつ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) approval/adoption (e.g. motion, bill)/passage" },
		{ "question": "可能", "answers": [ "かのう" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) possible/practicable/feasible" },
		{ "question": "台", "answers": [ "だい" ], "comment": "(n,n-suf) stand/rack/table/support" },
		{ "question": "台所", "answers": [ "だいどころ" ], "comment": "(n) kitchen" },
		{ "question": "台本", "answers": [ "だいほん" ], "comment": "(n) libretto/scenario" },
		{ "question": "台無し", "answers": [ "だいなし" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) mess/spoiled/(come to) nothing" },
		{ "question": "台詞", "answers": [ "せりふ" ], "comment": "(n) speech/words/one's lines/remarks" },
		{ "question": "台風", "answers": [ "たいふう" ], "comment": "(n) typhoon" },
		{ "question": "叱る", "answers": [ "しかる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to scold" },
		{ "question": "右", "answers": [ "みぎ" ], "comment": "(n) right hand side" },
		{ "question": "叶う", "answers": [ "かなう" ], "comment": "(v5u) to come true (wish)" },
		{ "question": "叶える", "answers": [ "かなえる" ], "comment": "(v1) to grant (request, wish)" },
		{ "question": "司る", "answers": [ "つかさどる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to rule/to govern/to administer" },
		{ "question": "司会", "answers": [ "しかい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) chairmanship" },
		{ "question": "司法", "answers": [ "しほう" ], "comment": "(n) administration of justice" },
		{ "question": "各々", "answers": [ "おのおの" ], "comment": "each/every/either/respectively/severally" },
		{ "question": "各地", "answers": [ "かくち" ], "comment": "(n) every place/various places" },
		{ "question": "各種", "answers": [ "かくしゅ" ], "comment": "(n) every kind/all sorts" },
		{ "question": "各自", "answers": [ "かくじ" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n-t) individual/each" },
		{ "question": "合う", "answers": [ "あう" ], "comment": "(v5u) to fit/to suit/to agree with/to match/to be correct/to be profitable" },
		{ "question": "合わす", "answers": [ "あわす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to join together/to face/to unite/to be opposite/to combine/to connect/to add up/to mix/to match/to overlap/to compare/to check with" },
		{ "question": "合わせる", "answers": [ "あわせる" ], "comment": "(v1) to join together/to be opposite/to face/to unite/to combine/to connect/to add up/to mix/to match/to overlap/to compare/to check with" },
		{ "question": "合併", "answers": [ "がっぺい" ], "comment": "(ok) (n) combination/union/amalgamation/consolidation/merger/coalition/fusion/annexation/affiliation/incorporation" },
		{ "question": "合同", "answers": [ "ごうどう" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) combination/incorporation/union/amalgamation/fusion/congruence" },
		{ "question": "合唱", "answers": [ "がっしょう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) chorus/singing in a chorus" },
		{ "question": "合図", "answers": [ "あいず" ], "comment": "(n,vs) sign/signal" },
		{ "question": "合意", "answers": [ "ごうい" ], "comment": "(n) agreement/consent/mutual understanding" },
		{ "question": "合成", "answers": [ "ごうせい" ], "comment": "(n) synthesis/composition/synthetic/composite/mixed/combined/compound" },
		{ "question": "合格", "answers": [ "ごうかく" ], "comment": "(n,vs) success/passing (e.g. exam)/eligibility" },
		{ "question": "合流", "answers": [ "ごうりゅう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) confluence/union/linking up/merge" },
		{ "question": "合理", "answers": [ "ごうり" ], "comment": "(n) rational" },
		{ "question": "合致", "answers": [ "がっち" ], "comment": "(n) agreement/concurrence/conforming to" },
		{ "question": "合計", "answers": [ "ごうけい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) sum total/total amount" },
		{ "question": "合議", "answers": [ "ごうぎ" ], "comment": "(n) consultation/conference" },
		{ "question": "合間", "answers": [ "あいま" ], "comment": "(n) interval" },
		{ "question": "吊す", "answers": [ "つるす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to hang" },
		{ "question": "吊り革", "answers": [ "つりかわ" ], "comment": "(n) strap" },
		{ "question": "吊る", "answers": [ "つる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to hang" },
		{ "question": "同い年", "answers": [ "おないどし" ], "comment": "(n) of the same age" },
		{ "question": "同じ", "answers": [ "おなじ" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) same/identical/equal/uniform/equivalent/similar/common (origin)/changeless" },
		{ "question": "同一", "answers": [ "どういつ" ], "comment": "(adj-na,adj-no,n) identity/sameness/similarity/equality/fairness" },
		{ "question": "同僚", "answers": [ "どうりょう" ], "comment": "(n) coworker/colleague/associate" },
		{ "question": "同士", "answers": [ "どうし" ], "comment": "(n) fellow/companion/comrade" },
		{ "question": "同封", "answers": [ "どうふう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) enclosure (e.g. in a letter)" },
		{ "question": "同居", "answers": [ "どうきょ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) living together" },
		{ "question": "同志", "answers": [ "どうし" ], "comment": "(n) same mind/comrade/kindred soul" },
		{ "question": "同情", "answers": [ "どうじょう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) sympathy/compassion/sympathize/pity/feel for" },
		{ "question": "同意", "answers": [ "どうい" ], "comment": "(n) agreement/consent/same meaning/same opinion/approval" },
		{ "question": "同感", "answers": [ "どうかん" ], "comment": "(n) agreement/same opinion/same feeling/sympathy/concurrence" },
		{ "question": "同時", "answers": [ "どうじ" ], "comment": "(adj-no,n) simultaneous(ly)/concurrent/same time/synchronous" },
		{ "question": "同格", "answers": [ "どうかく" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) the same rank/equality/apposition" },
		{ "question": "同様", "answers": [ "どうよう" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) identical/equal to/same (kind)/like" },
		{ "question": "同盟", "answers": [ "どうめい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) alliance/union/league" },
		{ "question": "同等", "answers": [ "どうとう" ], "comment": "(adj-na,adj-no,n) equality/equal/same rights/same rank" },
		{ "question": "同級", "answers": [ "どうきゅう" ], "comment": "(n) the same grade/same class" },
		{ "question": "同調", "answers": [ "どうちょう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) sympathy/agree with/alignment/tuning" },
		{ "question": "名", "answers": [ "な" ], "comment": "(n) name/reputation" },
		{ "question": "名人", "answers": [ "めいじん" ], "comment": "(n) master/expert" },
		{ "question": "名付ける", "answers": [ "なづける" ], "comment": "(v1) to name (someone)" },
		{ "question": "名作", "answers": [ "めいさく" ], "comment": "(n) masterpiece" },
		{ "question": "名刺", "answers": [ "めいし" ], "comment": "(n) business card" },
		{ "question": "名前", "answers": [ "なまえ" ], "comment": "(n) name" },
		{ "question": "名字", "answers": [ "みょうじ" ], "comment": "(n) surname/family name" },
		{ "question": "名所", "answers": [ "めいしょ" ], "comment": "(n) famous place" },
		{ "question": "名札", "answers": [ "なふだ" ], "comment": "(n) name plate/name tag" },
		{ "question": "名残", "answers": [ "なごり" ], "comment": "(n) remains/traces/memory" },
		{ "question": "名物", "answers": [ "めいぶつ" ], "comment": "(n) famous product/special product/speciality" },
		{ "question": "名産", "answers": [ "めいさん" ], "comment": "(n) noted product" },
		{ "question": "名称", "answers": [ "めいしょう" ], "comment": "(n) name" },
		{ "question": "名簿", "answers": [ "めいぼ" ], "comment": "(n) register of names" },
		{ "question": "名詞", "answers": [ "めいし" ], "comment": "(n) noun" },
		{ "question": "名誉", "answers": [ "めいよ" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) honor/credit/prestige" },
		{ "question": "名高い", "answers": [ "なだかい" ], "comment": "(adj) famous/celebrated/well-known" },
		{ "question": "吐き気", "answers": [ "はきけ" ], "comment": "(n) nausea/sickness in the stomach" },
		{ "question": "吐く", "answers": [ "はく" ], "comment": "(v5k) (1) to breathe/(2) to tell (lies)/(3) to vomit/to disgorge" },
		{ "question": "向かう", "answers": [ "むかう" ], "comment": "(io) (v5u) to face/to go towards" },
		{ "question": "向かい", "answers": [ "むかい" ], "comment": "(adj-no,n) facing/opposite/across the street/other side" },
		{ "question": "向く", "answers": [ "むく" ], "comment": "(v5k) to face" },
		{ "question": "向ける", "answers": [ "むける" ], "comment": "(v1) to turn towards/to point" },
		{ "question": "向こう", "answers": [ "むこう" ], "comment": "(n) beyond/over there/opposite direction/the other party" },
		{ "question": "向上", "answers": [ "こうじょう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) elevation/rise/improvement/advancement/progress" },
		{ "question": "君", "answers": [ "きみ" ], "comment": "(n,suf) Mr (junior)/master/boy" },
		{ "question": "君主", "answers": [ "くんしゅ" ], "comment": "(n) ruler/monarch" },
		{ "question": "吟味", "answers": [ "ぎんみ" ], "comment": "(n) testing/scrutiny/careful investigation" },
		{ "question": "吠える", "answers": [ "ほえる" ], "comment": "(v1) to bark/to bay/to howl/to bellow/to roar/to cry" },
		{ "question": "否", "answers": [ "いや","いな","ひ" ], "comment": "(n) no/the noes" },
		{ "question": "否定", "answers": [ "ひてい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) negation/denial/repudiation" },
		{ "question": "否決", "answers": [ "ひけつ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) rejection/negation/voting down" },
		{ "question": "含む", "answers": [ "ふくむ" ], "comment": "(v5m) to hold in the mouth/to bear in mind/to understand/to cherish/to harbor/to contain/to comprise/to have/to hold/to include/to embrace/to be charged or loaded with/to be dripping with/to be full of/to be suffused with" },
		{ "question": "含める", "answers": [ "ふくめる" ], "comment": "(v1,vt) to include/to instruct/to make one understand/to put in one's mouth" },
		{ "question": "吸う", "answers": [ "すう" ], "comment": "(v5u) to smoke/to breathe in/to suck" },
		{ "question": "吸収", "answers": [ "きゅうしゅう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) absorption/suction/attraction" },
		{ "question": "吹く", "answers": [ "ふく" ], "comment": "(v5k) (1) to blow (wind, etc)/(2) to emit/to spout" },
		{ "question": "吹奏", "answers": [ "すいそう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) playing wind instruments" },
		{ "question": "吹雪", "answers": [ "ふぶき" ], "comment": "(n) snow storm" },
		{ "question": "呆然", "answers": [ "ぼうぜん" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) dumbfounded/overcome with surprise/in blank amazement" },
		{ "question": "告げる", "answers": [ "つげる" ], "comment": "(v1) to inform" },
		{ "question": "告白", "answers": [ "こくはく" ], "comment": "(n,vs) confession/acknowledgement" },
		{ "question": "呑気", "answers": [ "のんき" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) carefree/optimistic/careless/reckless/heedless" },
		{ "question": "呟く", "answers": [ "つぶやく" ], "comment": "(v5k) to mutter/to murmur" },
		{ "question": "周り", "answers": [ "まわり" ], "comment": "(n,n-suf) circumference/surroundings/circulation" },
		{ "question": "周囲", "answers": [ "しゅうい" ], "comment": "(n) surroundings/circumference/environs" },
		{ "question": "周期", "answers": [ "しゅうき" ], "comment": "(n) cycle/period" },
		{ "question": "周辺", "answers": [ "しゅうへん" ], "comment": "(n) circumference/outskirts/environs/(computer) peripheral" },
		{ "question": "味", "answers": [ "あじ" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) flavor/taste" },
		{ "question": "味わい", "answers": [ "あじわい" ], "comment": "(adj-no,n) flavour/meaning/significance" },
		{ "question": "味わう", "answers": [ "あじわう" ], "comment": "(v5u) to taste/to savor/to relish" },
		{ "question": "味噌", "answers": [ "みそ" ], "comment": "(n) (1) miso/bean paste/(2) key (main) point" },
		{ "question": "味方", "answers": [ "みかた" ], "comment": "(n) friend/ally/supporter" },
		{ "question": "味覚", "answers": [ "みかく" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) taste/palate/sense of taste" },
		{ "question": "呼び出す", "answers": [ "よびだす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to summon/to call (e.g. phone)" },
		{ "question": "呼び掛ける", "answers": [ "よびかける" ], "comment": "(v1) to call out to/to accost/to address (crowd)/to appeal" },
		{ "question": "呼び止める", "answers": [ "よびとめる" ], "comment": "(v1) to challenge/to call somebody to halt" },
		{ "question": "呼ぶ", "answers": [ "よぶ" ], "comment": "(v5b) to call out/to invite" },
		{ "question": "呼吸", "answers": [ "こきゅう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) breath/respiration" },
		{ "question": "命", "answers": [ "いのち" ], "comment": "(n) command/decree/life/destiny" },
		{ "question": "命じる", "answers": [ "めいじる" ], "comment": "(v1) to order/to command/to appoint" },
		{ "question": "命ずる", "answers": [ "めいずる" ], "comment": "(v5z) to command/to appoint" },
		{ "question": "命中", "answers": [ "めいちゅう" ], "comment": "(n) a hit" },
		{ "question": "命令", "answers": [ "めいれい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) order/command/decree/directive/(software) instruction" },
		{ "question": "和やか", "answers": [ "なごやか" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) mild/calm/gentle/quiet/harmonious" },
		{ "question": "和らげる", "answers": [ "やわらげる" ], "comment": "(v1) to soften/to moderate/to relieve" },
		{ "question": "和文", "answers": [ "わぶん" ], "comment": "(n) Japanese text/sentence in Japanese" },
		{ "question": "和服", "answers": [ "わふく" ], "comment": "(n) Japanese clothes" },
		{ "question": "和英", "answers": [ "わえい" ], "comment": "(n) Japanese-English" },
		{ "question": "咲く", "answers": [ "さく" ], "comment": "(v5k) to bloom" },
		{ "question": "咳", "answers": [ "せき" ], "comment": "(n) cough" },
		{ "question": "哀れ", "answers": [ "あわれ" ], "comment": "(adj-na,int,n) helpless/pathos/pity/sorrow/grief/misery/compassion" },
		{ "question": "品", "answers": [ "しな","ひん" ], "comment": "(n) thing/article/goods/dignity/article (goods)/counter for meal courses" },
		{ "question": "品物", "answers": [ "しなもの" ], "comment": "(n) goods/article/thing" },
		{ "question": "品種", "answers": [ "ひんしゅ" ], "comment": "(n) brand/kind/description" },
		{ "question": "品質", "answers": [ "ひんしつ" ], "comment": "(n) quality" },
		{ "question": "哲学", "answers": [ "てつがく" ], "comment": "(n) philosophy" },
		{ "question": "唇", "answers": [ "くちびる" ], "comment": "(n) lips" },
		{ "question": "唯", "answers": [ "ただ","たった" ], "comment": "(adj-pn,adv,conj) free of charge/mere/sole/only/usual/common" },
		{ "question": "唯一", "answers": [ "ゆいいつ" ], "comment": "(adv,n) only/sole/unique" },
		{ "question": "唱える", "answers": [ "となえる" ], "comment": "(v1) to recite/to chant/to call upon" },
		{ "question": "唾", "answers": [ "つば" ], "comment": "(n) saliva/spit/sputum" },
		{ "question": "商人", "answers": [ "しょうにん" ], "comment": "(n) trader/shopkeeper/merchant" },
		{ "question": "商品", "answers": [ "しょうひん" ], "comment": "(n) commodity/article of commerce/goods/stock/merchandise" },
		{ "question": "商売", "answers": [ "しょうばい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) trade/business/commerce/transaction/occupation" },
		{ "question": "商店", "answers": [ "しょうてん" ], "comment": "(n) shop/business firm" },
		{ "question": "商業", "answers": [ "しょうぎょう" ], "comment": "(n) commerce/trade/business" },
		{ "question": "商社", "answers": [ "しょうしゃ" ], "comment": "(n) trading company/firm" },
		{ "question": "問い", "answers": [ "とい" ], "comment": "(n) question/query" },
		{ "question": "問い合わせ", "answers": [ "といあわせ" ], "comment": "(n) enquiry/ENQ" },
		{ "question": "問い合わせる", "answers": [ "といあわせる" ], "comment": "(v1) to enquire/to seek information" },
		{ "question": "問う", "answers": [ "とう" ], "comment": "(v5u-s) to ask/to question/to charge (i.e. with a crime)/to accuse/without regard to (neg)" },
		{ "question": "問屋", "answers": [ "とんや" ], "comment": "(n) wholesale store" },
		{ "question": "問答", "answers": [ "もんどう" ], "comment": "(n) questions and answers/dialogue" },
		{ "question": "問題", "answers": [ "もんだい" ], "comment": "(n) problem/question" },
		{ "question": "善", "answers": [ "ぜん" ], "comment": "(n) good/goodness/right/virtue" },
		{ "question": "善し悪し", "answers": [ "よしあし" ], "comment": "(n) good or bad/merits or demerits/quality/suitability" },
		{ "question": "善良", "answers": [ "ぜんりょう" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) goodness/excellence/virtue" },
		{ "question": "喉", "answers": [ "のど" ], "comment": "(n) (uk) throat" },
		{ "question": "喜び", "answers": [ "よろこび" ], "comment": "(n) (a) joy/(a) delight/rapture/pleasure/gratification/rejoicing/congratulations/felicitations" },
		{ "question": "喜ぶ", "answers": [ "よろこぶ" ], "comment": "(v5b) to be delighted/to be glad" },
		{ "question": "喜劇", "answers": [ "きげき" ], "comment": "(n) comedy/funny show" },
		{ "question": "喧嘩", "answers": [ "けんか" ], "comment": "(n) quarrel/(drunken) brawl/failure" },
		{ "question": "喫茶店", "answers": [ "きっさてん" ], "comment": "(n) coffee lounge" },
		{ "question": "営む", "answers": [ "いとなむ" ], "comment": "(v5m) to carry on (e.g. in ceremony)/to run a business" },
		{ "question": "営業", "answers": [ "えいぎょう" ], "comment": "(n) business/trade/management" },
		{ "question": "嗅ぐ", "answers": [ "かぐ" ], "comment": "(v5g,vt) to sniff/to smell" },
		{ "question": "嗜好", "answers": [ "しこう" ], "comment": "(n) taste/liking/preference" },
		{ "question": "嘆く", "answers": [ "なげく" ], "comment": "(v5k) to sigh/to lament/to grieve" },
		{ "question": "嘗める", "answers": [ "なめる" ], "comment": "(v1) to lick/to taste/to experience/to make fun of/to make light of/to put down/to treat with contempt" },
		{ "question": "嘘", "answers": [ "うそ" ], "comment": "(n) lie/falsehood/incorrect fact/inappropriate" },
		{ "question": "嘘つき", "answers": [ "うそつき" ], "comment": "(adj-no,n) (uk) liar (sometimes said with not much seriousness)/fibber" },
		{ "question": "嘴", "answers": [ "くちばし" ], "comment": "(n) (uk) beak/bill" },
		{ "question": "噂", "answers": [ "うわさ" ], "comment": "(n) rumour/report/gossip/common talk" },
		{ "question": "噛み切る", "answers": [ "かみきる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to bite off/to gnaw through" },
		{ "question": "噛む", "answers": [ "かむ" ], "comment": "(v5m) to bite/to chew/to gnaw" },
		{ "question": "器", "answers": [ "うつわ" ], "comment": "(n) bowl/vessel/container" },
		{ "question": "器具", "answers": [ "きぐ" ], "comment": "(n) utensil" },
		{ "question": "器官", "answers": [ "きかん" ], "comment": "(n) organ (of body)/instrument" },
		{ "question": "器械", "answers": [ "きかい" ], "comment": "(n) instrument" },
		{ "question": "器用", "answers": [ "きよう" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) skillful/handy" },
		{ "question": "噴出", "answers": [ "ふんしゅつ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) spewing/gushing/spouting/eruption/effusion" },
		{ "question": "噴水", "answers": [ "ふんすい" ], "comment": "(n) water fountain" },
		{ "question": "噴火", "answers": [ "ふんか" ], "comment": "(n,vs) eruption" },
		{ "question": "囁く", "answers": [ "ささやく" ], "comment": "(v5k) to whisper/to murmur" },
		{ "question": "四", "answers": [ "し","よん" ], "comment": "(num) four" },
		{ "question": "四つ", "answers": [ "よっつ" ], "comment": "(n) four" },
		{ "question": "四つ角", "answers": [ "よつかど" ], "comment": "(n) four corners/crossroads" },
		{ "question": "四季", "answers": [ "しき" ], "comment": "(n) four seasons" },
		{ "question": "四捨五入", "answers": [ "ししゃごにゅう" ], "comment": "(n) rounding up (fractions)" },
		{ "question": "四日", "answers": [ "よっか" ], "comment": "(n) (1) 4th day of month/(2) four days" },
		{ "question": "四角", "answers": [ "しかく" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) square" },
		{ "question": "四角い", "answers": [ "しかくい" ], "comment": "(adj) square" },
		{ "question": "回", "answers": [ "かい" ], "comment": "(n) counter for occurrences" },
		{ "question": "回す", "answers": [ "まわす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to turn/to revolve" },
		{ "question": "回り", "answers": [ "まわり" ], "comment": "(n,n-suf) circumference/surroundings/circulation" },
		{ "question": "回り道", "answers": [ "まわりみち" ], "comment": "(n) detour" },
		{ "question": "回る", "answers": [ "まわる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to wander around" },
		{ "question": "回収", "answers": [ "かいしゅう" ], "comment": "(n) collection/recovery" },
		{ "question": "回復", "answers": [ "かいふく" ], "comment": "(n,vs) recovery (from illness)/improvement/rehabilitation/restoration" },
		{ "question": "回数", "answers": [ "かいすう" ], "comment": "(n) number of times/frequency" },
		{ "question": "回数券", "answers": [ "かいすうけん" ], "comment": "(n) book of tickets" },
		{ "question": "回答", "answers": [ "かいとう" ], "comment": "(n) reply/answer" },
		{ "question": "回覧", "answers": [ "かいらん" ], "comment": "(n) circulation" },
		{ "question": "回路", "answers": [ "かいろ" ], "comment": "(n) circuit (electric)" },
		{ "question": "回転", "answers": [ "かいてん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) rotation/revolution/turning" },
		{ "question": "回送", "answers": [ "かいそう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) forwarding" },
		{ "question": "因る", "answers": [ "よる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to come from" },
		{ "question": "団体", "answers": [ "だんたい" ], "comment": "(n) organization/association" },
		{ "question": "団地", "answers": [ "だんち" ], "comment": "(n) multi-unit apartments" },
		{ "question": "団扇", "answers": [ "うちわ" ], "comment": "(n) fan" },
		{ "question": "団結", "answers": [ "だんけつ" ], "comment": "(n) unity/union/combination" },
		{ "question": "困る", "answers": [ "こまる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to be worried/to be bothered" },
		{ "question": "困難", "answers": [ "こんなん" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) difficulty/distress" },
		{ "question": "囲む", "answers": [ "かこむ" ], "comment": "(v5m) to surround/to encircle" },
		{ "question": "図", "answers": [ "ず" ], "comment": "(n,n-suf) figure (e.g. Fig 1)/drawing/picture/illustration" },
		{ "question": "図る", "answers": [ "はかる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to plot/to attempt/to plan/to take in/to deceive/to devise/to design/to refer A to B" },
		{ "question": "図形", "answers": [ "ずけい" ], "comment": "(n) figure" },
		{ "question": "図書", "answers": [ "としょ" ], "comment": "(n) books" },
		{ "question": "図書館", "answers": [ "としょかん" ], "comment": "(n) library" },
		{ "question": "図表", "answers": [ "ずひょう" ], "comment": "(n) chart/diagram/graph" },
		{ "question": "図鑑", "answers": [ "ずかん" ], "comment": "(n) picture book" },
		{ "question": "固い", "answers": [ "かたい" ], "comment": "(adj) stubborn/firm (not viscous or easily moved)/certain/solemn" },
		{ "question": "固まる", "answers": [ "かたまる" ], "comment": "(v5r,vi) to harden/to solidify/to become firm/to become certain" },
		{ "question": "固める", "answers": [ "かためる" ], "comment": "(v1,vt) to harden/to freeze/to fortify" },
		{ "question": "固定", "answers": [ "こてい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) fixation/fixing (e.g. salary, capital)" },
		{ "question": "固有", "answers": [ "こゆう" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n,pref) characteristic/tradition/peculiar/inherent/eigen-" },
		{ "question": "国", "answers": [ "くに" ], "comment": "(n) country" },
		{ "question": "国交", "answers": [ "こっこう" ], "comment": "(n) diplomatic relations" },
		{ "question": "国会", "answers": [ "こっかい" ], "comment": "(n) National Diet/parliament/congress" },
		{ "question": "国境", "answers": [ "こっきょう" ], "comment": "(n) national or state border" },
		{ "question": "国定", "answers": [ "こくてい" ], "comment": "(n) state-sponsored/national" },
		{ "question": "国家", "answers": [ "こっか" ], "comment": "(n) state/country/nation" },
		{ "question": "国有", "answers": [ "こくゆう" ], "comment": "(n) national ownership" },
		{ "question": "国民", "answers": [ "こくみん" ], "comment": "(n) national/people/citizen" },
		{ "question": "国王", "answers": [ "こくおう" ], "comment": "(n) king" },
		{ "question": "国産", "answers": [ "こくさん" ], "comment": "(n) domestic products" },
		{ "question": "国立", "answers": [ "こくりつ" ], "comment": "(n) national" },
		{ "question": "国籍", "answers": [ "こくせき" ], "comment": "(n) nationality" },
		{ "question": "国語", "answers": [ "こくご" ], "comment": "(n) national language" },
		{ "question": "国連", "answers": [ "こくれん" ], "comment": "(n) U.N./United Nations" },
		{ "question": "国防", "answers": [ "こくぼう" ], "comment": "(n) national defence" },
		{ "question": "国際", "answers": [ "こくさい" ], "comment": "(n) international" },
		{ "question": "園芸", "answers": [ "えんげい" ], "comment": "(n) horticulture/gardening" },
		{ "question": "土", "answers": [ "つち" ], "comment": "(n) earth/soil" },
		{ "question": "土俵", "answers": [ "どひょう" ], "comment": "(n) arena" },
		{ "question": "土台", "answers": [ "どだい" ], "comment": "(adv,n) foundation/base/basis" },
		{ "question": "土地", "answers": [ "とち" ], "comment": "(n) plot of land/lot/soil" },
		{ "question": "土手", "answers": [ "どて" ], "comment": "(n) embankment/bank" },
		{ "question": "土曜", "answers": [ "どよう" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n) Saturday" },
		{ "question": "土曜日", "answers": [ "どようび" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n) Saturday" },
		{ "question": "土木", "answers": [ "どぼく" ], "comment": "(n) public works" },
		{ "question": "土産", "answers": [ "みやげ" ], "comment": "(n) present/souvenir" },
		{ "question": "圧倒", "answers": [ "あっとう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) overwhelm/overpower/overwhelming" },
		{ "question": "圧力", "answers": [ "あつりょく" ], "comment": "(n,vs) stress/pressure" },
		{ "question": "圧縮", "answers": [ "あっしゅく" ], "comment": "(n,vs) compression/condensation/pressure" },
		{ "question": "圧迫", "answers": [ "あっぱく" ], "comment": "(n,vs) pressure/coercion/oppression" },
		{ "question": "在る", "answers": [ "ある" ], "comment": "(v5r-i) to live/to be" },
		{ "question": "在学", "answers": [ "ざいがく" ], "comment": "(n) (enrolled) in school" },
		{ "question": "在庫", "answers": [ "ざいこ" ], "comment": "(n) stockpile/stock" },
		{ "question": "地", "answers": [ "ち" ], "comment": "(n,n-suf) earth" },
		{ "question": "地下", "answers": [ "ちか" ], "comment": "(n) basement/underground" },
		{ "question": "地下水", "answers": [ "ちかすい" ], "comment": "(n) underground water" },
		{ "question": "地下鉄", "answers": [ "ちかてつ" ], "comment": "(n) underground train/subway" },
		{ "question": "地主", "answers": [ "じぬし" ], "comment": "(n) landlord" },
		{ "question": "地位", "answers": [ "ちい" ], "comment": "(n) (social) position/status" },
		{ "question": "地元", "answers": [ "じもと" ], "comment": "(n) local" },
		{ "question": "地区", "answers": [ "ちく" ], "comment": "(n) district/section/sector" },
		{ "question": "地名", "answers": [ "ちめい" ], "comment": "(n) place name" },
		{ "question": "地味", "answers": [ "じみ" ], "comment": "(n) soil fertility/product of the soil" },
		{ "question": "地図", "answers": [ "ちず" ], "comment": "(n) map" },
		{ "question": "地域", "answers": [ "ちいき" ], "comment": "(n) area/region" },
		{ "question": "地帯", "answers": [ "ちたい" ], "comment": "(n) area/zone" },
		{ "question": "地平線", "answers": [ "ちへいせん" ], "comment": "(n) horizon" },
		{ "question": "地形", "answers": [ "ちけい" ], "comment": "(n) terrain/geographical features/topography" },
		{ "question": "地方", "answers": [ "ちほう" ], "comment": "(n) area/locality/district/region/the coast" },
		{ "question": "地点", "answers": [ "ちてん" ], "comment": "(n) site/point on a map" },
		{ "question": "地獄", "answers": [ "じごく" ], "comment": "(n) hell" },
		{ "question": "地球", "answers": [ "ちきゅう" ], "comment": "(adj-no,n) the earth" },
		{ "question": "地理", "answers": [ "ちり" ], "comment": "(n) geography" },
		{ "question": "地盤", "answers": [ "じばん" ], "comment": "(n) (the) ground" },
		{ "question": "地質", "answers": [ "ちしつ" ], "comment": "(n) geological features" },
		{ "question": "地震", "answers": [ "じしん" ], "comment": "(n) earthquake" },
		{ "question": "地面", "answers": [ "じめん" ], "comment": "(n) ground/earth's surface" },
		{ "question": "坂", "answers": [ "さか" ], "comment": "(n) slope/hill" },
		{ "question": "均衡", "answers": [ "きんこう" ], "comment": "(n) equilibrium/balance" },
		{ "question": "坊さん", "answers": [ "ぼうさん" ], "comment": "(n) Buddhist priest/monk" },
		{ "question": "坊っちゃん", "answers": [ "ぼっちゃん" ], "comment": "(n) son (of others)" },
		{ "question": "坊や", "answers": [ "ぼうや" ], "comment": "(n) boy" },
		{ "question": "垂れる", "answers": [ "たれる" ], "comment": "(v1,vi) (1) to hang/to droop/to dangle/to sag/to lower/to pull down/(2) to leave behind (at death)/to give/to confer/(3) to drip/to ooze/to trickle/to drop" },
		{ "question": "垂直", "answers": [ "すいちょく" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) vertical/perpendicular" },
		{ "question": "型", "answers": [ "かた" ], "comment": "(n) mold/model/style/shape/data-type" },
		{ "question": "垢", "answers": [ "あか" ], "comment": "(n) dirt/filth" },
		{ "question": "垣根", "answers": [ "かきね" ], "comment": "(n) hedge" },
		{ "question": "埃", "answers": [ "ほこり" ], "comment": "(n) dust" },
		{ "question": "埋まる", "answers": [ "うまる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to be buried/to be surrounded/to overflow/to be filled" },
		{ "question": "埋める", "answers": [ "うずめる","うめる" ], "comment": "(v1) to bury/to fill up/to fill (a seat, a vacant position)" },
		{ "question": "埋め込む", "answers": [ "うめこむ" ], "comment": "(v5m) to bury" },
		{ "question": "埋蔵", "answers": [ "まいぞう" ], "comment": "(n) buried property/treasure trove" },
		{ "question": "城", "answers": [ "しろ" ], "comment": "(n) castle" },
		{ "question": "城下", "answers": [ "じょうか" ], "comment": "(n) land near the castle" },
		{ "question": "執着", "answers": [ "しゅうじゃく","しゅうちゃく" ], "comment": "(n) attachment/adhesion/tenacity" },
		{ "question": "執筆", "answers": [ "しっぴつ" ], "comment": "(n) writing" },
		{ "question": "基", "answers": [ "もと" ], "comment": "(n) basis" },
		{ "question": "基づく", "answers": [ "もとづく" ], "comment": "(v5k) to be grounded on/to be based on/to be due to/to originate from" },
		{ "question": "基地", "answers": [ "きち" ], "comment": "(n) base" },
		{ "question": "基本", "answers": [ "きほん" ], "comment": "(n) foundation/basis/standard" },
		{ "question": "基準", "answers": [ "きじゅん" ], "comment": "(n) standard/basis/criteria/norm" },
		{ "question": "基盤", "answers": [ "きばん" ], "comment": "(n) foundation/basis" },
		{ "question": "基礎", "answers": [ "きそ" ], "comment": "(n) foundation/basis" },
		{ "question": "基金", "answers": [ "ききん" ], "comment": "(n) fund/foundation" },
		{ "question": "堀", "answers": [ "ほり" ], "comment": "(n) moat/canal" },
		{ "question": "堂々", "answers": [ "どうどう" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) magnificent/grand/impressive" },
		{ "question": "堅い", "answers": [ "かたい" ], "comment": "(adj) hard (esp. wood)/steadfast/honorable/stuffy writing" },
		{ "question": "堤防", "answers": [ "ていぼう" ], "comment": "(n) bank/weir" },
		{ "question": "堪える", "answers": [ "たえる" ], "comment": "(v1) to bear/to stand/to endure/to put up with/to support/to withstand/to resist/to brave/to be fit for/to be equal to" },
		{ "question": "報じる", "answers": [ "ほうじる" ], "comment": "(v1) to inform/to report" },
		{ "question": "報ずる", "answers": [ "ほうずる" ], "comment": "(v5z) to inform/to report" },
		{ "question": "報告", "answers": [ "ほうこく" ], "comment": "(n,vs) report/information" },
		{ "question": "報道", "answers": [ "ほうどう" ], "comment": "(n) information/report" },
		{ "question": "報酬", "answers": [ "ほうしゅう" ], "comment": "(n) remuneration/recompense/reward/toll" },
		{ "question": "場", "answers": [ "ば" ], "comment": "(n) place/field (physics)" },
		{ "question": "場合", "answers": [ "ばあい" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n) case/situation" },
		{ "question": "場所", "answers": [ "ばしょ" ], "comment": "(n) place/location" },
		{ "question": "場面", "answers": [ "ばめん" ], "comment": "(n) scene/setting (e.g. of novel)" },
		{ "question": "塀", "answers": [ "へい" ], "comment": "(n) wall/fence" },
		{ "question": "塊", "answers": [ "かたまり" ], "comment": "(n) lump/mass/clod/cluster" },
		{ "question": "塔", "answers": [ "とう" ], "comment": "(n,n-suf) tower/pagoda" },
		{ "question": "塗る", "answers": [ "ぬる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to paint/to plaster/to lacquer/to varnish" },
		{ "question": "塞がる", "answers": [ "ふさがる" ], "comment": "(v5r,vi) to be plugged up/to be shut up" },
		{ "question": "塞ぐ", "answers": [ "ふさぐ" ], "comment": "(v5g,vt) to stop up/to close up/to block (up)/to occupy/to fill up/to take up/to stand in another's way/to plug up/to shut up" },
		{ "question": "塩", "answers": [ "しお" ], "comment": "(n) salt" },
		{ "question": "塩辛い", "answers": [ "しおからい" ], "comment": "(adj) salty (taste)" },
		{ "question": "塵", "answers": [ "ごみ","ちり" ], "comment": "(n) dust/dirt" },
		{ "question": "塵取り", "answers": [ "ちりとり" ], "comment": "(n) dustpan" },
		{ "question": "塵紙", "answers": [ "ちりがみ" ], "comment": "(n) tissue paper/toilet paper" },
		{ "question": "塵芥", "answers": [ "じんかい", "ちりあくた", "ごみあくた" ], "comment": "(n) trash/rubbish" },
		{ "question": "塾", "answers": [ "じゅく" ], "comment": "(n) coaching school/lessons" },
		{ "question": "境", "answers": [ "さかい" ], "comment": "(n) border/boundary/mental state" },
		{ "question": "境界", "answers": [ "きょうかい" ], "comment": "(n) boundary" },
		{ "question": "境遇", "answers": [ "きょうぐう" ], "comment": "(n) environment/circumstances" },
		{ "question": "墓", "answers": [ "はか" ], "comment": "(n) grave/tomb" },
		{ "question": "墓地", "answers": [ "ぼち" ], "comment": "(n) cemetery/graveyard" },
		{ "question": "増える", "answers": [ "ふえる" ], "comment": "(v1,vi) to increase/to multiply" },
		{ "question": "増す", "answers": [ "ます" ], "comment": "(v5s,vi) to increase/to grow" },
		{ "question": "増やす", "answers": [ "ふやす" ], "comment": "(v5s,vt) to increase/to add to/to augment" },
		{ "question": "増加", "answers": [ "ぞうか" ], "comment": "(n,vs) increase/addition" },
		{ "question": "増大", "answers": [ "ぞうだい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) enlargement" },
		{ "question": "増強", "answers": [ "ぞうきょう" ], "comment": "(n) augment/reinforce/increase" },
		{ "question": "増減", "answers": [ "ぞうげん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) increase and decrease/fluctuation" },
		{ "question": "増進", "answers": [ "ぞうしん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) promoting/increase/advance" },
		{ "question": "墜落", "answers": [ "ついらく" ], "comment": "(n,vs) falling/crashing" },
		{ "question": "墨", "answers": [ "すみ" ], "comment": "(n) ink" },
		{ "question": "壁", "answers": [ "かべ" ], "comment": "(n) wall" },
		{ "question": "壊す", "answers": [ "こわす" ], "comment": "(v5s,vt) to break/to break down" },
		{ "question": "壊れる", "answers": [ "こわれる" ], "comment": "(v1,vi) to be broken/to break" },
		{ "question": "壮大", "answers": [ "そうだい" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) magnificent/grand/majestic/splendid" },
		{ "question": "声", "answers": [ "こえ" ], "comment": "(n) voice" },
		{ "question": "声明", "answers": [ "せいめい" ], "comment": "(n) declaration/statement/proclamation" },
		{ "question": "売り出し", "answers": [ "うりだし" ], "comment": "(n) (bargain) sale" },
		{ "question": "売り出す", "answers": [ "うりだす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to put on sale/to market/to become popular" },
		{ "question": "売り切れ", "answers": [ "うりきれ" ], "comment": "(n) sold-out" },
		{ "question": "売り切れる", "answers": [ "うりきれる" ], "comment": "(v1) to be sold out" },
		{ "question": "売り場", "answers": [ "うりば" ], "comment": "(adj-no,n) place where things are sold/salesfloor/counter (in shop)" },
		{ "question": "売る", "answers": [ "うる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to sell" },
		{ "question": "売れる", "answers": [ "うれる" ], "comment": "(v1) to be sold" },
		{ "question": "売上", "answers": [ "うりあげ" ], "comment": "(n) amount sold/proceeds" },
		{ "question": "売店", "answers": [ "ばいてん" ], "comment": "(n) shop/stand" },
		{ "question": "売行き", "answers": [ "うれゆき" ], "comment": "(n) sales" },
		{ "question": "売買", "answers": [ "ばいばい" ], "comment": "(n) trade/buying and selling" },
		{ "question": "壷", "answers": [ "つぼ" ], "comment": "(n) tsubo jar/pot/vase" },
		{ "question": "変", "answers": [ "へん" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) change/incident/disturbance/strange/flat (music)/odd/peculiar/suspicious-looking/queer/eccentric/funny" },
		{ "question": "変える", "answers": [ "かえる" ], "comment": "(v1,vt) to change/to alter/to vary/to convert/to revise/to amend" },
		{ "question": "変わる", "answers": [ "かわる" ], "comment": "(v5r,vi) to change/to be transformed/to vary/to be revised/to be different/to move location" },
		{ "question": "変動", "answers": [ "へんどう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) change/fluctuation" },
		{ "question": "変化", "answers": [ "へんか" ], "comment": "(n) goblin/ghost/apparition/bugbear" },
		{ "question": "変更", "answers": [ "へんこう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) change/modification/alteration" },
		{ "question": "変遷", "answers": [ "へんせん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) change/transition/vicissitudes" },
		{ "question": "変革", "answers": [ "へんかく" ], "comment": "(n) change/reform/revolution/upheaval/(the) Reformation" },
		{ "question": "夏", "answers": [ "なつ" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n-t) summer" },
		{ "question": "夏休み", "answers": [ "なつやすみ" ], "comment": "(n) summer vacation/summer holiday" },
		{ "question": "夕べ", "answers": [ "ゆうべ" ], "comment": "(n) evening" },
		{ "question": "夕刊", "answers": [ "ゆうかん" ], "comment": "(n) evening paper" },
		{ "question": "夕方", "answers": [ "ゆうがた" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n-t) evening" },
		{ "question": "夕日", "answers": [ "ゆうひ" ], "comment": "(n) (in) the evening sun/setting sun" },
		{ "question": "夕暮れ", "answers": [ "ゆうぐれ" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n) evening/(evening) twilight" },
		{ "question": "夕焼け", "answers": [ "ゆうやけ" ], "comment": "(n) sunset" },
		{ "question": "夕立", "answers": [ "ゆうだち" ], "comment": "(n) (sudden) evening shower (rain)" },
		{ "question": "夕飯", "answers": [ "ゆうはん" ], "comment": "(n) evening meal" },
		{ "question": "外", "answers": [ "そと","ほか" ], "comment": "(n) other place/the rest" },
		{ "question": "外す", "answers": [ "はずす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to unfasten/to remove" },
		{ "question": "外れる", "answers": [ "はずれる" ], "comment": "(v1,vi) to be disconnected/to get out of place/to be off/to be out (e.g. of gear)" },
		{ "question": "外交", "answers": [ "がいこう" ], "comment": "(n) diplomacy" },
		{ "question": "外出", "answers": [ "がいしゅつ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) outing/going out" },
		{ "question": "外国", "answers": [ "がいこく" ], "comment": "(n) foreign country" },
		{ "question": "外国人", "answers": [ "がいこくじん" ], "comment": "(n) foreigner" },
		{ "question": "外方", "answers": [ "そっぽ" ], "comment": "(n) look (or turn) the other way" },
		{ "question": "外来", "answers": [ "がいらい" ], "comment": "(n) (abbr) imported/outpatient clinic" },
		{ "question": "外相", "answers": [ "がいしょう" ], "comment": "(n) Foreign Minister" },
		{ "question": "外科", "answers": [ "げか" ], "comment": "(n) surgical department" },
		{ "question": "外観", "answers": [ "がいかん" ], "comment": "(n) appearance/exterior/facade" },
		{ "question": "外貨", "answers": [ "がいか" ], "comment": "(n) imported goods/foreign money" },
		{ "question": "外部", "answers": [ "がいぶ" ], "comment": "(n) the outside/external" },
		{ "question": "多い", "answers": [ "おおい" ], "comment": "(adj) many/numerous" },
		{ "question": "多分", "answers": [ "たぶん" ], "comment": "(adv,n) perhaps/probably" },
		{ "question": "多少", "answers": [ "たしょう" ], "comment": "(adj-no,adv,n) more or less/somewhat/a little/some" },
		{ "question": "多忙", "answers": [ "たぼう" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) busy/pressure of work" },
		{ "question": "多数決", "answers": [ "たすうけつ" ], "comment": "(n) majority rule" },
		{ "question": "多様", "answers": [ "たよう" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) diversity/variety" },
		{ "question": "夜", "answers": [ "よ","よる" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n-t) evening/night" },
		{ "question": "夜中", "answers": [ "よなか" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n-t) midnight/dead of night" },
		{ "question": "夜具", "answers": [ "やぐ" ], "comment": "(n) bedding" },
		{ "question": "夜明け", "answers": [ "よあけ" ], "comment": "(n) dawn/daybreak" },
		{ "question": "夜更け", "answers": [ "よふけ" ], "comment": "(n) late at night" },
		{ "question": "夜更し", "answers": [ "よふかし" ], "comment": "(n) staying up late/keeping late hours/sitting up late at night/nighthawk" },
		{ "question": "夜行", "answers": [ "やこう" ], "comment": "(n) walking around at night/night train/night travel" },
		{ "question": "夜間", "answers": [ "やかん" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n-t) at night/nighttime" },
		{ "question": "夢", "answers": [ "ゆめ" ], "comment": "(n) dream" },
		{ "question": "夢中", "answers": [ "むちゅう" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) daze/(in a) trance/ecstasy/delirium/engrossment" },
		{ "question": "大いに", "answers": [ "おおいに" ], "comment": "(adv) very/much/greatly" },
		{ "question": "大きい", "answers": [ "おおきい" ], "comment": "(adj) big/large/great" },
		{ "question": "大した", "answers": [ "たいした" ], "comment": "(adj-pn) considerable/great/important/significant/a big deal" },
		{ "question": "大して", "answers": [ "たいして" ], "comment": "(adv) (not so) much/(not) very" },
		{ "question": "大丈夫", "answers": [ "だいじょうぶ" ], "comment": "(adj-na,adv,n) safe/all right/O.K." },
		{ "question": "大事", "answers": [ "だいじ" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) important/valuable/serious matter" },
		{ "question": "大人", "answers": [ "おとな" ], "comment": "(n) adult" },
		{ "question": "大会", "answers": [ "たいかい" ], "comment": "(n) convention/tournament/mass meeting/rally" },
		{ "question": "大体", "answers": [ "だいたい" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n-t) general/substantially/outline/main point" },
		{ "question": "大使", "answers": [ "たいし" ], "comment": "(n) ambassador" },
		{ "question": "大使館", "answers": [ "たいしかん" ], "comment": "(n) embassy" },
		{ "question": "大便", "answers": [ "だいべん" ], "comment": "(n) feces/excrement/shit" },
		{ "question": "大凡", "answers": [ "おおよそ" ], "comment": "(adv,n) (uk) about/roughly/as a rule/approximately" },
		{ "question": "大分", "answers": [ "だいぶ","だいぶん" ], "comment": "(adv) considerably/greatly/a lot" },
		{ "question": "大切", "answers": [ "たいせつ" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) important" },
		{ "question": "大勢", "answers": [ "おおぜい" ], "comment": "(n) great number of people" },
		{ "question": "大半", "answers": [ "たいはん" ], "comment": "(n) majority/mostly/generally" },
		{ "question": "大好き", "answers": [ "だいすき" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) very likeable/like very much" },
		{ "question": "大学", "answers": [ "だいがく" ], "comment": "(n) university" },
		{ "question": "大学生", "answers": [ "だいがくせい" ], "comment": "(n) college student" },
		{ "question": "大学院", "answers": [ "だいがくいん" ], "comment": "(n) graduate school" },
		{ "question": "大家", "answers": [ "おおや","たいか" ], "comment": "(n) rich family/distinguished family" },
		{ "question": "大小", "answers": [ "だいしょう" ], "comment": "(n) size" },
		{ "question": "大層", "answers": [ "たいそう" ], "comment": "(adj-na,adv,n) very much/exaggerated/very fine" },
		{ "question": "大工", "answers": [ "だいく" ], "comment": "(n) carpenter" },
		{ "question": "大幅", "answers": [ "おおはば" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) full width/large scale/drastic" },
		{ "question": "大戦", "answers": [ "たいせん" ], "comment": "(n) great war/great battle" },
		{ "question": "大抵", "answers": [ "たいてい" ], "comment": "(adj-na,adv,n) usually/generally" },
		{ "question": "大方", "answers": [ "おおかた" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n) perhaps/almost all/majority" },
		{ "question": "大木", "answers": [ "たいぼく" ], "comment": "(n) large tree" },
		{ "question": "大柄", "answers": [ "おおがら" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) large build/large pattern" },
		{ "question": "大概", "answers": [ "たいがい" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n-t) in general/mainly" },
		{ "question": "大気", "answers": [ "たいき" ], "comment": "(n) atmosphere" },
		{ "question": "大水", "answers": [ "おおみず" ], "comment": "(n) flood" },
		{ "question": "大空", "answers": [ "おおぞら" ], "comment": "(n) heaven/firmament/the sky" },
		{ "question": "大筋", "answers": [ "おおすじ" ], "comment": "(n) outline/summary" },
		{ "question": "大統領", "answers": [ "だいとうりょう" ], "comment": "(n) president/chief executive" },
		{ "question": "大胆", "answers": [ "だいたん" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) bold/daring/audacious" },
		{ "question": "大臣", "answers": [ "だいじん" ], "comment": "(n) cabinet minister" },
		{ "question": "大衆", "answers": [ "たいしゅう" ], "comment": "(n) general public" },
		{ "question": "大通り", "answers": [ "おおどおり" ], "comment": "(n) main street" },
		{ "question": "大部", "answers": [ "たいぶ" ], "comment": "(adv,n) most (e.g. most part)/greater/fairly/a good deal/much" },
		{ "question": "大部分", "answers": [ "だいぶぶん" ], "comment": "(n-t) most part/greater part/majority" },
		{ "question": "大金", "answers": [ "たいきん" ], "comment": "(n) great cost" },
		{ "question": "大陸", "answers": [ "たいりく" ], "comment": "(n) continent" },
		{ "question": "天", "answers": [ "てん" ], "comment": "(n) heaven/sky" },
		{ "question": "天下", "answers": [ "てんか" ], "comment": "(n) the world/whole country/descent from heaven/having one's own way/the public/the ruling power" },
		{ "question": "天体", "answers": [ "てんたい" ], "comment": "(n) heavenly body" },
		{ "question": "天候", "answers": [ "てんこう" ], "comment": "(n) weather" },
		{ "question": "天国", "answers": [ "てんごく" ], "comment": "(n) paradise/heaven/Kingdom of Heaven" },
		{ "question": "天地", "answers": [ "てんち" ], "comment": "(n) heaven and earth/the universe/nature/top and bottom/realm/sphere/world" },
		{ "question": "天才", "answers": [ "てんさい" ], "comment": "(n) genius/prodigy/natural gift" },
		{ "question": "天気", "answers": [ "てんき" ], "comment": "(n) weather/the elements/fine weather" },
		{ "question": "天気予報", "answers": [ "てんきよほう" ], "comment": "weather forecast/weather report" },
		{ "question": "天災", "answers": [ "てんさい" ], "comment": "(n) natural calamity/disaster" },
		{ "question": "天然", "answers": [ "てんねん" ], "comment": "(n) nature/spontaneity" },
		{ "question": "天皇", "answers": [ "てんのう" ], "comment": "(n) Emperor of Japan" },
		{ "question": "太い", "answers": [ "ふとい" ], "comment": "(adj) fat/thick" },
		{ "question": "太る", "answers": [ "ふとる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to grow fat (stout, plump)/to become fat" },
		{ "question": "太陽", "answers": [ "たいよう" ], "comment": "(n) sun/solar" },
		{ "question": "太鼓", "answers": [ "たいこ" ], "comment": "(n) drum/tambourine" },
		{ "question": "夫", "answers": [ "おっと" ], "comment": "(n) (hum) (my) husband" },
		{ "question": "夫人", "answers": [ "ふじん" ], "comment": "(n) wife/Mrs/madam" },
		{ "question": "夫妻", "answers": [ "ふさい" ], "comment": "(n) man and wife/married couple" },
		{ "question": "夫婦", "answers": [ "ふうふ" ], "comment": "(n) married couple/spouses/husband and wife/couple/pair" },
		{ "question": "失う", "answers": [ "うしなう" ], "comment": "(v5u) to lose/to part with" },
		{ "question": "失恋", "answers": [ "しつれん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) disappointed love/broken heart/unrequited love/be lovelorn" },
		{ "question": "失敗", "answers": [ "しっぱい" ], "comment": "(adj-no,n,vs) failure/mistake/blunder" },
		{ "question": "失望", "answers": [ "しつぼう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) disappointment/despair" },
		{ "question": "失格", "answers": [ "しっかく" ], "comment": "(n) disqualification/elimination/incapacity (legal)" },
		{ "question": "失業", "answers": [ "しつぎょう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) unemployment" },
		{ "question": "失礼", "answers": [ "しつれい" ], "comment": "(adj-na,int,n,vs,exp) (1) discourtesy/impoliteness/(2) Excuse me/Goodbye" },
		{ "question": "失脚", "answers": [ "しっきゃく" ], "comment": "(n,vs) losing one's standing/being overthrown/falling" },
		{ "question": "失調", "answers": [ "しっちょう" ], "comment": "(n) lack of harmony" },
		{ "question": "奇妙", "answers": [ "きみょう" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) strange/queer/curious" },
		{ "question": "奉る", "answers": [ "たてまつる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to offer/to present/to revere/to do respectfully" },
		{ "question": "奉仕", "answers": [ "ほうし" ], "comment": "(n) attendance/service" },
		{ "question": "契機", "answers": [ "けいき" ], "comment": "(n) opportunity/chance" },
		{ "question": "契約", "answers": [ "けいやく" ], "comment": "(n) contract/compact/agreement" },
		{ "question": "奥", "answers": [ "おく" ], "comment": "(n) interior/inner part" },
		{ "question": "奥さん", "answers": [ "おくさん" ], "comment": "(n) (hon) wife/your wife/his wife/married lady/madam" },
		{ "question": "奨励", "answers": [ "しょうれい" ], "comment": "(n) encouragement/promotion/message/address" },
		{ "question": "奨学金", "answers": [ "しょうがくきん" ], "comment": "(n) scholarship" },
		{ "question": "奪う", "answers": [ "うばう" ], "comment": "(v5u) to snatch away" },
		{ "question": "奮闘", "answers": [ "ふんとう" ], "comment": "(n) hard struggle/strenuous effort" },
		{ "question": "女", "answers": [ "おんな" ], "comment": "(n) woman/girl/daughter" },
		{ "question": "女の人", "answers": [ "おんなのひと" ], "comment": "woman" },
		{ "question": "女の子", "answers": [ "おんなのこ" ], "comment": "(n) girl" },
		{ "question": "女優", "answers": [ "じょゆう" ], "comment": "(n) actress" },
		{ "question": "女史", "answers": [ "じょし" ], "comment": "(n) Ms." },
		{ "question": "女子", "answers": [ "じょし" ], "comment": "(n) woman/girl" },
		{ "question": "女性", "answers": [ "じょせい" ], "comment": "(n) woman" },
		{ "question": "女房", "answers": [ "にょうぼう" ], "comment": "(n) wife" },
		{ "question": "女王", "answers": [ "じょおう" ], "comment": "(n) queen" },
		{ "question": "奴", "answers": [ "やつ" ], "comment": "(n) (vulg) fellow/guy/chap" },
		{ "question": "好き", "answers": [ "すき" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) liking/fondness/love" },
		{ "question": "好き好き", "answers": [ "すきずき" ], "comment": "(n) matter of taste" },
		{ "question": "好き嫌い", "answers": [ "すききらい" ], "comment": "(n) likes and dislikes/taste" },
		{ "question": "好ましい", "answers": [ "このましい" ], "comment": "(adj) nice/likeable/desirable" },
		{ "question": "好み", "answers": [ "このみ" ], "comment": "(n) liking/taste/choice" },
		{ "question": "好む", "answers": [ "このむ" ], "comment": "(v5m) to like/to prefer" },
		{ "question": "好意", "answers": [ "こうい" ], "comment": "(n) good will/favor/courtesy" },
		{ "question": "好況", "answers": [ "こうきょう" ], "comment": "(n) prosperous conditions/healthy economy" },
		{ "question": "好評", "answers": [ "こうひょう" ], "comment": "(n) popularity/favorable reputation" },
		{ "question": "好調", "answers": [ "こうちょう" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) favourable/promising/satisfactory/in good shape" },
		{ "question": "妊娠", "answers": [ "にんしん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) conception/pregnancy" },
		{ "question": "妙", "answers": [ "みょう" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) strange/unusual" },
		{ "question": "妥協", "answers": [ "だきょう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) compromise/giving in" },
		{ "question": "妥当", "answers": [ "だとう" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) valid/proper/right/appropriate" },
		{ "question": "妥結", "answers": [ "だけつ" ], "comment": "(n) agreement" },
		{ "question": "妨げる", "answers": [ "さまたげる" ], "comment": "(v1) to disturb/to prevent" },
		{ "question": "妨害", "answers": [ "ぼうがい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) disturbance/obstruction/hindrance/jamming/interference" },
		{ "question": "妬む", "answers": [ "ねたむ" ], "comment": "(v5m) to be jealous/to be envious" },
		{ "question": "妹", "answers": [ "いもうと" ], "comment": "(n) (hum) younger sister" },
		{ "question": "妻", "answers": [ "つま" ], "comment": "(n) (hum) wife" },
		{ "question": "姉", "answers": [ "あね" ], "comment": "(n) (hum) older sister" },
		{ "question": "姉妹", "answers": [ "しまい" ], "comment": "(n) sisters" },
		{ "question": "始まり", "answers": [ "はじまり" ], "comment": "(n) origin/beginning" },
		{ "question": "始まる", "answers": [ "はじまる" ], "comment": "(v5r,vi) to begin" },
		{ "question": "始めに", "answers": [ "はじめに" ], "comment": "to begin with/first of all" },
		{ "question": "始める", "answers": [ "はじめる" ], "comment": "(v1,vt) to start/to begin" },
		{ "question": "始末", "answers": [ "しまつ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) (1) management/(2) dealing/settlement/(3) cleaning up afterwards" },
		{ "question": "始発", "answers": [ "しはつ" ], "comment": "(n) first train" },
		{ "question": "始終", "answers": [ "しじゅう" ], "comment": "(adv,n) continuously/from beginning to end" },
		{ "question": "姓", "answers": [ "せい" ], "comment": "(n) surname/family name" },
		{ "question": "姓名", "answers": [ "せいめい" ], "comment": "(n) full name" },
		{ "question": "委員", "answers": [ "いいん" ], "comment": "(n) committee member" },
		{ "question": "委託", "answers": [ "いたく" ], "comment": "(n,vs) consign (goods (for sale) to a firm)/entrust (person with something)/commit" },
		{ "question": "姪", "answers": [ "めい" ], "comment": "(n) niece" },
		{ "question": "姿", "answers": [ "すがた" ], "comment": "(n) figure/shape/appearance" },
		{ "question": "姿勢", "answers": [ "しせい" ], "comment": "(n) attitude/posture" },
		{ "question": "威力", "answers": [ "いりょく" ], "comment": "(n) power/might/authority/influence" },
		{ "question": "威張る", "answers": [ "いばる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to be proud/to swagger" },
		{ "question": "娘", "answers": [ "むすめ" ], "comment": "(n) (hum) daughter" },
		{ "question": "娯楽", "answers": [ "ごらく" ], "comment": "(n) pleasure/amusement" },
		{ "question": "婉曲", "answers": [ "えんきょく" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) euphemistic/circumlocution/roundabout/indirect/insinuating" },
		{ "question": "婚約", "answers": [ "こんやく" ], "comment": "(n,vs) engagement/betrothal" },
		{ "question": "婦人", "answers": [ "ふじん" ], "comment": "(n) woman/female" },
		{ "question": "婿", "answers": [ "むこ" ], "comment": "(n) son-in-law" },
		{ "question": "嫁", "answers": [ "よめ" ], "comment": "(n) bride/daughter-in-law" },
		{ "question": "嫉妬", "answers": [ "しっと" ], "comment": "(n,vs) jealousy" },
		{ "question": "嫌", "answers": [ "いや" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) disagreeable/detestable/unpleasant/reluctant" },
		{ "question": "嫌い", "answers": [ "きらい" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) dislike/hate" },
		{ "question": "嫌う", "answers": [ "きらう" ], "comment": "(v5u) to hate/to dislike/to loathe" },
		{ "question": "嫌がる", "answers": [ "いやがる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to hate/to dislike" },
		{ "question": "嬉しい", "answers": [ "うれしい" ], "comment": "(adj) happy/glad/pleasant" },
		{ "question": "子", "answers": [ "こ" ], "comment": "(n) first sign of Chinese zodiac (The Rat, 11pm-1am, north, November)" },
		{ "question": "子供", "answers": [ "こども" ], "comment": "(n) child/children" },
		{ "question": "子孫", "answers": [ "しそん" ], "comment": "(n) descendants/posterity/offspring" },
		{ "question": "子息", "answers": [ "しそく" ], "comment": "(n) (hon) son" },
		{ "question": "字", "answers": [ "じ" ], "comment": "(n) character/hand-writing" },
		{ "question": "字体", "answers": [ "じたい" ], "comment": "(n) type/font/lettering" },
		{ "question": "字引", "answers": [ "じびき" ], "comment": "(n) dictionary" },
		{ "question": "存じる", "answers": [ "ぞんじる" ], "comment": "(v1) (hum) to know" },
		{ "question": "存在", "answers": [ "そんざい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) existence/being" },
		{ "question": "存続", "answers": [ "そんぞく" ], "comment": "(n,vs) duration/continuance" },
		{ "question": "孝行", "answers": [ "こうこう" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) filial piety" },
		{ "question": "季刊", "answers": [ "きかん" ], "comment": "(n) quarterly (e.g. magazine)" },
		{ "question": "季節", "answers": [ "きせつ" ], "comment": "(n) season" },
		{ "question": "孤児", "answers": [ "こじ" ], "comment": "(n) orphan" },
		{ "question": "孤独", "answers": [ "こどく" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) isolation/loneliness/solitude" },
		{ "question": "孤立", "answers": [ "こりつ" ], "comment": "(n) isolation/helplessness" },
		{ "question": "学", "answers": [ "がく" ], "comment": "(n) learning/scholarship/erudition/knowledge" },
		{ "question": "学ぶ", "answers": [ "まなぶ" ], "comment": "(v5b) to study (in depth)/to learn/to take lessons in" },
		{ "question": "学会", "answers": [ "がっかい" ], "comment": "(n) scientific society/academic meeting" },
		{ "question": "学力", "answers": [ "がくりょく" ], "comment": "(n) scholarship/knowledge/literary ability" },
		{ "question": "学問", "answers": [ "がくもん" ], "comment": "(n) scholarship/study/learning" },
		{ "question": "学士", "answers": [ "がくし" ], "comment": "(n) university graduate" },
		{ "question": "学年", "answers": [ "がくねん" ], "comment": "(n) year in school/grade in school" },
		{ "question": "学期", "answers": [ "がっき" ], "comment": "(n) term (school)" },
		{ "question": "学校", "answers": [ "がっこう" ], "comment": "(n) school" },
		{ "question": "学歴", "answers": [ "がくれき" ], "comment": "(n) academic background" },
		{ "question": "学生", "answers": [ "がくせい" ], "comment": "(n) student" },
		{ "question": "学科", "answers": [ "がっか" ], "comment": "(n) study subject/course of study" },
		{ "question": "学級", "answers": [ "がっきゅう" ], "comment": "(n) grade in school" },
		{ "question": "学習", "answers": [ "がくしゅう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) study/learning" },
		{ "question": "学者", "answers": [ "がくしゃ" ], "comment": "(n) scholar" },
		{ "question": "学芸", "answers": [ "がくげい" ], "comment": "(n) arts and sciences/liberal arts" },
		{ "question": "学術", "answers": [ "がくじゅつ" ], "comment": "(n) science/learning/scholarship" },
		{ "question": "学説", "answers": [ "がくせつ" ], "comment": "(n) theory" },
		{ "question": "学部", "answers": [ "がくぶ" ], "comment": "(n) department of a university/undergraduate" },
		{ "question": "孫", "answers": [ "まご" ], "comment": "(n) grandchild" },
		{ "question": "宅", "answers": [ "たく" ], "comment": "(n) house/home/husband" },
		{ "question": "宇宙", "answers": [ "うちゅう" ], "comment": "(n) universe/cosmos/space" },
		{ "question": "守る", "answers": [ "まもる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to protect/to obey/to guard/to abide (by the rules)" },
		{ "question": "守備", "answers": [ "しゅび" ], "comment": "(n) defense" },
		{ "question": "守衛", "answers": [ "しゅえい" ], "comment": "(n) security guard/doorkeeper" },
		{ "question": "安い", "answers": [ "やすい" ], "comment": "(adj) cheap/inexpensive/peaceful/quiet/gossipy/thoughtless" },
		{ "question": "安っぽい", "answers": [ "やすっぽい" ], "comment": "(adj) cheap-looking/tawdry/insignificant" },
		{ "question": "安全", "answers": [ "あんぜん" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) safety/security" },
		{ "question": "安定", "answers": [ "あんてい" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n,vs) stability/equilibrium" },
		{ "question": "安心", "answers": [ "あんしん" ], "comment": "(n) (Buddhism) obtaining peace of mind through faith or ascetic practice" },
		{ "question": "安易", "answers": [ "あんい" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) easy-going" },
		{ "question": "安静", "answers": [ "あんせい" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) rest" },
		{ "question": "完ぺき", "answers": [ "かんぺき" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) perfection/completeness/flawless" },
		{ "question": "完了", "answers": [ "かんりょう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) completion/conclusion" },
		{ "question": "完全", "answers": [ "かんぜん" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) perfection/completeness" },
		{ "question": "完成", "answers": [ "かんせい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) (1) complete/completion/(2) perfection/accomplishment" },
		{ "question": "宗教", "answers": [ "しゅうきょう" ], "comment": "(n) religion" },
		{ "question": "官僚", "answers": [ "かんりょう" ], "comment": "(n) bureaucrat/bureaucracy" },
		{ "question": "官庁", "answers": [ "かんちょう" ], "comment": "(n) government office/authorities" },
		{ "question": "宙返り", "answers": [ "ちゅうがえり" ], "comment": "(n) somersault/looping-the-loop" },
		{ "question": "定まる", "answers": [ "さだまる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to become settled/to be fixed" },
		{ "question": "定める", "answers": [ "さだめる" ], "comment": "(v1) to decide/to establish/to determine" },
		{ "question": "定休日", "answers": [ "ていきゅうび" ], "comment": "(n) regular holiday" },
		{ "question": "定価", "answers": [ "ていか" ], "comment": "(n) established price" },
		{ "question": "定員", "answers": [ "ていいん" ], "comment": "(n) fixed number of regular personnel/capacity (of boat, hall, aeroplane, etc.)" },
		{ "question": "定年", "answers": [ "ていねん" ], "comment": "(n) retirement age" },
		{ "question": "定期", "answers": [ "ていき" ], "comment": "(n) fixed term" },
		{ "question": "定期券", "answers": [ "ていきけん" ], "comment": "(n) commuter pass/season ticket" },
		{ "question": "定義", "answers": [ "ていぎ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) definition" },
		{ "question": "定規", "answers": [ "じょうぎ" ], "comment": "(n) (measuring) ruler" },
		{ "question": "定食", "answers": [ "ていしょく" ], "comment": "(n) set meal/special (of the day)" },
		{ "question": "宛てる", "answers": [ "あてる" ], "comment": "(v1) to address" },
		{ "question": "宛名", "answers": [ "あてな" ], "comment": "(n) address/direction" },
		{ "question": "宜しい", "answers": [ "よろしい" ], "comment": "(adj) (hon) good/OK/all right/fine/very well/will do/may/can" },
		{ "question": "宝", "answers": [ "たから" ], "comment": "(n) treasure" },
		{ "question": "宝石", "answers": [ "ほうせき" ], "comment": "(n) gem/jewel" },
		{ "question": "実", "answers": [ "じつ","み" ], "comment": "(n) fruit/nut/seed/content/good result" },
		{ "question": "実に", "answers": [ "じつに" ], "comment": "(adv) indeed/truly/surely" },
		{ "question": "実は", "answers": [ "じつは" ], "comment": "(adv,exp) as a matter of fact/by the way" },
		{ "question": "実る", "answers": [ "みのる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to bear fruit/to ripen" },
		{ "question": "実例", "answers": [ "じつれい" ], "comment": "(n) example/illustration" },
		{ "question": "実力", "answers": [ "じつりょく" ], "comment": "(n) merit/efficiency/arms/force" },
		{ "question": "実家", "answers": [ "じっか" ], "comment": "(n) (one's parents') home" },
		{ "question": "実感", "answers": [ "じっかん" ], "comment": "(n) feelings (actual, true)" },
		{ "question": "実態", "answers": [ "じったい" ], "comment": "(n) truth/fact" },
		{ "question": "実施", "answers": [ "じっし" ], "comment": "(n,vs) enforcement/enact/put into practice/carry out/operation" },
		{ "question": "実業家", "answers": [ "じつぎょうか" ], "comment": "(n) industrialist/businessman" },
		{ "question": "実物", "answers": [ "じつぶつ" ], "comment": "(n) real thing/original" },
		{ "question": "実現", "answers": [ "じつげん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) implementation/materialization/realization" },
		{ "question": "実用", "answers": [ "じつよう" ], "comment": "(n) practical use/utility" },
		{ "question": "実績", "answers": [ "じっせき" ], "comment": "(n) achievements/actual results" },
		{ "question": "実習", "answers": [ "じっしゅう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) practice/training" },
		{ "question": "実行", "answers": [ "じっこう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) practice/performance/execution (e.g. program)/realization" },
		{ "question": "実費", "answers": [ "じっぴ" ], "comment": "(n) actual expense/cost price" },
		{ "question": "実践", "answers": [ "じっせん" ], "comment": "(n) practice/put into practice" },
		{ "question": "実際", "answers": [ "じっさい" ], "comment": "(adj-no,adv,n) practical/actual condition/status quo" },
		{ "question": "実験", "answers": [ "じっけん" ], "comment": "(n) experiment" },
		{ "question": "客", "answers": [ "きゃく" ], "comment": "(n) guest/customer" },
		{ "question": "客席", "answers": [ "きゃくせき" ], "comment": "(n) guest seating" },
		{ "question": "客観", "answers": [ "きゃっかん" ], "comment": "(n) objective" },
		{ "question": "客間", "answers": [ "きゃくま" ], "comment": "(n) parlor/guest room" },
		{ "question": "宣伝", "answers": [ "せんでん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) propaganda/publicity" },
		{ "question": "宣教", "answers": [ "せんきょう" ], "comment": "(n) religious mission" },
		{ "question": "宣言", "answers": [ "せんげん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) declaration/proclamation/announcement" },
		{ "question": "宮殿", "answers": [ "きゅうでん" ], "comment": "(n) palace" },
		{ "question": "害", "answers": [ "がい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) injury/harm/evil influence/damage" },
		{ "question": "害する", "answers": [ "がいする" ], "comment": "(vs-s) to injure/to damage/to harm/to kill/to hinder" },
		{ "question": "宴会", "answers": [ "えんかい" ], "comment": "(n) party/banquet" },
		{ "question": "家", "answers": [ "いえ","うち" ], "comment": "(suf) house/family" },
		{ "question": "家主", "answers": [ "やぬし" ], "comment": "(n) landlord" },
		{ "question": "家事", "answers": [ "かじ" ], "comment": "(n) housework/domestic chores" },
		{ "question": "家具", "answers": [ "かぐ" ], "comment": "(n) furniture" },
		{ "question": "家内", "answers": [ "かない" ], "comment": "(n) (hum) wife" },
		{ "question": "家出", "answers": [ "いえで" ], "comment": "(n,vs) running away from home/leaving home" },
		{ "question": "家屋", "answers": [ "かおく" ], "comment": "(n) house/building" },
		{ "question": "家庭", "answers": [ "かてい" ], "comment": "(n) home/family/household" },
		{ "question": "家族", "answers": [ "かぞく" ], "comment": "(n) family/members of a family" },
		{ "question": "家来", "answers": [ "けらい" ], "comment": "(n) retainer/retinue/servant" },
		{ "question": "家畜", "answers": [ "かちく" ], "comment": "(n) domestic animals/livestock/cattle" },
		{ "question": "家計", "answers": [ "かけい" ], "comment": "(n) household economy/family finances" },
		{ "question": "家賃", "answers": [ "やちん" ], "comment": "(n) rent" },
		{ "question": "容器", "answers": [ "ようき" ], "comment": "(n) container/vessel" },
		{ "question": "容易", "answers": [ "ようい" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) easy/simple/plain" },
		{ "question": "容積", "answers": [ "ようせき" ], "comment": "(n) capacity/volume" },
		{ "question": "宿", "answers": [ "やど" ], "comment": "(n) inn/lodging" },
		{ "question": "宿命", "answers": [ "しゅくめい" ], "comment": "(n) fate/destiny/predestination" },
		{ "question": "宿泊", "answers": [ "しゅくはく" ], "comment": "(n) lodging" },
		{ "question": "宿題", "answers": [ "しゅくだい" ], "comment": "(n) homework" },
		{ "question": "寂しい", "answers": [ "さびしい" ], "comment": "(adj) lonely/lonesome/solitary/desolate" },
		{ "question": "寄せる", "answers": [ "よせる" ], "comment": "(v1) to collect/to gather/to add/to put aside" },
		{ "question": "寄り掛かる", "answers": [ "よりかかる" ], "comment": "(v5r,vi) to lean against/to recline on/to lean on/to rely on" },
		{ "question": "寄る", "answers": [ "よる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to visit/to drop in/to approach" },
		{ "question": "寄与", "answers": [ "きよ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) contribution/service" },
		{ "question": "寄付", "answers": [ "きふ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) contribution/donation" },
		{ "question": "寄贈", "answers": [ "きぞう" ], "comment": "(n) donation/presentation" },
		{ "question": "密か", "answers": [ "ひそか" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) secret/private/surreptitious" },
		{ "question": "密度", "answers": [ "みつど" ], "comment": "(n) density" },
		{ "question": "密接", "answers": [ "みっせつ" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) related/connected/close/intimate" },
		{ "question": "密集", "answers": [ "みっしゅう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) crowd/close formation/dense" },
		{ "question": "富", "answers": [ "とみ" ], "comment": "(n) wealth/fortune" },
		{ "question": "富む", "answers": [ "とむ" ], "comment": "(v5m) to be rich/to become rich" },
		{ "question": "富豪", "answers": [ "ふごう" ], "comment": "(n) wealthy person/millionaire" },
		{ "question": "寒い", "answers": [ "さむい" ], "comment": "(adj) cold (e.g. weather)" },
		{ "question": "寒帯", "answers": [ "かんたい" ], "comment": "(n) frigid zone" },
		{ "question": "寒気", "answers": [ "さむけ" ], "comment": "(n) (1) cold/frost/(2) a cold/a chill/shivering fit" },
		{ "question": "寛容", "answers": [ "かんよう" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) forbearance/tolerance/generosity" },
		{ "question": "寝かせる", "answers": [ "ねかせる" ], "comment": "(v1) to put to bed/to lay down/to ferment" },
		{ "question": "寝る", "answers": [ "ねる" ], "comment": "(v1) to go to bed/to lie down/to sleep" },
		{ "question": "寝台", "answers": [ "しんだい" ], "comment": "(n) bed/couch" },
		{ "question": "寝坊", "answers": [ "ねぼう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) sleeping in late" },
		{ "question": "寝巻", "answers": [ "ねまき" ], "comment": "(n) sleep-wear/nightclothes/pyjamas/nightgown/nightdress" },
		{ "question": "寝間着", "answers": [ "ねまき" ], "comment": "(n) sleep-wear/nightclothes/pyjamas/nightgown/nightdress" },
		{ "question": "察する", "answers": [ "さっする" ], "comment": "(vs-s) to guess/to sense/to presume/to judge/to sympathize with" },
		{ "question": "寧ろ", "answers": [ "むしろ" ], "comment": "(adv) rather/better/instead" },
		{ "question": "審判", "answers": [ "しんぱん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) refereeing/trial/judgement/umpire/referee" },
		{ "question": "審査", "answers": [ "しんさ" ], "comment": "(n) judging/inspection/examination/investigation" },
		{ "question": "審議", "answers": [ "しんぎ" ], "comment": "(n) deliberation" },
		{ "question": "寮", "answers": [ "りょう" ], "comment": "(n) hostel/dormitory" },
		{ "question": "寸法", "answers": [ "すんぽう" ], "comment": "(n) measurement/size/dimension" },
		{ "question": "寺", "answers": [ "てら" ], "comment": "(n) temple" },
		{ "question": "寺院", "answers": [ "じいん" ], "comment": "(n) temple" },
		{ "question": "対", "answers": [ "たい","つい" ], "comment": "(n) pair/couple/set" },
		{ "question": "対する", "answers": [ "たいする" ], "comment": "(vs-s) to face/to confront/to oppose" },
		{ "question": "対処", "answers": [ "たいしょ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) deal with/cope" },
		{ "question": "対応", "answers": [ "たいおう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) interaction/correspondence/coping with/dealing with" },
		{ "question": "対抗", "answers": [ "たいこう" ], "comment": "(n) opposition/antagonism" },
		{ "question": "対比", "answers": [ "たいひ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) contrast/comparison" },
		{ "question": "対決", "answers": [ "たいけつ" ], "comment": "(n) confrontation/showdown" },
		{ "question": "対照", "answers": [ "たいしょう" ], "comment": "(n) contrast/antithesis/comparison" },
		{ "question": "対立", "answers": [ "たいりつ" ], "comment": "(n) confrontation/opposition/antagonism" },
		{ "question": "対等", "answers": [ "たいとう" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) equivalent" },
		{ "question": "対策", "answers": [ "たいさく" ], "comment": "(n) counter-plan/counter-measure" },
		{ "question": "対話", "answers": [ "たいわ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) interactive/interaction/conversation/dialogue" },
		{ "question": "対談", "answers": [ "たいだん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) talk/dialogue/conversation" },
		{ "question": "対象", "answers": [ "たいしょう" ], "comment": "(n) target/object (of worship, study, etc)/subject (of taxation, etc)" },
		{ "question": "対面", "answers": [ "たいめん" ], "comment": "(n) interview/meeting" },
		{ "question": "寿命", "answers": [ "じゅみょう" ], "comment": "(n) life span" },
		{ "question": "封", "answers": [ "ふう" ], "comment": "(n) seal" },
		{ "question": "封建", "answers": [ "ほうけん" ], "comment": "(n) feudalistic" },
		{ "question": "封筒", "answers": [ "ふうとう" ], "comment": "(n) envelope" },
		{ "question": "封鎖", "answers": [ "ふうさ" ], "comment": "(n) blockade/freezing (funds)" },
		{ "question": "専ら", "answers": [ "もっぱら" ], "comment": "(adv) wholly/solely/entirely" },
		{ "question": "専修", "answers": [ "せんしゅう" ], "comment": "(n) specialization" },
		{ "question": "専制", "answers": [ "せんせい" ], "comment": "(n) despotism/autocracy" },
		{ "question": "専攻", "answers": [ "せんこう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) major subject/special study" },
		{ "question": "専用", "answers": [ "せんよう" ], "comment": "(n,pref,suf) exclusive use/personal use" },
		{ "question": "専門", "answers": [ "せんもん" ], "comment": "(n) speciality/subject of study/expert" },
		{ "question": "射す", "answers": [ "さす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to shine/to strike" },
		{ "question": "将来", "answers": [ "しょうらい" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n-t) future/prospects" },
		{ "question": "将棋", "answers": [ "しょうぎ" ], "comment": "(n) Japanese chess" },
		{ "question": "尊い", "answers": [ "とうとい" ], "comment": "(adj) precious/valuable/priceless/noble/exalted/sacred" },
		{ "question": "尊ぶ", "answers": [ "とうとぶ" ], "comment": "(v5b) to value/to prize/to esteem" },
		{ "question": "尊敬", "answers": [ "そんけい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) respect/esteem/reverence/honour" },
		{ "question": "尊重", "answers": [ "そんちょう" ], "comment": "(n) respect/esteem/regard" },
		{ "question": "尋ねる", "answers": [ "たずねる" ], "comment": "(v1) to ask/to enquire" },
		{ "question": "導く", "answers": [ "みちびく" ], "comment": "(v5k) to be guided/to be shown" },
		{ "question": "導入", "answers": [ "どうにゅう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) introduction/bringing in/leading in" },
		{ "question": "小さい", "answers": [ "ちいさい" ], "comment": "(adj) small/little/tiny" },
		{ "question": "小便", "answers": [ "しょうべん" ], "comment": "(n) (col) urine/piss" },
		{ "question": "小児科", "answers": [ "しょうにか" ], "comment": "(n) pediatrics" },
		{ "question": "小切手", "answers": [ "こぎって" ], "comment": "(n) cheque/check" },
		{ "question": "小包", "answers": [ "こづつみ" ], "comment": "(n) parcel/package" },
		{ "question": "小売", "answers": [ "こうり" ], "comment": "(n,vs) retail" },
		{ "question": "小学校", "answers": [ "しょうがっこう" ], "comment": "(n) primary school/elementary school" },
		{ "question": "小学生", "answers": [ "しょうがくせい" ], "comment": "(n) grade school student" },
		{ "question": "小屋", "answers": [ "こや" ], "comment": "(n) hut/cabin/shed/(animal) pen" },
		{ "question": "小指", "answers": [ "こゆび" ], "comment": "(n) little finger" },
		{ "question": "小数", "answers": [ "しょうすう" ], "comment": "(n) fraction (part of)/decimal" },
		{ "question": "小柄", "answers": [ "こがら" ], "comment": "(n) knife attached to the sheath of a sword" },
		{ "question": "小母さん", "answers": [ "おばさん" ], "comment": "(n) (uk) lady/woman/ma'am" },
		{ "question": "小父さん", "answers": [ "おじさん" ], "comment": "(n) (hon) (uk) middle-aged gentleman/uncle" },
		{ "question": "小説", "answers": [ "しょうせつ" ], "comment": "(n) novel/story" },
		{ "question": "小遣い", "answers": [ "こづかい" ], "comment": "(n) personal expenses/pocket money/spending money/incidental expenses/allowance" },
		{ "question": "小銭", "answers": [ "こぜに" ], "comment": "(n) coins/small change" },
		{ "question": "小鳥", "answers": [ "ことり" ], "comment": "(n) small bird" },
		{ "question": "小麦", "answers": [ "こむぎ" ], "comment": "(n) wheat" },
		{ "question": "少々", "answers": [ "しょうしょう" ], "comment": "(adv,exp,n-adv,n) just a minute/small quantity" },
		{ "question": "少し", "answers": [ "すこし" ], "comment": "(adv,n) (1) small quantity/little/few/something/(2) little while/(3) short distance" },
		{ "question": "少しも", "answers": [ "すこしも" ], "comment": "(adv,exp) anything of/not one bit" },
		{ "question": "少ない", "answers": [ "すくない" ], "comment": "(adj) few/a little/scarce/insufficient/seldom" },
		{ "question": "少女", "answers": [ "しょうじょ" ], "comment": "(n) daughter/young lady/virgin/maiden/little girl" },
		{ "question": "少年", "answers": [ "しょうねん" ], "comment": "(n) boys/juveniles" },
		{ "question": "尖る", "answers": [ "とがる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to taper to a point/to become sharp/to be sour/to look displeased" },
		{ "question": "尤も", "answers": [ "もっとも" ], "comment": "(adj-na,adv,conj,n) quite right/plausible/natural/but then/although" },
		{ "question": "就く", "answers": [ "つく" ], "comment": "(v5k) to settle in (place)/to take (seat, position)/to study (under teacher)" },
		{ "question": "就任", "answers": [ "しゅうにん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) inauguration/assumption of office" },
		{ "question": "就業", "answers": [ "しゅうぎょう" ], "comment": "(n) employment/starting work" },
		{ "question": "就職", "answers": [ "しゅうしょく" ], "comment": "(n,vs) finding employment/inauguration" },
		{ "question": "尻", "answers": [ "しり" ], "comment": "(n) buttocks/bottom" },
		{ "question": "尽きる", "answers": [ "つきる" ], "comment": "(v1) to be used up/to be run out/to be exhausted/to be consumed/to come to an end" },
		{ "question": "尽くす", "answers": [ "つくす" ], "comment": "(v5s) (1) to exhaust/to run out/(2) to devote/to serve (a person)/to befriend" },
		{ "question": "尾", "answers": [ "お" ], "comment": "(n) tail/ridge" },
		{ "question": "尿", "answers": [ "にょう" ], "comment": "(n) urine" },
		{ "question": "局", "answers": [ "きょく" ], "comment": "(n) court lady/lady in waiting" },
		{ "question": "局限", "answers": [ "きょくげん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) limit/localize" },
		{ "question": "居る", "answers": [ "いる","おる" ], "comment": "(v5r) (uk) (hum) to be (animate)/to be/to exist" },
		{ "question": "居住", "answers": [ "きょじゅう" ], "comment": "(n) residence" },
		{ "question": "居眠り", "answers": [ "いねむり" ], "comment": "(n,vs) dozing/nodding off" },
		{ "question": "居間", "answers": [ "いま" ], "comment": "(n) living room (western style)" },
		{ "question": "屈折", "answers": [ "くっせつ" ], "comment": "(n) bending/indentation/refraction" },
		{ "question": "届", "answers": [ "とどけ" ], "comment": "(n,n-suf) report/notification/registration" },
		{ "question": "届く", "answers": [ "とどく" ], "comment": "(v5k,vi) to reach" },
		{ "question": "届ける", "answers": [ "とどける" ], "comment": "(v1) to deliver/to forward/to send/to report/to file notice (to the authorities)" },
		{ "question": "屋上", "answers": [ "おくじょう" ], "comment": "(n) rooftop" },
		{ "question": "屋外", "answers": [ "おくがい" ], "comment": "(n) outdoors" },
		{ "question": "屋敷", "answers": [ "やしき" ], "comment": "(n) mansion" },
		{ "question": "屋根", "answers": [ "やね" ], "comment": "(n) roof" },
		{ "question": "屎尿", "answers": [ "しにょう" ], "comment": "(n) excreta/raw sewage/human waste/night soil" },
		{ "question": "屑", "answers": [ "くず" ], "comment": "(n) waste/scrap" },
		{ "question": "展望", "answers": [ "てんぼう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) view/outlook/prospect" },
		{ "question": "展示", "answers": [ "てんじ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) exhibition/display" },
		{ "question": "展覧会", "answers": [ "てんらんかい" ], "comment": "(n) exhibition" },
		{ "question": "展開", "answers": [ "てんかい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) develop/expansion (opposite of compression)" },
		{ "question": "属する", "answers": [ "ぞくする" ], "comment": "(vs-s) to belong to/to come under/to be affiliated with/to be subject to" },
		{ "question": "履く", "answers": [ "はく" ], "comment": "(v5k) to wear/to put on (lower body)" },
		{ "question": "履歴", "answers": [ "りれき" ], "comment": "(n) personal history/background/career/log" },
		{ "question": "山", "answers": [ "やま" ], "comment": "(n) (1) mountain/(2) pile/heap/(3) climax/critical point" },
		{ "question": "山岳", "answers": [ "さんがく" ], "comment": "(n) mountains" },
		{ "question": "山林", "answers": [ "さんりん" ], "comment": "(n) mountain forest/mountains and forest" },
		{ "question": "山脈", "answers": [ "さんみゃく" ], "comment": "(n) mountain range" },
		{ "question": "山腹", "answers": [ "さんぷく" ], "comment": "(n) hillside/mountainside" },
		{ "question": "岩", "answers": [ "いわ" ], "comment": "(n) rock/crag" },
		{ "question": "岩石", "answers": [ "がんせき" ], "comment": "(n) rock" },
		{ "question": "岬", "answers": [ "みさき" ], "comment": "(n) cape (on coast)" },
		{ "question": "岸", "answers": [ "きし" ], "comment": "(n) bank/coast/shore" },
		{ "question": "峠", "answers": [ "とうげ" ], "comment": "(n,n-suf) ridge/(mountain) pass/difficult part" },
		{ "question": "峰", "answers": [ "みね" ], "comment": "(n) peak/ridge" },
		{ "question": "島", "answers": [ "しま" ], "comment": "(n) island" },
		{ "question": "崇拝", "answers": [ "すうはい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) worship/adoration/admiration/cult" },
		{ "question": "崖", "answers": [ "がけ" ], "comment": "(n) cliff" },
		{ "question": "崩す", "answers": [ "くずす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to destroy/to pull down/to make change (money)" },
		{ "question": "崩れる", "answers": [ "くずれる" ], "comment": "(v1) to collapse/to crumble" },
		{ "question": "崩壊", "answers": [ "ほうかい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) collapse/decay (physics)/crumbling/breaking down/caving in" },
		{ "question": "嵐", "answers": [ "あらし" ], "comment": "(n) storm/tempest" },
		{ "question": "川", "answers": [ "かわ" ], "comment": "(n) river" },
		{ "question": "州", "answers": [ "しゅう" ], "comment": "(n) sandbank" },
		{ "question": "巡る", "answers": [ "めぐる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to go around" },
		{ "question": "巡査", "answers": [ "じゅんさ" ], "comment": "(n) police/policeman" },
		{ "question": "巣", "answers": [ "す" ], "comment": "(n) nest/rookery/breeding place/beehive/cobweb/den/haunt" },
		{ "question": "工事", "answers": [ "こうじ" ], "comment": "(n) construction work" },
		{ "question": "工作", "answers": [ "こうさく" ], "comment": "(n) work/construction/handicraft/maneuvering" },
		{ "question": "工員", "answers": [ "こういん" ], "comment": "(n) factory worker" },
		{ "question": "工場", "answers": [ "こうじょう","こうば" ], "comment": "(n) factory/plant/mill/workshop" },
		{ "question": "工夫", "answers": [ "くふう" ], "comment": "(n) labourer/worker" },
		{ "question": "工学", "answers": [ "こうがく" ], "comment": "(n) engineering" },
		{ "question": "工業", "answers": [ "こうぎょう" ], "comment": "(n) (manufacturing) industry" },
		{ "question": "工芸", "answers": [ "こうげい" ], "comment": "(n) industrial arts" },
		{ "question": "左", "answers": [ "ひだり" ], "comment": "(n) left hand side" },
		{ "question": "左利き", "answers": [ "ひだりきき" ], "comment": "(n) left-handedness/sake drinker/left-hander" },
		{ "question": "左右", "answers": [ "さゆう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) (1) left and right/(2) influence/control/domination" },
		{ "question": "巧み", "answers": [ "たくみ" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) skill/cleverness" },
		{ "question": "巧妙", "answers": [ "こうみょう" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) ingenious/skillful/clever/deft" },
		{ "question": "巨大", "answers": [ "きょだい" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) huge/gigantic/enormous" },
		{ "question": "差", "answers": [ "さ" ], "comment": "(n,n-suf) difference/variation" },
		{ "question": "差し上げる", "answers": [ "さしあげる" ], "comment": "(v1) (pol) to give/to hold up/to lift up/to offer" },
		{ "question": "差し出す", "answers": [ "さしだす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to present/to submit/to tender/to hold out" },
		{ "question": "差し引き", "answers": [ "さしひき" ], "comment": "(n) deduction/subtraction/balance/ebb and flow/rise and fall" },
		{ "question": "差し支え", "answers": [ "さしつかえ" ], "comment": "(n) hindrance/impediment" },
		{ "question": "差し支える", "answers": [ "さしつかえる" ], "comment": "(v1) to interfere/to hinder/to become impeded" },
		{ "question": "差す", "answers": [ "さす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to raise (stretch out) hands/to raise umbrella" },
		{ "question": "差別", "answers": [ "さべつ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) discrimination/distinction/differentiation" },
		{ "question": "差額", "answers": [ "さがく" ], "comment": "(n) balance/difference/margin" },
		{ "question": "巻く", "answers": [ "まく" ], "comment": "(v5k) to wind/to coil/to roll" },
		{ "question": "市", "answers": [ "いち","し" ], "comment": "(n-suf) city" },
		{ "question": "市場", "answers": [ "いちば","しじょう" ], "comment": "(n) (the) market (as a concept)" },
		{ "question": "市民", "answers": [ "しみん" ], "comment": "(n) citizen/townspeople" },
		{ "question": "布", "answers": [ "ぬの" ], "comment": "(n) cloth" },
		{ "question": "布告", "answers": [ "ふこく" ], "comment": "(n,vs) edict/ordinance/proclamation" },
		{ "question": "布団", "answers": [ "ふとん" ], "comment": "(n) bedding (Japanese style)/futon" },
		{ "question": "布巾", "answers": [ "ふきん" ], "comment": "(n) tea-towel/dish cloth" },
		{ "question": "希望", "answers": [ "きぼう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) hope/wish/aspiration" },
		{ "question": "席", "answers": [ "せき" ], "comment": "(n) seat" },
		{ "question": "帯", "answers": [ "おび" ], "comment": "(n-suf) band (e.g. conduction, valence)" },
		{ "question": "帯びる", "answers": [ "おびる" ], "comment": "(v1) to wear/to carry/to be entrusted/to have/to take on/to have a trace of/to be tinged with" },
		{ "question": "帰す", "answers": [ "かえす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to send back" },
		{ "question": "帰り", "answers": [ "かえり" ], "comment": "(n) return/coming back" },
		{ "question": "帰る", "answers": [ "かえる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to go back/to go home/to come home/to return" },
		{ "question": "帰京", "answers": [ "ききょう" ], "comment": "(n) returning to Tokyo" },
		{ "question": "帰宅", "answers": [ "きたく" ], "comment": "(n,vs) returning home" },
		{ "question": "常に", "answers": [ "つねに" ], "comment": "(adv) always/constantly" },
		{ "question": "常識", "answers": [ "じょうしき" ], "comment": "(n) common sense" },
		{ "question": "帽子", "answers": [ "ぼうし" ], "comment": "(n) hat" },
		{ "question": "幅", "answers": [ "はば" ], "comment": "(n) width/breadth" },
		{ "question": "幕", "answers": [ "まく" ], "comment": "curtain/bunting/act (in play)" },
		{ "question": "干し物", "answers": [ "ほしもの" ], "comment": "(n) dried washing (clothes)" },
		{ "question": "干す", "answers": [ "ほす" ], "comment": "(v5s,vt) to air/to dry/to desiccate/to drain (off)/to drink up" },
		{ "question": "干渉", "answers": [ "かんしょう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) interference/intervention" },
		{ "question": "平たい", "answers": [ "ひらたい" ], "comment": "(adj) flat/even/level/simple/plain" },
		{ "question": "平ら", "answers": [ "たいら" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) flatness/level/smooth/calm/plain/sitting tailor fashion" },
		{ "question": "平仮名", "answers": [ "ひらがな" ], "comment": "(n) hiragana/47 syllables/the cursive syllabary" },
		{ "question": "平凡", "answers": [ "へいぼん" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) common/commonplace/ordinary/mediocre" },
		{ "question": "平和", "answers": [ "へいわ" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) peace/harmony" },
		{ "question": "平均", "answers": [ "へいきん" ], "comment": "(n) equilibrium/balance/average/mean" },
		{ "question": "平常", "answers": [ "へいじょう" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n-adv,n-t) normal/usual" },
		{ "question": "平方", "answers": [ "へいほう" ], "comment": "(n) square (e.g. metre)/square" },
		{ "question": "平日", "answers": [ "へいじつ" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n) weekday/ordinary days" },
		{ "question": "平気", "answers": [ "へいき" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) coolness/calmness/composure/unconcern" },
		{ "question": "平等", "answers": [ "びょうどう" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) equality (a)/impartiality/evenness" },
		{ "question": "平野", "answers": [ "へいや" ], "comment": "(n) plain/open field" },
		{ "question": "年", "answers": [ "とし" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n) year/age" },
		{ "question": "年中", "answers": [ "ねんじゅう" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n) whole year/always/everyday" },
		{ "question": "年代", "answers": [ "ねんだい" ], "comment": "(n) age/era/period/date" },
		{ "question": "年号", "answers": [ "ねんごう" ], "comment": "(n) name of an era/year number" },
		{ "question": "年寄", "answers": [ "としより" ], "comment": "(n) old people/the aged" },
		{ "question": "年度", "answers": [ "ねんど" ], "comment": "(n,n-suf) year/fiscal year/school year/term" },
		{ "question": "年月", "answers": [ "としつき","ねんげつ" ], "comment": "(n) months and years" },
		{ "question": "年賀", "answers": [ "ねんが" ], "comment": "(n) New Year's greetings/New Year's card" },
		{ "question": "年輪", "answers": [ "ねんりん" ], "comment": "(n) annual tree ring" },
		{ "question": "年鑑", "answers": [ "ねんかん" ], "comment": "(n) yearbook" },
		{ "question": "年長", "answers": [ "ねんちょう" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) seniority" },
		{ "question": "年間", "answers": [ "ねんかん" ], "comment": "(n-t) year" },
		{ "question": "年頃", "answers": [ "としごろ" ], "comment": "(adv,n) age/marriageable age/age of puberty/adolescence/for some years" },
		{ "question": "年齢", "answers": [ "ねんれい" ], "comment": "(n) age/years" },
		{ "question": "幸い", "answers": [ "さいわい" ], "comment": "(adj-na,adv,n) happiness/blessedness" },
		{ "question": "幸せ", "answers": [ "しあわせ" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) happiness/good fortune/luck/blessing" },
		{ "question": "幸福", "answers": [ "こうふく" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) happiness/blessedness" },
		{ "question": "幸運", "answers": [ "こううん" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) good luck/fortune" },
		{ "question": "幹", "answers": [ "みき" ], "comment": "(n) (tree) trunk" },
		{ "question": "幹線", "answers": [ "かんせん" ], "comment": "(n) main line/trunk line" },
		{ "question": "幹部", "answers": [ "かんぶ" ], "comment": "(n) management/(executive) staff/leaders" },
		{ "question": "幼い", "answers": [ "おさない" ], "comment": "(adj) very young/childish" },
		{ "question": "幼児", "answers": [ "ようじ" ], "comment": "(n) infant/baby/child" },
		{ "question": "幼稚園", "answers": [ "ようちえん" ], "comment": "(n) kindergarten" },
		{ "question": "幽霊", "answers": [ "ゆうれい" ], "comment": "(n) ghost/specter/apparition/phantom" },
		{ "question": "幾つ", "answers": [ "いくつ" ], "comment": "(n) how many?/how old?" },
		{ "question": "幾ら", "answers": [ "いくら" ], "comment": "(adv,n) how much?/how many?" },
		{ "question": "幾分", "answers": [ "いくぶん" ], "comment": "(adv,n) somewhat" },
		{ "question": "幾多", "answers": [ "いくた" ], "comment": "(adv,n) many/numerous" },
		{ "question": "広々", "answers": [ "ひろびろ" ], "comment": "(adj-na,adv,n) extensive/spacious" },
		{ "question": "広い", "answers": [ "ひろい" ], "comment": "(adj) spacious/vast/wide" },
		{ "question": "広がる", "answers": [ "ひろがる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to spread (out)/to extend/to stretch/to reach to/to get around" },
		{ "question": "広げる", "answers": [ "ひろげる" ], "comment": "(v1) to spread/to extend/to expand/to enlarge/to widen/to broaden/to unfold/to open/to unroll" },
		{ "question": "広さ", "answers": [ "ひろさ" ], "comment": "(n) extent" },
		{ "question": "広まる", "answers": [ "ひろまる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to spread/to be propagated" },
		{ "question": "広める", "answers": [ "ひろめる" ], "comment": "(v1) to broaden/to propagate" },
		{ "question": "広告", "answers": [ "こうこく" ], "comment": "(n) advertisement" },
		{ "question": "広場", "answers": [ "ひろば" ], "comment": "(n) plaza" },
		{ "question": "庇う", "answers": [ "かばう" ], "comment": "(v5u) to protect someone/to take under one's wing/to plead for/to stick up for/to cover up for someone" },
		{ "question": "床", "answers": [ "ゆか", "とこ" ], "comment": "(n) floor\n(n) bed" },
		{ "question": "床の間", "answers": [ "とこのま" ], "comment": "(n) alcove" },
		{ "question": "床屋", "answers": [ "とこや" ], "comment": "(n) barber" },
		{ "question": "底", "answers": [ "そこ" ], "comment": "(n) bottom/sole" },
		{ "question": "庖丁", "answers": [ "ほうちょう" ], "comment": "(n) kitchen knife/carving knife" },
		{ "question": "店", "answers": [ "みせ" ], "comment": "(n,n-suf) store/shop/establishment" },
		{ "question": "店員", "answers": [ "てんいん" ], "comment": "(n) shop assistant/employee/clerk/salesperson" },
		{ "question": "店屋", "answers": [ "みせや" ], "comment": "(n) store/shop" },
		{ "question": "度", "answers": [ "たび","ど" ], "comment": "(n,n-suf) counter for occurrences" },
		{ "question": "度忘れ", "answers": [ "どわすれ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) lapse of memory/forget for a moment" },
		{ "question": "座る", "answers": [ "すわる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to sit" },
		{ "question": "座布団", "answers": [ "ざぶとん" ], "comment": "(n) cushion (Japanese)/square cushion used when sitting on one's knees in a tatami-mat floor" },
		{ "question": "座席", "answers": [ "ざせき" ], "comment": "(n) seat" },
		{ "question": "座敷", "answers": [ "ざしき" ], "comment": "(n) tatami room" },
		{ "question": "座標", "answers": [ "ざひょう" ], "comment": "(n) coordinate(s)" },
		{ "question": "座談会", "answers": [ "ざだんかい" ], "comment": "(n) symposium/round-table discussion" },
		{ "question": "庭", "answers": [ "にわ" ], "comment": "(n) garden" },
		{ "question": "庶務", "answers": [ "しょむ" ], "comment": "(n) general affairs" },
		{ "question": "庶民", "answers": [ "しょみん" ], "comment": "(n) masses/common people" },
		{ "question": "廃棄", "answers": [ "はいき" ], "comment": "(n,vs) annullment/disposal/abandon/scrap/discarding/repeal" },
		{ "question": "廃止", "answers": [ "はいし" ], "comment": "(n,vs) abolition/repeal" },
		{ "question": "廊下", "answers": [ "ろうか" ], "comment": "(n) corridor" },
		{ "question": "延ばす", "answers": [ "のばす" ], "comment": "(v5s,vt) to lengthen/to stretch/to reach out/to postpone/to prolong/to extend/to grow (beard)" },
		{ "question": "延びる", "answers": [ "のびる" ], "comment": "(v1) to be prolonged" },
		{ "question": "延べ", "answers": [ "のべ" ], "comment": "(n) futures/credit (buying)/stretching/total" },
		{ "question": "延期", "answers": [ "えんき" ], "comment": "(n,vs) postponement/adjournment" },
		{ "question": "延長", "answers": [ "えんちょう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) extension/elongation/prolongation/lengthening" },
		{ "question": "建つ", "answers": [ "たつ" ], "comment": "(v5t) to erect/to be erected/to be built" },
		{ "question": "建てる", "answers": [ "たてる" ], "comment": "(v1) to build/to construct" },
		{ "question": "建前", "answers": [ "たてまえ" ], "comment": "(n) face/official stance/public position or attitude (as opposed to private thoughts)" },
		{ "question": "建物", "answers": [ "たてもの" ], "comment": "(n) building" },
		{ "question": "建築", "answers": [ "けんちく" ], "comment": "(n,vs) construction/architecture" },
		{ "question": "建設", "answers": [ "けんせつ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) construction/establishment" },
		{ "question": "弁償", "answers": [ "べんしょう" ], "comment": "(n) next word/compensation/reparation/indemnity/reimbursement" },
		{ "question": "弁当", "answers": [ "べんとう" ], "comment": "(n) box lunch" },
		{ "question": "弁解", "answers": [ "べんかい" ], "comment": "(n) explanation/justification/defence/excuse" },
		{ "question": "弁論", "answers": [ "べんろん" ], "comment": "(n) discussion/debate/argument" },
		{ "question": "弁護", "answers": [ "べんご" ], "comment": "(n) defense/pleading/advocacy" },
		{ "question": "式", "answers": [ "しき" ], "comment": "(n,n-suf) equation/formula/ceremony" },
		{ "question": "式場", "answers": [ "しきじょう" ], "comment": "(n) ceremonial hall/place of ceremony (e.g. marriage)" },
		{ "question": "弓", "answers": [ "ゆみ" ], "comment": "(n) bow (and arrow)" },
		{ "question": "引きずる", "answers": [ "ひきずる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to seduce/to drag along/to pull/to prolong/to support" },
		{ "question": "引き上げる", "answers": [ "ひきあげる" ], "comment": "(v1) to withdraw/to leave/to pull out/to retire" },
		{ "question": "引き出し", "answers": [ "ひきだし" ], "comment": "(n) drawer/drawing out" },
		{ "question": "引き止める", "answers": [ "ひきとめる" ], "comment": "(v1) to detain/to check/to restrain" },
		{ "question": "引き起こす", "answers": [ "ひきおこす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to cause" },
		{ "question": "引く", "answers": [ "ひく" ], "comment": "(v5k) minus/to pull/to play (string instr.)" },
		{ "question": "引っ張る", "answers": [ "ひっぱる" ], "comment": "(v5r) (1) to pull/to draw/to stretch/to drag/(2) to pull the ball (baseball)" },
		{ "question": "引っ掛かる", "answers": [ "ひっかかる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to be caught in/to be stuck in/to be cheated" },
		{ "question": "引っ掻く", "answers": [ "ひっかく" ], "comment": "(v5k) to scratch" },
		{ "question": "引っ繰り返す", "answers": [ "ひっくりかえす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to turn over/to overturn/to knock over/to upset/to turn inside out" },
		{ "question": "引っ繰り返る", "answers": [ "ひっくりかえる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to be overturned/to be upset/to topple over/to be reversed" },
		{ "question": "引っ越す", "answers": [ "ひっこす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to move/to change residence" },
		{ "question": "引っ込む", "answers": [ "ひっこむ" ], "comment": "(v5m) to draw back/to sink/to cave in" },
		{ "question": "引下げる", "answers": [ "ひきさげる" ], "comment": "(v1) to pull down/to lower/to reduce/to withdraw" },
		{ "question": "引出す", "answers": [ "ひきだす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to pull out/to take out/to draw out/to withdraw" },
		{ "question": "引分け", "answers": [ "ひきわけ" ], "comment": "(n) a draw (in competition)/tie game" },
		{ "question": "引力", "answers": [ "いんりょく" ], "comment": "(n) gravity" },
		{ "question": "引取る", "answers": [ "ひきとる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to take charge of/to take over/to retire to a private place" },
		{ "question": "引受る", "answers": [ "ひきうける" ], "comment": "(v1) to undertake/to take up/to take over/to be responsible for/to guarantee/to contract (disease)" },
		{ "question": "引用", "answers": [ "いんよう" ], "comment": "(n) quotation/citation" },
		{ "question": "引算", "answers": [ "ひきざん" ], "comment": "(n) subtraction" },
		{ "question": "引越し", "answers": [ "ひっこし" ], "comment": "(io) (n) moving (dwelling, office, etc.)/changing residence" },
		{ "question": "引返す", "answers": [ "ひきかえす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to repeat/to send back/to bring back/to retrace one's steps" },
		{ "question": "引退", "answers": [ "いんたい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) retire" },
		{ "question": "弛み", "answers": [ "たるみ" ], "comment": "(n) slack/slackening/dullness/letdown" },
		{ "question": "弛む", "answers": [ "たるむ" ], "comment": "(v5m,vi) to slacken/to loosen/to relax" },
		{ "question": "弟", "answers": [ "おとうと" ], "comment": "(n) younger brother/faithful service to those older/brotherly affection" },
		{ "question": "弟子", "answers": [ "でし" ], "comment": "(n) pupil/disciple/adherent/follower/apprentice/young person/teacher's student-helper" },
		{ "question": "弱", "answers": [ "じゃく" ], "comment": "weak/delicate/supple" },
		{ "question": "弱い", "answers": [ "よわい" ], "comment": "(adj) weak/frail/delicate/tender/unskilled/weak (wine)" },
		{ "question": "弱まる", "answers": [ "よわまる" ], "comment": "(v5r,vi) to abate/to weaken/to be emaciated/to be dejected/to be perplexed" },
		{ "question": "弱める", "answers": [ "よわめる" ], "comment": "(v1,vt) to weaken" },
		{ "question": "弱る", "answers": [ "よわる" ], "comment": "(v5r,vi,vt) to weaken/to be troubled/to be downcast/to be emaciated/to be dejected/to be perplexed/to impair" },
		{ "question": "弱点", "answers": [ "じゃくてん" ], "comment": "(n) weak point/weakness" },
		{ "question": "張り切る", "answers": [ "はりきる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to be in high spirits/to be full of vigor/to be enthusiastic/to be eager/to stretch to breaking point" },
		{ "question": "張り紙", "answers": [ "はりがみ" ], "comment": "(n) paper patch/paper backing/poster" },
		{ "question": "張る", "answers": [ "はる" ], "comment": "(v5r,vi,vt) to stick/to paste/to put/to affix/to stretch/to spread/to strain/to stick out/to slap/to be expensive/to tighten" },
		{ "question": "強い", "answers": [ "つよい" ], "comment": "(adj) strong/powerful/mighty/potent" },
		{ "question": "強いて", "answers": [ "しいて" ], "comment": "(adv) by force" },
		{ "question": "強いる", "answers": [ "しいる" ], "comment": "(v1) to force/to compel/to coerce" },
		{ "question": "強まる", "answers": [ "つよまる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to get strong/to gain strength" },
		{ "question": "強める", "answers": [ "つよめる" ], "comment": "(v1) to strengthen/to emphasize" },
		{ "question": "強制", "answers": [ "きょうせい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) obligation/coercion/compulsion/enforcement" },
		{ "question": "強力", "answers": [ "きょうりょく" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) herculean strength/mountain carrier-guide" },
		{ "question": "強化", "answers": [ "きょうか" ], "comment": "(n,vs) strengthen/intensify/reinforce/solidify" },
		{ "question": "強引", "answers": [ "ごういん" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) overbearing/coercive/pushy/forcible/high-handed" },
		{ "question": "強気", "answers": [ "つよき" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) firm/strong" },
		{ "question": "強烈", "answers": [ "きょうれつ" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) strong/intense/severe" },
		{ "question": "強盗", "answers": [ "ごうとう" ], "comment": "(n) robbery/burglary" },
		{ "question": "強硬", "answers": [ "きょうこう" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) firm/vigorous/unbending/unyielding/strong/stubborn" },
		{ "question": "強行", "answers": [ "きょうこう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) forcing/enforcement" },
		{ "question": "強調", "answers": [ "きょうちょう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) emphasis/stress/stressed point" },
		{ "question": "弾", "answers": [ "たま" ], "comment": "(n) bullet/shot/shell" },
		{ "question": "弾く", "answers": [ "はじく","ひく" ], "comment": "(v5k) to play (piano, guitar)" },
		{ "question": "弾む", "answers": [ "はずむ" ], "comment": "(v5m) to spring/to bound/to bounce/to be stimulated/to be encouraged/to get lively/to treat oneself to/to splurge on" },
		{ "question": "弾力", "answers": [ "だんりょく" ], "comment": "(n) elasticity/flexibility" },
		{ "question": "当たる", "answers": [ "あたる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to be hit/to be successful/to face (confront)/to lie (in the direction of)/to undertake/to treat/to be equivalent to/to apply to/to be applicable/to be assigned" },
		{ "question": "当て", "answers": [ "あて" ], "comment": "(n) object/aim/end/hopes/expectations" },
		{ "question": "当てる", "answers": [ "あてる" ], "comment": "(v1) to hit/to apply a patch" },
		{ "question": "当て字", "answers": [ "あてじ" ], "comment": "(n) phonetic-equivalent character/substitute character" },
		{ "question": "当り", "answers": [ "あたり" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n) hit/success/reaching the mark/per .../vicinity/neighborhood" },
		{ "question": "当人", "answers": [ "とうにん" ], "comment": "(n) the one concerned/the said person" },
		{ "question": "当日", "answers": [ "とうじつ" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n-t) appointed day/very day" },
		{ "question": "当時", "answers": [ "とうじ" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n-t) at that time/in those days" },
		{ "question": "当然", "answers": [ "とうぜん" ], "comment": "(adj-na,adv,n) naturally/as a matter of course" },
		{ "question": "当番", "answers": [ "とうばん" ], "comment": "(n) being on duty" },
		{ "question": "当選", "answers": [ "とうせん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) being elected/winning the prize" },
		{ "question": "形", "answers": [ "かたち" ], "comment": "(n) form/shape/figure/type" },
		{ "question": "形勢", "answers": [ "けいせい" ], "comment": "(n) condition/situation/prospects" },
		{ "question": "形容動詞", "answers": [ "けいようどうし" ], "comment": "(n) adjectival noun/quasi-adjective" },
		{ "question": "形容詞", "answers": [ "けいようし" ], "comment": "(n) 'true' adjective" },
		{ "question": "形式", "answers": [ "けいしき" ], "comment": "(n) form/formality/format/math expression" },
		{ "question": "形態", "answers": [ "けいたい" ], "comment": "(n) form/shape/figure" },
		{ "question": "形成", "answers": [ "けいせい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) formation" },
		{ "question": "彫る", "answers": [ "ほる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to carve/to engrave/to sculpture/to chisel" },
		{ "question": "彫刻", "answers": [ "ちょうこく" ], "comment": "(n) carving/engraving/sculpture" },
		{ "question": "影", "answers": [ "かげ" ], "comment": "(n) shade/shadow/other side" },
		{ "question": "影響", "answers": [ "えいきょう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) influence/effect" },
		{ "question": "役", "answers": [ "やく" ], "comment": "(n,n-suf) use/service/role/position" },
		{ "question": "役に立つ", "answers": [ "やくにたつ" ], "comment": "(v5t) to be helpful/to be useful" },
		{ "question": "役人", "answers": [ "やくにん" ], "comment": "(n) government official" },
		{ "question": "役割", "answers": [ "やくわり" ], "comment": "(n) part/assigning (allotment of) parts/role/duties" },
		{ "question": "役場", "answers": [ "やくば" ], "comment": "(n) town hall" },
		{ "question": "役所", "answers": [ "やくしょ" ], "comment": "(n) government office/public office" },
		{ "question": "役目", "answers": [ "やくめ" ], "comment": "(n) duty/business" },
		{ "question": "役者", "answers": [ "やくしゃ" ], "comment": "(n) actor/actress" },
		{ "question": "役職", "answers": [ "やくしょく" ], "comment": "(n) post/managerial position/official position" },
		{ "question": "彼", "answers": [ "かれ" ], "comment": "(n) he/boyfriend" },
		{ "question": "彼ら", "answers": [ "かれら" ], "comment": "(n) they (usually male)" },
		{ "question": "彼女", "answers": [ "かのじょ" ], "comment": "(n) she/girl friend/sweetheart" },
		{ "question": "彼等", "answers": [ "かれら" ], "comment": "(n) they (usually male)" },
		{ "question": "往復", "answers": [ "おうふく" ], "comment": "(n,vs) (col) round trip/coming and going/return ticket" },
		{ "question": "往診", "answers": [ "おうしん" ], "comment": "(n) doctor's visit/house call" },
		{ "question": "征服", "answers": [ "せいふく" ], "comment": "(n) conquest/subjugation/overcoming" },
		{ "question": "待ち合わせ", "answers": [ "まちあわせ" ], "comment": "(n) appointment" },
		{ "question": "待ち合わせる", "answers": [ "まちあわせる" ], "comment": "(v1) to rendezvous/to meet at a prearranged place and time" },
		{ "question": "待ち望む", "answers": [ "まちのぞむ" ], "comment": "(v5m) to look anxiously for/to wait eagerly for" },
		{ "question": "待ち遠しい", "answers": [ "まちどおしい" ], "comment": "(adj) looking forward to" },
		{ "question": "待つ", "answers": [ "まつ" ], "comment": "(v5t) to wait" },
		{ "question": "待合室", "answers": [ "まちあいしつ" ], "comment": "(n) waiting room" },
		{ "question": "待望", "answers": [ "たいぼう" ], "comment": "(n) expectant waiting" },
		{ "question": "待遇", "answers": [ "たいぐう" ], "comment": "(n) treatment/reception" },
		{ "question": "後", "answers": [ "あと","うしろ","ご","のち" ], "comment": "(adj-no,n) afterwards/since then/in the future" },
		{ "question": "後回し", "answers": [ "あとまわし" ], "comment": "(n) putting off/postponing" },
		{ "question": "後悔", "answers": [ "こうかい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) regret/repentance" },
		{ "question": "後者", "answers": [ "こうしゃ" ], "comment": "(n) the latter" },
		{ "question": "後輩", "answers": [ "こうはい" ], "comment": "(n) junior (at work or school)" },
		{ "question": "後退", "answers": [ "こうたい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) retreat/backspace (BS)" },
		{ "question": "徐々に", "answers": [ "じょじょに" ], "comment": "(adv) slowly/little by little/gradually/steadily/quietly" },
		{ "question": "徐行", "answers": [ "じょこう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) going slowly" },
		{ "question": "徒歩", "answers": [ "とほ" ], "comment": "(n) walking/going on foot" },
		{ "question": "従う", "answers": [ "したがう" ], "comment": "(v5u) to abide (by the rules)/to obey/to follow/to accompany" },
		{ "question": "従事", "answers": [ "じゅうじ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) engaging/pursuing/following" },
		{ "question": "従兄弟", "answers": [ "いとこ" ], "comment": "(n) (uk) cousin (male)" },
		{ "question": "従姉妹", "answers": [ "いとこ" ], "comment": "(n) (uk) cousin (female)" },
		{ "question": "従来", "answers": [ "じゅうらい" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n-t) up to now/so far/traditional" },
		{ "question": "従業員", "answers": [ "じゅうぎょういん" ], "comment": "(n) employee/worker" },
		{ "question": "得る", "answers": [ "うる","える" ], "comment": "(v1) to get/to gain/to win" },
		{ "question": "得意", "answers": [ "とくい" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) pride/triumph/prosperity/one's strong point/one's forte/one's specialty/customer/client" },
		{ "question": "得点", "answers": [ "とくてん" ], "comment": "(n) score/points made/marks obtained/runs" },
		{ "question": "御", "answers": [ "お" ], "comment": "(pref) honourable" },
		{ "question": "御世辞", "answers": [ "おせじ" ], "comment": "(n) flattery/compliment" },
		{ "question": "御中", "answers": [ "おんちゅう" ], "comment": "(n) and Company/Messrs." },
		{ "question": "御主人", "answers": [ "ごしゅじん" ], "comment": "(n) (hon) your husband/her husband" },
		{ "question": "御免", "answers": [ "ごめん" ], "comment": "(int,n) your pardon/declining (something)/dismissal/permission" },
		{ "question": "御手洗", "answers": [ "おてあらい" ], "comment": "(n) font of purifying water placed at the entrance of a shrine" },
		{ "question": "御無沙汰", "answers": [ "ごぶさた" ], "comment": "(n,vs) not writing or contacting for a while" },
		{ "question": "御覧", "answers": [ "ごらん" ], "comment": "(int,n) (hon) look/inspection/try" },
		{ "question": "御辞儀", "answers": [ "おじぎ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) bow" },
		{ "question": "御飯", "answers": [ "ごはん" ], "comment": "(n) rice (cooked)/meal" },
		{ "question": "御馳走", "answers": [ "ごちそう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) feast/treating (someone)" },
		{ "question": "復旧", "answers": [ "ふっきゅう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) restoration/restitution/rehabilitation" },
		{ "question": "復活", "answers": [ "ふっかつ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) revival (e.g. musical)/restoration" },
		{ "question": "復習", "answers": [ "ふくしゅう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) review/revision" },
		{ "question": "復興", "answers": [ "ふっこう" ], "comment": "(n) revival/renaissance/reconstruction" },
		{ "question": "循環", "answers": [ "じゅんかん" ], "comment": "(n) circulation/rotation/cycle" },
		{ "question": "微か", "answers": [ "かすか" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) faint/dim/weak/indistinct/hazy/poor/wretched" },
		{ "question": "微塵", "answers": [ "みじん" ], "comment": "(n) particle/atom" },
		{ "question": "微妙", "answers": [ "びみょう" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) delicate/subtle" },
		{ "question": "微笑", "answers": [ "びしょう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) smile" },
		{ "question": "微笑む", "answers": [ "ほほえむ" ], "comment": "(v5m) to smile" },
		{ "question": "微量", "answers": [ "びりょう" ], "comment": "(n) minuscule amount/extremely small quantity" },
		{ "question": "徴収", "answers": [ "ちょうしゅう" ], "comment": "(n) collection/levy" },
		{ "question": "徹する", "answers": [ "てっする" ], "comment": "(vs-s) to sink in/to penetrate/to devote oneself/to believe in/to go through/to do intently and exclusively" },
		{ "question": "徹夜", "answers": [ "てつや" ], "comment": "(n) all night/all night vigil/sleepless night" },
		{ "question": "徹底", "answers": [ "てってい" ], "comment": "(n) thoroughness/completeness" },
		{ "question": "心", "answers": [ "こころ" ], "comment": "(n) core/heart/wick/marrow" },
		{ "question": "心中", "answers": [ "しんじゅう" ], "comment": "(n) in one's heart/true motives/mind" },
		{ "question": "心地", "answers": [ "ここち" ], "comment": "(n) feeling/sensation/mood" },
		{ "question": "心強い", "answers": [ "こころづよい" ], "comment": "(adj) heartening/reassuring" },
		{ "question": "心当たり", "answers": [ "こころあたり" ], "comment": "(n) having some knowledge of/happening to know" },
		{ "question": "心得", "answers": [ "こころえ" ], "comment": "(n) knowledge/information" },
		{ "question": "心得る", "answers": [ "こころえる" ], "comment": "(v1) to be informed/to have thorough knowledge" },
		{ "question": "心情", "answers": [ "しんじょう" ], "comment": "(n) mentality" },
		{ "question": "心掛け", "answers": [ "こころがけ" ], "comment": "(n) readiness/intention/aim" },
		{ "question": "心掛ける", "answers": [ "こころがける" ], "comment": "(v1) to bear in mind/to aim to do" },
		{ "question": "心理", "answers": [ "しんり" ], "comment": "(n) mentality" },
		{ "question": "心細い", "answers": [ "こころぼそい" ], "comment": "(adj) helpless/forlorn/hopeless/unpromising/lonely/discouraging/disheartening" },
		{ "question": "心臓", "answers": [ "しんぞう" ], "comment": "(n) heart" },
		{ "question": "心身", "answers": [ "しんしん" ], "comment": "(n) mind and body" },
		{ "question": "心配", "answers": [ "しんぱい" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n,vs) worry/concern/anxiety/care" },
		{ "question": "必ず", "answers": [ "かならず" ], "comment": "(adv) necessarily/certainly/without fail/positively/invariably" },
		{ "question": "必ずしも", "answers": [ "かならずしも" ], "comment": "(adv) (not) always/(not) necessarily/(not) all/(not) entirely" },
		{ "question": "必修", "answers": [ "ひっしゅう" ], "comment": "(n) required (subject)" },
		{ "question": "必死", "answers": [ "ひっし" ], "comment": "(adj-na,adj-no,n) inevitable death/desperation/frantic/inevitable result" },
		{ "question": "必然", "answers": [ "ひつぜん" ], "comment": "(n) inevitable/necessary" },
		{ "question": "必要", "answers": [ "ひつよう" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) necessary/essential/indispensable" },
		{ "question": "必需品", "answers": [ "ひつじゅひん" ], "comment": "(n) necessities/necessary article/requisite/essential" },
		{ "question": "志", "answers": [ "こころざし" ], "comment": "(n) will/intention/motive" },
		{ "question": "志す", "answers": [ "こころざす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to plan/to intend/to aspire to/to set aims (sights on)" },
		{ "question": "志向", "answers": [ "しこう" ], "comment": "(n) intention/aim" },
		{ "question": "志望", "answers": [ "しぼう" ], "comment": "(n) wish/desire/ambition" },
		{ "question": "忘れる", "answers": [ "わすれる" ], "comment": "(v1) to forget/to leave carelessly/to be forgetful of/to forget about/to forget (an article)" },
		{ "question": "忘れ物", "answers": [ "わすれもの" ], "comment": "(n) lost article/something forgotten" },
		{ "question": "忙しい", "answers": [ "いそがしい" ], "comment": "(adj) busy/irritated" },
		{ "question": "応じる", "answers": [ "おうじる" ], "comment": "(v1) to respond/to satisfy/to accept/to comply with/to apply for" },
		{ "question": "応ずる", "answers": [ "おうずる" ], "comment": "(v5z) to answer/to respond/to meet/to satisfy/to accept" },
		{ "question": "応募", "answers": [ "おうぼ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) subscription/application" },
		{ "question": "応対", "answers": [ "おうたい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) receiving/dealing with" },
		{ "question": "応急", "answers": [ "おうきゅう" ], "comment": "(n) emergency" },
		{ "question": "応接", "answers": [ "おうせつ" ], "comment": "(n) reception" },
		{ "question": "応接間", "answers": [ "おうせつま" ], "comment": "(n) reception room" },
		{ "question": "応援", "answers": [ "おうえん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) aid/assistance/help/reinforcement/rooting/barracking/support/cheering" },
		{ "question": "応用", "answers": [ "おうよう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) application/put to practical use" },
		{ "question": "忠告", "answers": [ "ちゅうこく" ], "comment": "(n,vs) advice/warning" },
		{ "question": "快い", "answers": [ "こころよい" ], "comment": "(adj) pleasant/agreeable" },
		{ "question": "快晴", "answers": [ "かいせい" ], "comment": "(n) good weather" },
		{ "question": "快適", "answers": [ "かいてき" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) pleasant/agreeable/comfortable" },
		{ "question": "念", "answers": [ "ねん" ], "comment": "(n) sense/idea/thought/feeling/desire/concern/attention/care" },
		{ "question": "念願", "answers": [ "ねんがん" ], "comment": "(n) one's heart's desire/earnest petition" },
		{ "question": "怒り", "answers": [ "いかり" ], "comment": "(n) anger/hatred" },
		{ "question": "怒る", "answers": [ "おこる","いかる" ], "comment": "(v5r) (1) to get angry/to get mad/(2) to be angry" },
		{ "question": "怖い", "answers": [ "こわい" ], "comment": "(adj) scary/frightening/eerie/dreadful" },
		{ "question": "思い付き", "answers": [ "おもいつき" ], "comment": "(n) plan/idea/suggestion" },
		{ "question": "思い付く", "answers": [ "おもいつく" ], "comment": "(v5k) to think of/to hit upon/to come into one's mind/to be struck with an idea" },
		{ "question": "思い出", "answers": [ "おもいで" ], "comment": "(n) memories/recollections/reminiscence" },
		{ "question": "思い出す", "answers": [ "おもいだす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to recall/to remember" },
		{ "question": "思い切り", "answers": [ "おもいきり" ], "comment": "(adv,n) with all one's strength (heart)/resignation/resolution" },
		{ "question": "思い掛けない", "answers": [ "おもいがけない" ], "comment": "(adj) unexpected/casual" },
		{ "question": "思い込む", "answers": [ "おもいこむ" ], "comment": "(v5m) to be under impression that/to be convinced that/to imagine that/to set one's heart on/to be bent on" },
		{ "question": "思う", "answers": [ "おもう" ], "comment": "(v5u) to think/to feel" },
		{ "question": "思わず", "answers": [ "おもわず" ], "comment": "(adv) unintentional/spontaneous" },
		{ "question": "思想", "answers": [ "しそう" ], "comment": "(n) thought/idea" },
		{ "question": "思考", "answers": [ "しこう" ], "comment": "(n) thought" },
		{ "question": "怠ける", "answers": [ "なまける" ], "comment": "(v1) to be idle/to neglect" },
		{ "question": "怠る", "answers": [ "おこたる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to neglect/to be off guard/to be feeling better" },
		{ "question": "怠慢", "answers": [ "たいまん" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) negligence/procrastination/carelessness" },
		{ "question": "急", "answers": [ "きゅう" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) (1) urgent/sudden/(2) steep" },
		{ "question": "急かす", "answers": [ "せかす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to hurry/to urge on" },
		{ "question": "急ぐ", "answers": [ "いそぐ" ], "comment": "(v5g) to hurry/to rush" },
		{ "question": "急激", "answers": [ "きゅうげき" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) sudden/precipitous/radical" },
		{ "question": "急行", "answers": [ "きゅうこう" ], "comment": "(n) express (e.g. train that bypasses many stations)" },
		{ "question": "急速", "answers": [ "きゅうそく" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) rapid (e.g. progress)" },
		{ "question": "性", "answers": [ "せい" ], "comment": "(n,n-suf) sex/gender" },
		{ "question": "性別", "answers": [ "せいべつ" ], "comment": "(n) distinction by sex/sex/gender" },
		{ "question": "性格", "answers": [ "せいかく" ], "comment": "(n) character/personality" },
		{ "question": "性能", "answers": [ "せいのう" ], "comment": "(n) ability/efficiency" },
		{ "question": "性質", "answers": [ "せいしつ" ], "comment": "(n) nature/property/disposition" },
		{ "question": "怪しい", "answers": [ "あやしい" ], "comment": "(adj) suspicious/dubious/doubtful" },
		{ "question": "怪我", "answers": [ "けが" ], "comment": "(n,vs) injury (to animate object)/hurt" },
		{ "question": "怪獣", "answers": [ "かいじゅう" ], "comment": "(n) monster" },
		{ "question": "怯える", "answers": [ "おびえる" ], "comment": "(v1) to become frightened/to have a nightmare" },
		{ "question": "恋", "answers": [ "こい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) love/tender passion" },
		{ "question": "恋しい", "answers": [ "こいしい" ], "comment": "(adj) (1) dear/beloved/darling/(2) yearned for" },
		{ "question": "恋する", "answers": [ "こいする" ], "comment": "(vs-s) to fall in love with/to love" },
		{ "question": "恋人", "answers": [ "こいびと" ], "comment": "(n) lover/sweetheart" },
		{ "question": "恋愛", "answers": [ "れんあい" ], "comment": "(n) love/love-making/passion/emotion/affections" },
		{ "question": "恐れ", "answers": [ "おそれ" ], "comment": "(n) fear/horror" },
		{ "question": "恐れる", "answers": [ "おそれる" ], "comment": "(v1) to fear/to be afraid of" },
		{ "question": "恐れ入る", "answers": [ "おそれいる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to be filled with awe/to feel small/to be amazed/to be surprised/to be disconcerted/to be sorry/to be grateful/to be defeated/to confess guilt" },
		{ "question": "恐ろしい", "answers": [ "おそろしい" ], "comment": "(adj) terrible/dreadful" },
		{ "question": "恐怖", "answers": [ "きょうふ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) be afraid/dread/dismay/terror" },
		{ "question": "恐縮", "answers": [ "きょうしゅく" ], "comment": "(exp,n) shame/very kind of you/sorry to trouble" },
		{ "question": "恥", "answers": [ "はじ" ], "comment": "(n) shame/embarrassment" },
		{ "question": "恥じらう", "answers": [ "はじらう" ], "comment": "(v5u) to feel shy/to be bashful/to blush" },
		{ "question": "恥じる", "answers": [ "はじる" ], "comment": "(v1) to feel ashamed" },
		{ "question": "恥ずかしい", "answers": [ "はずかしい" ], "comment": "(adj) shy/ashamed/embarrassed" },
		{ "question": "恨み", "answers": [ "うらみ" ], "comment": "(n) resentment" },
		{ "question": "恨む", "answers": [ "うらむ" ], "comment": "(v5m) to curse/to feel bitter" },
		{ "question": "恩", "answers": [ "おん" ], "comment": "(n) favour/obligation/debt of gratitude" },
		{ "question": "恩恵", "answers": [ "おんけい" ], "comment": "(n) grace/favor/blessing/benefit" },
		{ "question": "息", "answers": [ "いき" ], "comment": "(n) breath/tone" },
		{ "question": "息子", "answers": [ "むすこ" ], "comment": "(n) (hum) son" },
		{ "question": "恵まれる", "answers": [ "めぐまれる" ], "comment": "(v1) to be blessed with/to be rich in" },
		{ "question": "恵み", "answers": [ "めぐみ" ], "comment": "(n) blessing" },
		{ "question": "恵む", "answers": [ "めぐむ" ], "comment": "(v5m) to bless/to show mercy to" },
		{ "question": "悔しい", "answers": [ "くやしい" ], "comment": "(adj) regrettable/mortifying/vexing" },
		{ "question": "悔やむ", "answers": [ "くやむ" ], "comment": "(v5m) to mourn" },
		{ "question": "悟る", "answers": [ "さとる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to attain enlightenment/to perceive/to understand/to discern" },
		{ "question": "悠々", "answers": [ "ゆうゆう" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) quiet/calm/leisurely" },
		{ "question": "患者", "answers": [ "かんじゃ" ], "comment": "(n) a patient" },
		{ "question": "悩ましい", "answers": [ "なやましい" ], "comment": "(adj) seductive/melancholy/languid" },
		{ "question": "悩ます", "answers": [ "なやます" ], "comment": "(v5s) to afflict/to torment/to harass/to molest" },
		{ "question": "悩み", "answers": [ "なやみ" ], "comment": "(n) trouble(s)/worry/distress/anguish/agony/problem" },
		{ "question": "悩む", "answers": [ "なやむ" ], "comment": "(v5m) to be worried/to be troubled" },
		{ "question": "悪", "answers": [ "あく" ], "comment": "(n) bad thing/bad person" },
		{ "question": "悪い", "answers": [ "わるい" ], "comment": "(adj) bad/inferior" },
		{ "question": "悪化", "answers": [ "あっか" ], "comment": "(n,vs) (suffer) deterioration/growing worse/aggravation/degeneration/corruption" },
		{ "question": "悪口", "answers": [ "わるくち" ], "comment": "(n) abuse/insult/slander/evil speaking" },
		{ "question": "悪者", "answers": [ "わるもの" ], "comment": "(n) bad fellow/rascal/ruffian/scoundrel" },
		{ "question": "悪魔", "answers": [ "あくま" ], "comment": "(n) devil/demon/fiend/Satan/evil spirit" },
		{ "question": "悲しい", "answers": [ "かなしい" ], "comment": "(adj) sad/sorrowful" },
		{ "question": "悲しむ", "answers": [ "かなしむ" ], "comment": "(v5m) to be sad/to mourn for/to regret" },
		{ "question": "悲劇", "answers": [ "ひげき" ], "comment": "(n) tragedy" },
		{ "question": "悲惨", "answers": [ "ひさん" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) (1) tragedy/disaster/(2) misery/wretched/pitiful" },
		{ "question": "悲観", "answers": [ "ひかん" ], "comment": "(n) pessimism/disappointment" },
		{ "question": "悲鳴", "answers": [ "ひめい" ], "comment": "(n) shriek/scream" },
		{ "question": "情", "answers": [ "じょう" ], "comment": "(n) feelings/emotion/passion" },
		{ "question": "情け", "answers": [ "なさけ" ], "comment": "(n) sympathy/compassion" },
		{ "question": "情勢", "answers": [ "じょうせい" ], "comment": "(n) state of things/condition/situation" },
		{ "question": "情報", "answers": [ "じょうほう" ], "comment": "(n) information/(military) intelligence" },
		{ "question": "情深い", "answers": [ "なさけぶかい" ], "comment": "(adj) tender-hearted/compassionate" },
		{ "question": "情無い", "answers": [ "なさけない" ], "comment": "(adj) miserable/pitiable/shameful/deplorable" },
		{ "question": "情熱", "answers": [ "じょうねつ" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) passion/enthusiasm/zeal" },
		{ "question": "情緒", "answers": [ "じょうしょ","じょうちょ" ], "comment": "(n) emotion/feeling" },
		{ "question": "惑星", "answers": [ "わくせい" ], "comment": "(n) planet" },
		{ "question": "惚ける", "answers": [ "ぼける" ], "comment": "(v1) to grow senile/to fade" },
		{ "question": "惜しい", "answers": [ "おしい" ], "comment": "(adj) regrettable/disappointing/precious" },
		{ "question": "惜しむ", "answers": [ "おしむ" ], "comment": "(v5m) to be frugal/to value/to regret" },
		{ "question": "想像", "answers": [ "そうぞう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) imagination/guess" },
		{ "question": "愉快", "answers": [ "ゆかい" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) pleasant/happy" },
		{ "question": "意向", "answers": [ "いこう" ], "comment": "(n) intention/idea/inclination" },
		{ "question": "意味", "answers": [ "いみ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) meaning/significance" },
		{ "question": "意図", "answers": [ "いと" ], "comment": "(n) intention/aim/design" },
		{ "question": "意地", "answers": [ "いじ" ], "comment": "(n) disposition/spirit/willpower/obstinacy/backbone/appetite" },
		{ "question": "意地悪", "answers": [ "いじわる" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) malicious/ill-tempered/unkind" },
		{ "question": "意外", "answers": [ "いがい" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) unexpected/surprising" },
		{ "question": "意志", "answers": [ "いし" ], "comment": "(n) will/volition" },
		{ "question": "意思", "answers": [ "いし" ], "comment": "(n) intention/purpose" },
		{ "question": "意欲", "answers": [ "いよく" ], "comment": "(n) will/desire/ambition" },
		{ "question": "意気込む", "answers": [ "いきごむ" ], "comment": "(v5m) to be enthusiastic about" },
		{ "question": "意義", "answers": [ "いぎ" ], "comment": "(n) meaning/significance" },
		{ "question": "意見", "answers": [ "いけん" ], "comment": "(n) opinion/view" },
		{ "question": "意識", "answers": [ "いしき" ], "comment": "(n,vs) consciousness/senses" },
		{ "question": "愚か", "answers": [ "おろか" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) foolish/stupid" },
		{ "question": "愚痴", "answers": [ "ぐち" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) idle complaint/grumble" },
		{ "question": "愛", "answers": [ "あい" ], "comment": "(n,n-suf,vs) love" },
		{ "question": "愛する", "answers": [ "あいする" ], "comment": "(vs-s) to love" },
		{ "question": "愛情", "answers": [ "あいじょう" ], "comment": "(n) love/affection" },
		{ "question": "愛想", "answers": [ "あいそう" ], "comment": "(n) civility/courtesy/compliments/sociability/graces" },
		{ "question": "感じ", "answers": [ "かんじ" ], "comment": "(n) feeling/sense/impression" },
		{ "question": "感じる", "answers": [ "かんじる" ], "comment": "(v1) to feel/to sense/to experience" },
		{ "question": "感ずる", "answers": [ "かんずる" ], "comment": "(v5z) to feel/to sense" },
		{ "question": "感動", "answers": [ "かんどう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) being deeply moved emotionally/excitement/impression/deep emotion" },
		{ "question": "感度", "answers": [ "かんど" ], "comment": "(n) sensitivity/severity (quake)" },
		{ "question": "感心", "answers": [ "かんしん" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n,vs) admiration/Well done!" },
		{ "question": "感情", "answers": [ "かんじょう" ], "comment": "(n) emotion(s)/feeling(s)/sentiment" },
		{ "question": "感想", "answers": [ "かんそう" ], "comment": "(n) impressions/thoughts" },
		{ "question": "感染", "answers": [ "かんせん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) infection/contagion" },
		{ "question": "感激", "answers": [ "かんげき" ], "comment": "(n) deep emotion/impression/inspiration" },
		{ "question": "感無量", "answers": [ "かんむりょう" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) deep feeling/inexpressible feeling/filled with emotion" },
		{ "question": "感覚", "answers": [ "かんかく" ], "comment": "(n) sense/sensation" },
		{ "question": "感触", "answers": [ "かんしょく" ], "comment": "(n) sense of touch/feeling/sensation" },
		{ "question": "感謝", "answers": [ "かんしゃ" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n,vs) thanks/gratitude" },
		{ "question": "態勢", "answers": [ "たいせい" ], "comment": "(n) attitude/conditions/preparations" },
		{ "question": "態度", "answers": [ "たいど" ], "comment": "(n) attitude/manner" },
		{ "question": "慎重", "answers": [ "しんちょう" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) discretion/prudence" },
		{ "question": "慕う", "answers": [ "したう" ], "comment": "(v5u) to yearn for/to miss/to adore/to love dearly" },
		{ "question": "慣らす", "answers": [ "ならす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to accustom" },
		{ "question": "慣れ", "answers": [ "なれ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) practice/experience" },
		{ "question": "慣れる", "answers": [ "なれる" ], "comment": "(v1) to grow accustomed to" },
		{ "question": "慣例", "answers": [ "かんれい" ], "comment": "(adj-no,n) custom/precedent/of convention" },
		{ "question": "慣習", "answers": [ "かんしゅう" ], "comment": "(n) usual (historical) custom" },
		{ "question": "慣行", "answers": [ "かんこう" ], "comment": "(adj-no,n) customary practice/habit/traditional event" },
		{ "question": "慰める", "answers": [ "なぐさめる" ], "comment": "(v1) to comfort/to console" },
		{ "question": "慶び", "answers": [ "よろこび" ], "comment": "(oK) (n) (a) joy/(a) delight/rapture/pleasure/gratification/rejoicing/congratulations/felicitations" },
		{ "question": "憂鬱", "answers": [ "ゆううつ" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) depression/melancholy/dejection/gloom" },
		{ "question": "憎い", "answers": [ "にくい" ], "comment": "(adj) hateful/abominable/poor-looking/detestable" },
		{ "question": "憎しみ", "answers": [ "にくしみ" ], "comment": "(n) hatred" },
		{ "question": "憎む", "answers": [ "にくむ" ], "comment": "(v5m) to hate/to detest" },
		{ "question": "憎らしい", "answers": [ "にくらしい" ], "comment": "(adj) odious/hateful" },
		{ "question": "憤慨", "answers": [ "ふんがい" ], "comment": "(n) indignation/resentment" },
		{ "question": "憧れ", "answers": [ "あこがれ" ], "comment": "(n) yearning/longing/aspiration" },
		{ "question": "憧れる", "answers": [ "あこがれる" ], "comment": "(v1) to long for/to yearn after/to admire/to be attracted by" },
		{ "question": "憲法", "answers": [ "けんぽう" ], "comment": "(n) constitution" },
		{ "question": "懐かしい", "answers": [ "なつかしい" ], "comment": "(adj) dear/desired/missed" },
		{ "question": "懐く", "answers": [ "なつく" ], "comment": "(v5k) to become emotionally attached" },
		{ "question": "懲りる", "answers": [ "こりる" ], "comment": "(v1) to learn by experience/to be disgusted with" },
		{ "question": "懸命", "answers": [ "けんめい" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) eagerness/earnestness/risking one's life" },
		{ "question": "懸賞", "answers": [ "けんしょう" ], "comment": "(n) offering prizes/winning/reward" },
		{ "question": "成り立つ", "answers": [ "なりたつ" ], "comment": "(v5t) (1) to consist of/(2) to be practical (logical, feasible, viable)/to be concluded/to hold true" },
		{ "question": "成る", "answers": [ "なる" ], "comment": "(v5r) (uk) to become" },
		{ "question": "成人", "answers": [ "せいじん" ], "comment": "(n) adult" },
		{ "question": "成分", "answers": [ "せいぶん" ], "comment": "(n) ingredient/component/composition" },
		{ "question": "成功", "answers": [ "せいこう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) success/hit" },
		{ "question": "成年", "answers": [ "せいねん" ], "comment": "(n) majority/adult age" },
		{ "question": "成果", "answers": [ "せいか" ], "comment": "(n) results/fruits" },
		{ "question": "成熟", "answers": [ "せいじゅく" ], "comment": "(n) maturity/ripeness" },
		{ "question": "成程", "answers": [ "なるほど" ], "comment": "(adv,exp) (uk) I see/That's right!/indeed" },
		{ "question": "成立", "answers": [ "せいりつ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) coming into existence/arrangements/establishment/completion" },
		{ "question": "成績", "answers": [ "せいせき" ], "comment": "(n) results/record" },
		{ "question": "成育", "answers": [ "せいいく" ], "comment": "(n) growth/raising" },
		{ "question": "成長", "answers": [ "せいちょう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) growth/grow to adulthood" },
		{ "question": "我", "answers": [ "われ" ], "comment": "(n) me/oneself/self/ego" },
		{ "question": "我々", "answers": [ "われわれ" ], "comment": "(n) we" },
		{ "question": "我慢", "answers": [ "がまん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) patience/endurance/perseverance/tolerance/self-control/self-denial" },
		{ "question": "或る", "answers": [ "ある" ], "comment": "(adj-pn) a certain.../some..." },
		{ "question": "戦い", "answers": [ "たたかい" ], "comment": "(n) battle/fight/struggle/conflict" },
		{ "question": "戦う", "answers": [ "たたかう" ], "comment": "(v5u) to fight/to battle/to combat/to struggle against/to wage war/to engage in contest" },
		{ "question": "戦争", "answers": [ "せんそう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) war" },
		{ "question": "戦力", "answers": [ "せんりょく" ], "comment": "(n) war potential" },
		{ "question": "戦災", "answers": [ "せんさい" ], "comment": "(n) war damage" },
		{ "question": "戦術", "answers": [ "せんじゅつ" ], "comment": "(n) tactics" },
		{ "question": "戦闘", "answers": [ "せんとう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) battle/fight/combat" },
		{ "question": "戯曲", "answers": [ "ぎきょく" ], "comment": "(n) play/drama" },
		{ "question": "戸", "answers": [ "と" ], "comment": "(n) door (Japanese style)" },
		{ "question": "戸棚", "answers": [ "とだな" ], "comment": "(n) cupboard/locker/closet/wardrobe" },
		{ "question": "戸籍", "answers": [ "こせき" ], "comment": "(n) census/family register" },
		{ "question": "戸締り", "answers": [ "とじまり" ], "comment": "(n) closing up/fastening the doors" },
		{ "question": "戻す", "answers": [ "もどす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to restore/to put back/to return" },
		{ "question": "戻る", "answers": [ "もどる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to turn back/to return" },
		{ "question": "所", "answers": [ "ところ" ], "comment": "(n) place" },
		{ "question": "所々", "answers": [ "ところどころ" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n-t) here and there/some parts (of something)" },
		{ "question": "所在", "answers": [ "しょざい" ], "comment": "(n) whereabouts" },
		{ "question": "所定", "answers": [ "しょてい" ], "comment": "(n) fixed/prescribed" },
		{ "question": "所属", "answers": [ "しょぞく" ], "comment": "(n) attached to/belong to" },
		{ "question": "所得", "answers": [ "しょとく" ], "comment": "(n) income/earnings" },
		{ "question": "所持", "answers": [ "しょじ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) possession/owning" },
		{ "question": "所有", "answers": [ "しょゆう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) one's possessions/ownership" },
		{ "question": "所為", "answers": [ "せい" ], "comment": "(n) cause/reason/fault" },
		{ "question": "扇ぐ", "answers": [ "あおぐ" ], "comment": "(v5g) to fan/to flap" },
		{ "question": "扇子", "answers": [ "せんす" ], "comment": "(n) folding fan" },
		{ "question": "扇風機", "answers": [ "せんぷうき" ], "comment": "(n) electric fan" },
		{ "question": "扉", "answers": [ "とびら" ], "comment": "(n) door/opening" },
		{ "question": "手", "answers": [ "て" ], "comment": "(n) hand" },
		{ "question": "手伝い", "answers": [ "てつだい" ], "comment": "(n) help/helper/assistant" },
		{ "question": "手伝う", "answers": [ "てつだう" ], "comment": "(v5u) to help/to assist/to take part in" },
		{ "question": "手元", "answers": [ "てもと" ], "comment": "(n) (1) (money) on hand or at home/one's purse/(2) usual skill" },
		{ "question": "手入れ", "answers": [ "ていれ" ], "comment": "(n) repairs/maintenance" },
		{ "question": "手分け", "answers": [ "てわけ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) division of labour" },
		{ "question": "手前", "answers": [ "てまえ" ], "comment": "(n) before/this side/we/you" },
		{ "question": "手品", "answers": [ "てじな" ], "comment": "(n) sleight of hand/conjuring trick/magic/juggling" },
		{ "question": "手回し", "answers": [ "てまわし" ], "comment": "(n) preparations/arrangements" },
		{ "question": "手帳", "answers": [ "てちょう" ], "comment": "(n) notebook" },
		{ "question": "手引", "answers": [ "てびき" ], "comment": "(n) guidance/guide/introduction" },
		{ "question": "手当", "answers": [ "てあて" ], "comment": "(n) allowance/compensation/treatment/medical care" },
		{ "question": "手拭い", "answers": [ "てぬぐい" ], "comment": "(n) (hand) towel" },
		{ "question": "手掛かり", "answers": [ "てがかり" ], "comment": "(n) contact/trail/scent/on hand/hand hold/clue/key" },
		{ "question": "手掛ける", "answers": [ "てがける" ], "comment": "(v1) to handle/to manage/to work with/to rear/to look after/to have experience with" },
		{ "question": "手数", "answers": [ "てかず","てすう" ], "comment": "(n) trouble/labor/handling" },
		{ "question": "手本", "answers": [ "てほん" ], "comment": "(n) model/pattern" },
		{ "question": "手段", "answers": [ "しゅだん" ], "comment": "(n) means/way/measure" },
		{ "question": "手法", "answers": [ "しゅほう" ], "comment": "(n) technique" },
		{ "question": "手洗い", "answers": [ "てあらい" ], "comment": "(n) restroom/lavatory/hand-washing" },
		{ "question": "手筈", "answers": [ "てはず" ], "comment": "(n) arrangement/plan/programme" },
		{ "question": "手紙", "answers": [ "てがみ" ], "comment": "(n) letter" },
		{ "question": "手続き", "answers": [ "てつづき" ], "comment": "(n,vs) procedure/(legal) process/formalities" },
		{ "question": "手芸", "answers": [ "しゅげい" ], "comment": "(n) handicrafts" },
		{ "question": "手術", "answers": [ "しゅじゅつ" ], "comment": "(n) surgical operation" },
		{ "question": "手袋", "answers": [ "てぶくろ" ], "comment": "(n) glove" },
		{ "question": "手軽", "answers": [ "てがる" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) easy/simple/informal/offhand/cheap" },
		{ "question": "手近", "answers": [ "てぢか" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) near/handy/familiar" },
		{ "question": "手遅れ", "answers": [ "ておくれ" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) (1) being (too) late/(2) belated treatment" },
		{ "question": "手配", "answers": [ "てはい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) arrangement/search (by police)" },
		{ "question": "手錠", "answers": [ "てじょう" ], "comment": "(n) handcuffs/manacles" },
		{ "question": "手間", "answers": [ "てま" ], "comment": "(n) time/labour" },
		{ "question": "手際", "answers": [ "てぎわ" ], "comment": "(n) performance/skill/tact" },
		{ "question": "手頃", "answers": [ "てごろ" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) moderate/handy" },
		{ "question": "手順", "answers": [ "てじゅん" ], "comment": "(n) process/procedure/protocol" },
		{ "question": "手首", "answers": [ "てくび" ], "comment": "(n) wrist" },
		{ "question": "才能", "answers": [ "さいのう" ], "comment": "(n) talent/ability" },
		{ "question": "打ち切る", "answers": [ "うちきる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to stop/to abort/to discontinue/to close" },
		{ "question": "打ち明ける", "answers": [ "うちあける" ], "comment": "(v1) to be frank/to speak one's mind/to open one's heart" },
		{ "question": "打ち消し", "answers": [ "うちけし" ], "comment": "(n) (gram) negation/denial/negative" },
		{ "question": "打ち消す", "answers": [ "うちけす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to deny/to negate/to contradict" },
		{ "question": "打ち込む", "answers": [ "うちこむ" ], "comment": "(v5m) to drive in (e.g. nail, stake)/to devote oneself to/to shoot into/to smash/to throw into/to cast into" },
		{ "question": "打つ", "answers": [ "うつ","ぶつ" ], "comment": "(v5t) to hit/to strike" },
		{ "question": "打合せ", "answers": [ "うちあわせ" ], "comment": "(n) business meeting/previous arrangement/appointment" },
		{ "question": "打撃", "answers": [ "だげき" ], "comment": "(n) (1) blow/shock/strike/damage/(2) batting (baseball)" },
		{ "question": "打開", "answers": [ "だかい" ], "comment": "(n) break in the deadlock" },
		{ "question": "払い戻す", "answers": [ "はらいもどす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to repay/to pay back" },
		{ "question": "払い込む", "answers": [ "はらいこむ" ], "comment": "(v5m) to deposit/to pay in" },
		{ "question": "払う", "answers": [ "はらう" ], "comment": "(v5u) (1) to pay/(2) to brush/to wipe" },
		{ "question": "扱い", "answers": [ "あつかい" ], "comment": "(n,n-suf,vs) treatment/service" },
		{ "question": "扱う", "answers": [ "あつかう" ], "comment": "(v5u) to handle/to deal with/to treat" },
		{ "question": "扶養", "answers": [ "ふよう" ], "comment": "(n) support/maintenance" },
		{ "question": "批判", "answers": [ "ひはん" ], "comment": "(n) criticism/judgement/comment" },
		{ "question": "批評", "answers": [ "ひひょう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) criticism/review/commentary" },
		{ "question": "承る", "answers": [ "うけたまわる" ], "comment": "(v5r) (hum) to hear/to be told/to know" },
		{ "question": "承知", "answers": [ "しょうち" ], "comment": "(n,vs) consent/acceptance/assent/admitting/acknowledgment/compliance/agreement/awareness" },
		{ "question": "承認", "answers": [ "しょうにん" ], "comment": "(n) recognition/acknowledgement/approval/consent/agreement" },
		{ "question": "承諾", "answers": [ "しょうだく" ], "comment": "(n,vs) consent/acquiescence/agreement" },
		{ "question": "技", "answers": [ "わざ" ], "comment": "(n) art/technique" },
		{ "question": "技師", "answers": [ "ぎし" ], "comment": "(n) engineer/technician" },
		{ "question": "技能", "answers": [ "ぎのう" ], "comment": "(n) technical skill/ability/capacity" },
		{ "question": "技術", "answers": [ "ぎじゅつ" ], "comment": "(n) art/technique/technology/skill" },
		{ "question": "把握", "answers": [ "はあく" ], "comment": "(n,vs) grasp/catch/understanding" },
		{ "question": "抑制", "answers": [ "よくせい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) control/restraint/suppression" },
		{ "question": "抑圧", "answers": [ "よくあつ" ], "comment": "(n) check/restraint/oppression/suppression" },
		{ "question": "投げる", "answers": [ "なげる" ], "comment": "(v1) to throw/to cast away" },
		{ "question": "投げ出す", "answers": [ "なげだす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to throw down/to abandon/to sacrifice/to throw out" },
		{ "question": "投入", "answers": [ "とうにゅう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) throw/investment/making (an electrical circuit)" },
		{ "question": "投書", "answers": [ "とうしょ" ], "comment": "(n) letter to the editor/letter from a reader/contribution" },
		{ "question": "投票", "answers": [ "とうひょう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) voting/poll" },
		{ "question": "投資", "answers": [ "とうし" ], "comment": "(n) investment" },
		{ "question": "抗争", "answers": [ "こうそう" ], "comment": "(n) dispute/resistance" },
		{ "question": "抗議", "answers": [ "こうぎ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) protest/objection" },
		{ "question": "折", "answers": [ "おり" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n-t) chance/suitable time" },
		{ "question": "折り返す", "answers": [ "おりかえす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to turn up/to fold back" },
		{ "question": "折る", "answers": [ "おる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to break/to fold/to pick flower" },
		{ "question": "折れる", "answers": [ "おれる" ], "comment": "(v1,vi,vt) to break/to be folded/to give in/to turn (a corner)" },
		{ "question": "折衷", "answers": [ "せっちゅう" ], "comment": "(n) compromise/cross/blending/eclecticism" },
		{ "question": "折角", "answers": [ "せっかく" ], "comment": "(adv,n) with trouble/at great pains/long-awaited" },
		{ "question": "抜かす", "answers": [ "ぬかす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to omit/to leave out" },
		{ "question": "抜く", "answers": [ "ぬく" ], "comment": "(v5k) to extract/to omit/to surpass/to draw out/to unplug" },
		{ "question": "抜ける", "answers": [ "ぬける" ], "comment": "(v1) to come out/to fall out/to be omitted/to be missing/to escape" },
		{ "question": "抜け出す", "answers": [ "ぬけだす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to slip out/to sneak away/to excel" },
		{ "question": "抱える", "answers": [ "かかえる" ], "comment": "(v1) to hold or carry under or in the arms" },
		{ "question": "抱く", "answers": [ "いだく","だく" ], "comment": "(v5k) (sl) to embrace/to hug/to harbour/to entertain/`to sleep with'" },
		{ "question": "抱っこ", "answers": [ "だっこ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) (child's) hug" },
		{ "question": "抵抗", "answers": [ "ていこう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) electrical resistance/resistance/opposition" },
		{ "question": "押える", "answers": [ "おさえる" ], "comment": "(v1) to stop/to restrain/to seize/to repress/to suppress/to press down" },
		{ "question": "押し入れ", "answers": [ "おしいれ" ], "comment": "(n) closet" },
		{ "question": "押し切る", "answers": [ "おしきる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to have one's own way" },
		{ "question": "押し寄せる", "answers": [ "おしよせる" ], "comment": "(v1) to push aside/to advance on" },
		{ "question": "押し込む", "answers": [ "おしこむ" ], "comment": "(v5m) to push into/to crowd into" },
		{ "question": "押す", "answers": [ "おす" ], "comment": "(v5s,vt) to push/to press/to stamp (i.e. a passport)" },
		{ "question": "抽象", "answers": [ "ちゅうしょう" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) abstract" },
		{ "question": "抽選", "answers": [ "ちゅうせん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) lottery/raffle/drawing (of lots)" },
		{ "question": "担う", "answers": [ "になう" ], "comment": "(v5u) to carry on shoulder/to bear (burden)/to shoulder (gun)" },
		{ "question": "担ぐ", "answers": [ "かつぐ" ], "comment": "(v5g) to shoulder/to carry on shoulder" },
		{ "question": "担当", "answers": [ "たんとう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) (in) charge" },
		{ "question": "担架", "answers": [ "たんか" ], "comment": "(n) stretcher/litter" },
		{ "question": "拍手", "answers": [ "はくしゅ" ], "comment": "(n) clapping hands/applause" },
		{ "question": "拒否", "answers": [ "きょひ" ], "comment": "(n) denial/veto/rejection/refusal" },
		{ "question": "拒絶", "answers": [ "きょぜつ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) refusal/rejection" },
		{ "question": "拘束", "answers": [ "こうそく" ], "comment": "(n,vs) restriction/restraint" },
		{ "question": "招き", "answers": [ "まねき" ], "comment": "(n) invitation" },
		{ "question": "招く", "answers": [ "まねく" ], "comment": "(v5k) to invite" },
		{ "question": "招待", "answers": [ "しょうたい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) invitation" },
		{ "question": "拝む", "answers": [ "おがむ" ], "comment": "(v5m) to worship/to beg/to make a supplication" },
		{ "question": "拝借", "answers": [ "はいしゃく" ], "comment": "(n,vs) (hum) (pol) borrowing" },
		{ "question": "拝啓", "answers": [ "はいけい" ], "comment": "(int,n) Dear (so and so)" },
		{ "question": "拝見", "answers": [ "はいけん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) (hum) (pol) seeing/look at" },
		{ "question": "拡充", "answers": [ "かくじゅう" ], "comment": "(n) expansion" },
		{ "question": "拡大", "answers": [ "かくだい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) magnification/enlargement" },
		{ "question": "拡張", "answers": [ "かくちょう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) expansion/extension/enlargement/escape (ESC)" },
		{ "question": "拡散", "answers": [ "かくさん" ], "comment": "(n) scattering/diffusion" },
		{ "question": "括弧", "answers": [ "かっこ" ], "comment": "(n) parenthesis/brackets" },
		{ "question": "拭く", "answers": [ "ふく" ], "comment": "(v5k) to wipe/to dry" },
		{ "question": "拾う", "answers": [ "ひろう" ], "comment": "(v5u) to pick up/to find/to gather" },
		{ "question": "持ち上げる", "answers": [ "もちあげる" ], "comment": "(v1) to raise/to lift up/to flatter" },
		{ "question": "持ち切り", "answers": [ "もちきり" ], "comment": "(n) hot topic/talk of the town" },
		{ "question": "持つ", "answers": [ "もつ" ], "comment": "(v5t) (1) to hold/to carry/(2) to possess" },
		{ "question": "持参", "answers": [ "じさん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) bringing/taking/carrying" },
		{ "question": "持続", "answers": [ "じぞく" ], "comment": "(n) continuation" },
		{ "question": "指", "answers": [ "ゆび" ], "comment": "(n) finger" },
		{ "question": "指す", "answers": [ "さす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to point/to put up umbrella/to play" },
		{ "question": "指令", "answers": [ "しれい" ], "comment": "(n) orders/instructions/directive" },
		{ "question": "指図", "answers": [ "さしず" ], "comment": "(n) instruction/mandate" },
		{ "question": "指定", "answers": [ "してい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) designation/specification/assignment/pointing at" },
		{ "question": "指導", "answers": [ "しどう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) leadership/guidance/coaching" },
		{ "question": "指差す", "answers": [ "ゆびさす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to point at" },
		{ "question": "指揮", "answers": [ "しき" ], "comment": "(n) command/direction" },
		{ "question": "指摘", "answers": [ "してき" ], "comment": "(n,vs) pointing out/identification" },
		{ "question": "指輪", "answers": [ "ゆびわ" ], "comment": "(n) (finger) ring" },
		{ "question": "挑む", "answers": [ "いどむ" ], "comment": "(v5m) to challenge/to contend for/to make love to" },
		{ "question": "挑戦", "answers": [ "ちょうせん" ], "comment": "(n) challenge/defiance" },
		{ "question": "挟まる", "answers": [ "はさまる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to get between/to be caught in" },
		{ "question": "挟む", "answers": [ "はさむ" ], "comment": "(v5m) to interpose/to hold between/to insert" },
		{ "question": "挨拶", "answers": [ "あいさつ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) greeting/salutation" },
		{ "question": "振り", "answers": [ "ふり" ], "comment": "(suf) style/manner" },
		{ "question": "振り仮名", "answers": [ "ふりがな" ], "comment": "furigana (hiragana over kanji)/pronunciation key" },
		{ "question": "振り出し", "answers": [ "ふりだし" ], "comment": "(n) outset/starting point/drawing or issuing (draft)" },
		{ "question": "振り向く", "answers": [ "ふりむく" ], "comment": "(v5k) to turn one's face/to turn around" },
		{ "question": "振り返る", "answers": [ "ふりかえる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to turn head/to look over one's shoulder/to turn around/to look back" },
		{ "question": "振る", "answers": [ "ふる" ], "comment": "(v5r,vt) (1) to wave/to shake/to swing/(2) to sprinkle/(3) to cast (actor)/to allocate (work)" },
		{ "question": "振動", "answers": [ "しんどう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) oscillation/vibration" },
		{ "question": "振興", "answers": [ "しんこう" ], "comment": "(n) promotion/encouragement" },
		{ "question": "振舞う", "answers": [ "ふるまう" ], "comment": "(v5u) to behave/to conduct oneself/to entertain (vt)" },
		{ "question": "挿す", "answers": [ "さす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to insert/to put in/to graft/to wear in belt" },
		{ "question": "捕える", "answers": [ "とらえる" ], "comment": "(v1) to seize/to grasp/to capture/to arrest" },
		{ "question": "捕まえる", "answers": [ "つかまえる" ], "comment": "(v1) to catch/to arrest/to seize" },
		{ "question": "捕まる", "answers": [ "つかまる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to be caught/to be arrested" },
		{ "question": "捕る", "answers": [ "とる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to take/to catch (fish)/to capture" },
		{ "question": "捕獲", "answers": [ "ほかく" ], "comment": "(n,vs) capture/seizure" },
		{ "question": "捕虜", "answers": [ "ほりょ" ], "comment": "(n) prisoner (of war)" },
		{ "question": "捕鯨", "answers": [ "ほげい" ], "comment": "(n) whaling/whale fishing" },
		{ "question": "捗る", "answers": [ "はかどる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to make progress/to move right ahead (with the work)/to advance" },
		{ "question": "捜す", "answers": [ "さがす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to search/to seek/to look for" },
		{ "question": "捜査", "answers": [ "そうさ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) search (esp. in criminal investigations)/investigation" },
		{ "question": "捜索", "answers": [ "そうさく" ], "comment": "(n) search (esp. for someone or something missing)/investigation" },
		{ "question": "捧げる", "answers": [ "ささげる" ], "comment": "(v1) to lift up/to give/to offer/to consecrate/to devote/to sacrifice/to dedicate" },
		{ "question": "捨てる", "answers": [ "すてる" ], "comment": "(v1) to throw away/to cast aside/to abandon/to resign" },
		{ "question": "捩る", "answers": [ "ねじる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to twist" },
		{ "question": "据える", "answers": [ "すえる" ], "comment": "(v1) to set (table)/to lay (foundation)/to place (gun)/to apply (moxa)" },
		{ "question": "据え付ける", "answers": [ "すえつける" ], "comment": "(v1) to install/to equip/to mount" },
		{ "question": "捲る", "answers": [ "めくる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to turn over/to turn pages of a book/to tear off/to strip off" },
		{ "question": "捻る", "answers": [ "ひねる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to turn (a switch) on or off/to twist/to puzzle over" },
		{ "question": "掃く", "answers": [ "はく" ], "comment": "(v5k) to sweep/to brush/to gather up" },
		{ "question": "掃除", "answers": [ "そうじ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) cleaning/sweeping" },
		{ "question": "授ける", "answers": [ "さずける" ], "comment": "(v1) to grant/to award/to teach" },
		{ "question": "授業", "answers": [ "じゅぎょう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) lesson/class work" },
		{ "question": "掌", "answers": [ "てのひら" ], "comment": "(n) the palm" },
		{ "question": "掏摸", "answers": [ "すり" ], "comment": "(n) pickpocket" },
		{ "question": "排水", "answers": [ "はいすい" ], "comment": "(n) drainage" },
		{ "question": "排除", "answers": [ "はいじょ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) exclusion/removal/rejection" },
		{ "question": "掘る", "answers": [ "ほる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to dig/to excavate" },
		{ "question": "掛かる", "answers": [ "かかる" ], "comment": "(v5r,vi) to take (e.g. time, money, etc)/to hang" },
		{ "question": "掛ける", "answers": [ "かける" ], "comment": "(aux-v,v1) (1) to wear/to put on/to hang/to begin to/to cover/to multiply/to turn on (a switch)/to play (a record)/to pour (water)/(2) to sit down/(3) to make a phone call" },
		{ "question": "掛け算", "answers": [ "かけざん" ], "comment": "(n) multiplication" },
		{ "question": "採る", "answers": [ "とる" ], "comment": "(v5r) (1) to adopt (measure, proposal)/(2) to pick (fruit)/(3) to assume (attitude)" },
		{ "question": "採択", "answers": [ "さいたく" ], "comment": "(n,vs) adoption/selection/choice" },
		{ "question": "採掘", "answers": [ "さいくつ" ], "comment": "(n) mining" },
		{ "question": "採決", "answers": [ "さいけつ" ], "comment": "(n) vote/roll call" },
		{ "question": "採点", "answers": [ "さいてん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) marking/grading/looking over" },
		{ "question": "採用", "answers": [ "さいよう" ], "comment": "(n) use/adopt" },
		{ "question": "採算", "answers": [ "さいさん" ], "comment": "(n) profit" },
		{ "question": "採集", "answers": [ "さいしゅう" ], "comment": "(n) collecting/gathering" },
		{ "question": "探す", "answers": [ "さがす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to search/to seek/to look for" },
		{ "question": "探る", "answers": [ "さぐる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to search/to look for/to sound out" },
		{ "question": "探検", "answers": [ "たんけん" ], "comment": "(n) exploration/expedition" },
		{ "question": "接ぐ", "answers": [ "つぐ" ], "comment": "(v5g) (1) to join/(2) to piece together/(3) to set (bones)/(4) to graft (trees)" },
		{ "question": "接する", "answers": [ "せっする" ], "comment": "(vs-s) to come in contact with/to connect/to attend/to receive" },
		{ "question": "接続", "answers": [ "せつぞく" ], "comment": "(n,vs) (1) connection/union/join/link/(2) changing trains" },
		{ "question": "接続詞", "answers": [ "せつぞくし" ], "comment": "(n) conjunction" },
		{ "question": "接触", "answers": [ "せっしょく" ], "comment": "(n,vs) touch/contact" },
		{ "question": "接近", "answers": [ "せっきん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) getting closer/drawing nearer/approaching" },
		{ "question": "控える", "answers": [ "ひかえる" ], "comment": "(v1) to draw in/to hold back/to make notes/to be temperate in" },
		{ "question": "控室", "answers": [ "ひかえしつ" ], "comment": "(n) waiting room" },
		{ "question": "控除", "answers": [ "こうじょ" ], "comment": "(n) subsidy/deduction" },
		{ "question": "推定", "answers": [ "すいてい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) presumption/assumption/estimation" },
		{ "question": "推測", "answers": [ "すいそく" ], "comment": "(n,vs) guess/conjecture" },
		{ "question": "推理", "answers": [ "すいり" ], "comment": "(n) reasoning/inference/mystery or detective genre (movie, novel, etc.)" },
		{ "question": "推薦", "answers": [ "すいせん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) recommendation" },
		{ "question": "推進", "answers": [ "すいしん" ], "comment": "(n) propulsion/driving force" },
		{ "question": "措置", "answers": [ "そち" ], "comment": "(n) measure/step" },
		{ "question": "掲げる", "answers": [ "かかげる" ], "comment": "(v1) (1) to publish/to print/to carry (an article)/(2) to put up/to hang out/to hoist/to fly (a sail)/to float (a flag)" },
		{ "question": "掲示", "answers": [ "けいじ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) notice/bulletin" },
		{ "question": "掲載", "answers": [ "けいさい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) appearance (e.g. article in paper)" },
		{ "question": "掴む", "answers": [ "つかむ" ], "comment": "(v5m) to seize/to catch/to grasp/to grip/to grab/to hold/to catch hold of/to lay one's hands on" },
		{ "question": "掻き回す", "answers": [ "かきまわす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to stir up/to churn/to ransack/to disturb" },
		{ "question": "掻く", "answers": [ "かく" ], "comment": "(v5k) (uk) to scratch/to perspire" },
		{ "question": "揃い", "answers": [ "そろい" ], "comment": "(n) set/suit/uniform" },
		{ "question": "揃う", "answers": [ "そろう" ], "comment": "(v5u) to become complete/to be equal/to be all present/to gather" },
		{ "question": "揃える", "answers": [ "そろえる" ], "comment": "(v1) to put things in order/to arrange/to make uniform/to get something ready" },
		{ "question": "揉む", "answers": [ "もむ" ], "comment": "(v5m) to rub/to crumple (up)/to wrinkle/to massage/to be troubled about/to worry over/to train/to coach" },
		{ "question": "描く", "answers": [ "えがく" ], "comment": "(v5k) to draw/to paint/to sketch/to depict/to describe" },
		{ "question": "描写", "answers": [ "びょうしゃ" ], "comment": "(n) depiction/description/portrayal" },
		{ "question": "提供", "answers": [ "ていきょう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) offer/tender/program sponsoring/furnishing" },
		{ "question": "提出", "answers": [ "ていしゅつ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) presentation/submission/filing" },
		{ "question": "提携", "answers": [ "ていけい" ], "comment": "(n) cooperation/tie-up/joint business/link-up" },
		{ "question": "提案", "answers": [ "ていあん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) proposal/proposition/suggestion" },
		{ "question": "提示", "answers": [ "ていじ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) presentation/exhibit/suggest/citation" },
		{ "question": "換える", "answers": [ "かえる" ], "comment": "(v1) to exchange/to interchange/to substitute/to replace" },
		{ "question": "換気", "answers": [ "かんき" ], "comment": "(n) ventilation" },
		{ "question": "換算", "answers": [ "かんさん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) conversion/change/exchange" },
		{ "question": "握る", "answers": [ "にぎる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to grasp/to seize/to mould sushi" },
		{ "question": "握手", "answers": [ "あくしゅ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) handshake" },
		{ "question": "援助", "answers": [ "えんじょ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) assistance/aid/support" },
		{ "question": "揺さぶる", "answers": [ "ゆさぶる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to shake/to jolt/to rock/to swing" },
		{ "question": "揺らぐ", "answers": [ "ゆらぐ" ], "comment": "(v5g) to swing/to sway/to shake/to tremble" },
		{ "question": "揺れる", "answers": [ "ゆれる" ], "comment": "(v1) to shake/to sway" },
		{ "question": "損", "answers": [ "そん" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n,n-suf,vs) loss/disadvantage" },
		{ "question": "損う", "answers": [ "そこなう" ], "comment": "(io) (suf,v5u) to harm/to hurt/to injure/to damage/to fail in doing" },
		{ "question": "損失", "answers": [ "そんしつ" ], "comment": "(n) loss" },
		{ "question": "損害", "answers": [ "そんがい" ], "comment": "(n) damage/injury/loss" },
		{ "question": "損得", "answers": [ "そんとく" ], "comment": "(n) loss and gain/advantage and disadvantage" },
		{ "question": "携わる", "answers": [ "たずさわる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to participate/to take part" },
		{ "question": "携帯", "answers": [ "けいたい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) (1) carrying something/(2) mobile telephone (abbr)" },
		{ "question": "摘む", "answers": [ "つむ" ], "comment": "(v5m) to pluck/to pick/to trim" },
		{ "question": "摩する", "answers": [ "さする" ], "comment": "(vs-s) (1) to rub/to scrub/(2) to draw near/to press" },
		{ "question": "摩擦", "answers": [ "まさつ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) friction/rubbing/rubdown/chafe" },
		{ "question": "撃つ", "answers": [ "うつ" ], "comment": "(v5t) to attack/to defeat/to destroy" },
		{ "question": "撒く", "answers": [ "まく" ], "comment": "(v5k) to scatter/to sprinkle/to sow" },
		{ "question": "撫でる", "answers": [ "なでる" ], "comment": "(v1) to brush gently/to stroke" },
		{ "question": "撮る", "answers": [ "とる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to take (a photo)/to make (a film)" },
		{ "question": "撮影", "answers": [ "さつえい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) photographing" },
		{ "question": "操る", "answers": [ "あやつる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to manipulate/to operate/to pull strings" },
		{ "question": "操作", "answers": [ "そうさ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) operation/management/processing" },
		{ "question": "操縦", "answers": [ "そうじゅう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) management/handling/control/manipulation" },
		{ "question": "擦る", "answers": [ "かする","こする","する" ], "comment": "(v5r) to rub/to chafe/to file/to frost (glass)/to strike (match)" },
		{ "question": "擦れる", "answers": [ "すれる" ], "comment": "(v1) to rub/to chafe/to wear/to become sophisticated" },
		{ "question": "支える", "answers": [ "ささえる" ], "comment": "(v1) to be blocked/to choke/to be obstructed/to feel a pressure on one's chest" },
		{ "question": "支出", "answers": [ "ししゅつ" ], "comment": "(n) expenditure/expenses" },
		{ "question": "支店", "answers": [ "してん" ], "comment": "(n) branch store (office)" },
		{ "question": "支度", "answers": [ "したく" ], "comment": "(n,vs) preparation" },
		{ "question": "支払", "answers": [ "しはらい" ], "comment": "(n) payment" },
		{ "question": "支払う", "answers": [ "しはらう" ], "comment": "(v5u) to pay" },
		{ "question": "支持", "answers": [ "しじ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) support/maintenance" },
		{ "question": "支給", "answers": [ "しきゅう" ], "comment": "(n) payment/allowance" },
		{ "question": "支配", "answers": [ "しはい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) rule/control/direction" },
		{ "question": "改まる", "answers": [ "あらたまる" ], "comment": "(v5r) (1) to be renewed/(2) to stand on ceremony/to be formal/(3) to take a turn for the worse" },
		{ "question": "改めて", "answers": [ "あらためて" ], "comment": "(adv) another time/again/over again/anew/formally" },
		{ "question": "改める", "answers": [ "あらためる" ], "comment": "(v1) to change/to alter/to reform/to revise" },
		{ "question": "改修", "answers": [ "かいしゅう" ], "comment": "(n) repair/improvement" },
		{ "question": "改善", "answers": [ "かいぜん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) betterment/improvement/incremental and continuous improvement" },
		{ "question": "改定", "answers": [ "かいてい" ], "comment": "(n) reform" },
		{ "question": "改悪", "answers": [ "かいあく" ], "comment": "(n) deterioration/changing for the worse" },
		{ "question": "改札", "answers": [ "かいさつ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) examination of tickets" },
		{ "question": "改正", "answers": [ "かいせい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) revision/amendment/alteration" },
		{ "question": "改良", "answers": [ "かいりょう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) improvement/reform" },
		{ "question": "改訂", "answers": [ "かいてい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) revision" },
		{ "question": "改造", "answers": [ "かいぞう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) (1) remodeling/(2) modding (comp)" },
		{ "question": "改革", "answers": [ "かいかく" ], "comment": "(n) reform/reformation/innovation" },
		{ "question": "攻め", "answers": [ "せめ" ], "comment": "(n) attack/offence" },
		{ "question": "攻める", "answers": [ "せめる" ], "comment": "(v1) to attack/to assault" },
		{ "question": "攻撃", "answers": [ "こうげき" ], "comment": "(n,vs) attack/strike/offensive/criticism/censure" },
		{ "question": "放す", "answers": [ "はなす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to separate/to set free" },
		{ "question": "放り出す", "answers": [ "ほうりだす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to throw out/to fire/to expel/to give up/to abandon/to neglect" },
		{ "question": "放り込む", "answers": [ "ほうりこむ" ], "comment": "(v5m) to throw into" },
		{ "question": "放る", "answers": [ "ほうる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to let go" },
		{ "question": "放れる", "answers": [ "はなれる" ], "comment": "(v1) to leave/to get free/to cut oneself off" },
		{ "question": "放出", "answers": [ "ほうしゅつ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) release/emit" },
		{ "question": "放射", "answers": [ "ほうしゃ" ], "comment": "(n) radiation/emission" },
		{ "question": "放射能", "answers": [ "ほうしゃのう" ], "comment": "(n) radioactivity" },
		{ "question": "放置", "answers": [ "ほうち" ], "comment": "(n,vs) leave as is/leave to chance/leave alone/neglect" },
		{ "question": "放送", "answers": [ "ほうそう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) broadcast/broadcasting" },
		{ "question": "政党", "answers": [ "せいとう" ], "comment": "(n) (member of) political party" },
		{ "question": "政府", "answers": [ "せいふ" ], "comment": "(n) government/administration" },
		{ "question": "政権", "answers": [ "せいけん" ], "comment": "(n) (political) administration/political power" },
		{ "question": "政治", "answers": [ "せいじ" ], "comment": "(n) politics/government" },
		{ "question": "政策", "answers": [ "せいさく" ], "comment": "(n) political measures/policy" },
		{ "question": "故", "answers": [ "ゆえ" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n) reason/cause/circumstances" },
		{ "question": "故人", "answers": [ "こじん" ], "comment": "(n) the deceased/old friend" },
		{ "question": "故郷", "answers": [ "こきょう","ふるさと" ], "comment": "(n) home town/birthplace/old village/historic village/native place/one's old home" },
		{ "question": "故障", "answers": [ "こしょう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) break-down/failure/accident/out of order" },
		{ "question": "敏感", "answers": [ "びんかん" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) sensibility/susceptibility/sensitive (to)/well attuned to" },
		{ "question": "救い", "answers": [ "すくい" ], "comment": "(n) help/aid/relief" },
		{ "question": "救う", "answers": [ "すくう" ], "comment": "(v5u) to rescue from/to help out of" },
		{ "question": "救助", "answers": [ "きゅうじょ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) relief/aid/rescue" },
		{ "question": "救援", "answers": [ "きゅうえん" ], "comment": "(n) relief/rescue/reinforcement" },
		{ "question": "救済", "answers": [ "きゅうさい" ], "comment": "(n) relief/aid/rescue/salvation/help" },
		{ "question": "敗北", "answers": [ "はいぼく" ], "comment": "(n,vs) defeat (as a verb it means 'to be defeated')" },
		{ "question": "敗戦", "answers": [ "はいせん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) defeat/losing a war" },
		{ "question": "教え", "answers": [ "おしえ" ], "comment": "(n) teachings/precept/lesson/doctrine" },
		{ "question": "教える", "answers": [ "おしえる" ], "comment": "(v1) to teach/to inform/to instruct" },
		{ "question": "教わる", "answers": [ "おそわる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to be taught" },
		{ "question": "教会", "answers": [ "きょうかい" ], "comment": "(n) church" },
		{ "question": "教室", "answers": [ "きょうしつ" ], "comment": "(n) classroom" },
		{ "question": "教師", "answers": [ "きょうし" ], "comment": "(n) teacher (classroom)" },
		{ "question": "教授", "answers": [ "きょうじゅ" ], "comment": "(n) teaching/instruction/professor" },
		{ "question": "教材", "answers": [ "きょうざい" ], "comment": "(n) teaching materials" },
		{ "question": "教科", "answers": [ "きょうか" ], "comment": "(n) subject/curriculum" },
		{ "question": "教科書", "answers": [ "きょうかしょ" ], "comment": "(n) text book" },
		{ "question": "教習", "answers": [ "きょうしゅう" ], "comment": "(n) training/instruction" },
		{ "question": "教職", "answers": [ "きょうしょく" ], "comment": "(n) teaching certificate/the teaching profession" },
		{ "question": "教育", "answers": [ "きょういく" ], "comment": "(adj-no,n,vs) training/education" },
		{ "question": "教訓", "answers": [ "きょうくん" ], "comment": "(n) lesson/precept/moral instruction" },
		{ "question": "教養", "answers": [ "きょうよう" ], "comment": "(n) culture/education/refinement/cultivation" },
		{ "question": "敢えて", "answers": [ "あえて" ], "comment": "(adv) dare (to do)/challenge (to do)" },
		{ "question": "散らかす", "answers": [ "ちらかす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to scatter around/to leave untidy" },
		{ "question": "散らかる", "answers": [ "ちらかる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to be in disorder/to lie scattered around" },
		{ "question": "散らす", "answers": [ "ちらす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to scatter/to disperse/to distribute" },
		{ "question": "散る", "answers": [ "ちる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to fall/to scatter (e.g. blossoms)" },
		{ "question": "散歩", "answers": [ "さんぽ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) walk/stroll" },
		{ "question": "敬う", "answers": [ "うやまう" ], "comment": "(v5u) to show respect/to honour" },
		{ "question": "敬具", "answers": [ "けいぐ" ], "comment": "(int,n) Sincerely yours" },
		{ "question": "敬意", "answers": [ "けいい" ], "comment": "(n) respect/honour" },
		{ "question": "敬語", "answers": [ "けいご" ], "comment": "(n) honorific/term of respect" },
		{ "question": "数", "answers": [ "かず","すう" ], "comment": "(n,n-suf) number/figure" },
		{ "question": "数える", "answers": [ "かぞえる" ], "comment": "(v1) to count" },
		{ "question": "数字", "answers": [ "すうじ" ], "comment": "(n) numeral/figure" },
		{ "question": "数学", "answers": [ "すうがく" ], "comment": "(n) mathematics/arithmetic" },
		{ "question": "数詞", "answers": [ "すうし" ], "comment": "(n) numeral" },
		{ "question": "整う", "answers": [ "ととのう" ], "comment": "(v5u) to be prepared/to be in order/to be put in order/to be arranged" },
		{ "question": "整える", "answers": [ "ととのえる" ], "comment": "(v1) (1) to put in order/to arrange/to adjust/(2) to get ready/to prepare/(3) to raise money" },
		{ "question": "整備", "answers": [ "せいび" ], "comment": "(n,vs) adjustment/completion/consolidation" },
		{ "question": "整列", "answers": [ "せいれつ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) stand in a row/form a line" },
		{ "question": "整数", "answers": [ "せいすう" ], "comment": "(n) integer" },
		{ "question": "整然", "answers": [ "せいぜん" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) orderly/regular/well-organized/trim/accurate" },
		{ "question": "整理", "answers": [ "せいり" ], "comment": "(n,vs) sorting/arrangement/adjustment/regulation" },
		{ "question": "敵", "answers": [ "てき" ], "comment": "(n) enemy/rival" },
		{ "question": "敷く", "answers": [ "しく" ], "comment": "(v5k) to spread out/to lay out" },
		{ "question": "敷地", "answers": [ "しきち" ], "comment": "(n) site" },
		{ "question": "文", "answers": [ "ぶん" ], "comment": "(n) sentence" },
		{ "question": "文体", "answers": [ "ぶんたい" ], "comment": "(n) literary style" },
		{ "question": "文化", "answers": [ "ぶんか" ], "comment": "(n) culture/civilization" },
		{ "question": "文化財", "answers": [ "ぶんかざい" ], "comment": "(n) cultural assets/cultural property" },
		{ "question": "文句", "answers": [ "もんく" ], "comment": "(n) phrase/complaint" },
		{ "question": "文字", "answers": [ "もじ","もんじ" ], "comment": "(n) letter (of alphabet)/character" },
		{ "question": "文学", "answers": [ "ぶんがく" ], "comment": "(n) literature" },
		{ "question": "文房具", "answers": [ "ぶんぼうぐ" ], "comment": "(n) stationery" },
		{ "question": "文明", "answers": [ "ぶんめい" ], "comment": "(n) civilization/culture" },
		{ "question": "文書", "answers": [ "ぶんしょ" ], "comment": "(n) document/writing/letter/note/records/archives" },
		{ "question": "文法", "answers": [ "ぶんぽう" ], "comment": "(n) grammar" },
		{ "question": "文献", "answers": [ "ぶんけん" ], "comment": "(n) literature/books (reference)" },
		{ "question": "文章", "answers": [ "ぶんしょう" ], "comment": "(n) sentence/article" },
		{ "question": "文脈", "answers": [ "ぶんみゃく" ], "comment": "(n) context" },
		{ "question": "文芸", "answers": [ "ぶんげい" ], "comment": "(n) literature/art and literature/belles-lettres" },
		{ "question": "文語", "answers": [ "ぶんご" ], "comment": "(n) written language/literary language" },
		{ "question": "斑", "answers": [ "むら" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) (uk) unevenness/inconsistancy/erraticness/irregularity" },
		{ "question": "料理", "answers": [ "りょうり" ], "comment": "(n,vs) cooking/cookery/cuisine" },
		{ "question": "料金", "answers": [ "りょうきん" ], "comment": "(n) fee/charge/fare" },
		{ "question": "斜め", "answers": [ "ななめ" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) obliqueness" },
		{ "question": "斜面", "answers": [ "しゃめん" ], "comment": "(n) slope/slanting surface/bevel" },
		{ "question": "斡旋", "answers": [ "あっせん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) kind offices/mediation" },
		{ "question": "斬る", "answers": [ "きる" ], "comment": "(oK) (v5r) to behead/to murder" },
		{ "question": "断つ", "answers": [ "たつ" ], "comment": "(v5t) to sever/to cut off/to suppress/to abstain (from)" },
		{ "question": "断る", "answers": [ "ことわる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to refuse/to inform/to ask leave/to decline/to dismiss" },
		{ "question": "断定", "answers": [ "だんてい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) conclusion/decision" },
		{ "question": "断水", "answers": [ "だんすい" ], "comment": "(n) water outage" },
		{ "question": "断然", "answers": [ "だんぜん" ], "comment": "(adj-na,adv,n) firmly/absolutely/definitely" },
		{ "question": "断言", "answers": [ "だんげん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) assertion/declaration/affirmation" },
		{ "question": "断面", "answers": [ "だんめん" ], "comment": "(n) cross section" },
		{ "question": "新しい", "answers": [ "あたらしい" ], "comment": "(adj) new" },
		{ "question": "新た", "answers": [ "あらた" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) new/fresh/novel" },
		{ "question": "新人", "answers": [ "しんじん" ], "comment": "(n) new face/newcomer" },
		{ "question": "新入生", "answers": [ "しんにゅうせい" ], "comment": "(n) freshman/first-year student" },
		{ "question": "新婚", "answers": [ "しんこん" ], "comment": "(n) newly-wed" },
		{ "question": "新幹線", "answers": [ "しんかんせん" ], "comment": "(n) bullet train (very high speed)/shinkansen" },
		{ "question": "新築", "answers": [ "しんちく" ], "comment": "(n) new building/new construction" },
		{ "question": "新聞", "answers": [ "しんぶん" ], "comment": "(n) newspaper" },
		{ "question": "新聞社", "answers": [ "しんぶんしゃ" ], "comment": "(n) newspaper company" },
		{ "question": "新興", "answers": [ "しんこう" ], "comment": "(n) rising/developing/emergent" },
		{ "question": "新鮮", "answers": [ "しんせん" ], "comment": "(adj-na) fresh" },
		{ "question": "方", "answers": [ "かた","ほう" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n) side" },
		{ "question": "方々", "answers": [ "かたがた","ほうぼう" ], "comment": "(adv,conj,n-adv,n-t) persons/this and that/here and there/everywhere/any way/all sides/all gentlemen/all people" },
		{ "question": "方向", "answers": [ "ほうこう" ], "comment": "(n) direction/course/way" },
		{ "question": "方式", "answers": [ "ほうしき" ], "comment": "(n) form/method/system" },
		{ "question": "方法", "answers": [ "ほうほう" ], "comment": "(n) method/manner/way/means/technique" },
		{ "question": "方程式", "answers": [ "ほうていしき" ], "comment": "(n) equation" },
		{ "question": "方策", "answers": [ "ほうさく" ], "comment": "(n) plan/policy" },
		{ "question": "方角", "answers": [ "ほうがく" ], "comment": "(n) direction/way/compass point" },
		{ "question": "方言", "answers": [ "ほうげん" ], "comment": "(n) dialect" },
		{ "question": "方針", "answers": [ "ほうしん" ], "comment": "(n) objective/plan/policy" },
		{ "question": "方面", "answers": [ "ほうめん" ], "comment": "(n) direction/district/field (e.g., of study)" },
		{ "question": "於いて", "answers": [ "おいて" ], "comment": "(uk) at/in/on" },
		{ "question": "施す", "answers": [ "ほどこす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to donate/to give/to conduct/to apply/to perform" },
		{ "question": "施行", "answers": [ "しこう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) (1) execution/enforcing/carrying out" },
		{ "question": "施設", "answers": [ "しせつ" ], "comment": "(n) institution/establishment/facility/(army) engineer" },
		{ "question": "旅", "answers": [ "たび" ], "comment": "(n,vs) travel/trip/journey" },
		{ "question": "旅券", "answers": [ "りょけん" ], "comment": "(n) passport" },
		{ "question": "旅客", "answers": [ "りょかく" ], "comment": "(n) passenger (transport)" },
		{ "question": "旅行", "answers": [ "りょこう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) travel/trip" },
		{ "question": "旅館", "answers": [ "りょかん" ], "comment": "(n) Japanese hotel/inn" },
		{ "question": "旗", "answers": [ "はた" ], "comment": "(n) flag" },
		{ "question": "既に", "answers": [ "すでに" ], "comment": "(adv) already/too late" },
		{ "question": "既婚", "answers": [ "きこん" ], "comment": "(adj-no,n) marriage/married" },
		{ "question": "日", "answers": [ "にち","ひ" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n-t) sun/sunshine/day" },
		{ "question": "日の丸", "answers": [ "ひのまる" ], "comment": "(n) the Japanese flag" },
		{ "question": "日の入り", "answers": [ "ひのいり" ], "comment": "(n) sunset" },
		{ "question": "日の出", "answers": [ "ひので" ], "comment": "(n) sunrise" },
		{ "question": "日中", "answers": [ "にっちゅう" ], "comment": "(n-t) daytime/broad daylight" },
		{ "question": "日付", "answers": [ "ひづけ" ], "comment": "(n) date/dating" },
		{ "question": "日光", "answers": [ "にっこう" ], "comment": "(n) sunlight" },
		{ "question": "日取り", "answers": [ "ひどり" ], "comment": "(n) fixed date/appointed day" },
		{ "question": "日向", "answers": [ "ひなた" ], "comment": "(n) sunny place/in the sun" },
		{ "question": "日夜", "answers": [ "にちや" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n) day and night/always" },
		{ "question": "日帰り", "answers": [ "ひがえり" ], "comment": "(n) day trip" },
		{ "question": "日常", "answers": [ "にちじょう" ], "comment": "(adj-no,n-adv,n-t) ordinary/regular/everyday/usual" },
		{ "question": "日当たり", "answers": [ "ひあたり" ], "comment": "(n) exposure to the sun/sunny place" },
		{ "question": "日日", "answers": [ "ひにち" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n-t) every day/daily/day after day" },
		{ "question": "日時", "answers": [ "にちじ" ], "comment": "(n) date and time" },
		{ "question": "日曜", "answers": [ "にちよう" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n) Sunday" },
		{ "question": "日曜日", "answers": [ "にちようび" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n) Sunday" },
		{ "question": "日本", "answers": [ "にっぽん","にほん" ], "comment": "Japan" },
		{ "question": "日焼け", "answers": [ "ひやけ" ], "comment": "(n) sunburn" },
		{ "question": "日用品", "answers": [ "にちようひん" ], "comment": "(n) daily necessities" },
		{ "question": "日程", "answers": [ "にってい" ], "comment": "(n) agenda" },
		{ "question": "日記", "answers": [ "にっき" ], "comment": "(n) diary/journal" },
		{ "question": "日課", "answers": [ "にっか" ], "comment": "(n) daily lesson/daily work/daily routine" },
		{ "question": "日陰", "answers": [ "ひかげ" ], "comment": "(n) shadow" },
		{ "question": "日頃", "answers": [ "ひごろ" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n-t) normally/habitually" },
		{ "question": "旦那", "answers": [ "だんな" ], "comment": "(n) master (of house)/husband (informal)" },
		{ "question": "旧", "answers": [ "きゅう" ], "comment": "(n,pref) ex-" },
		{ "question": "旧知", "answers": [ "きゅうち" ], "comment": "(n) old friend/old friendship" },
		{ "question": "早い", "answers": [ "はやい" ], "comment": "(adj) early" },
		{ "question": "早める", "answers": [ "はやめる" ], "comment": "(v1) to hasten/to quicken/to expedite/to precipitate/to accelerate" },
		{ "question": "早口", "answers": [ "はやくち" ], "comment": "(n) fast-talking" },
		{ "question": "早急", "answers": [ "さっきゅう","そうきゅう" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) urgent" },
		{ "question": "早速", "answers": [ "さっそく" ], "comment": "(adv) at once/immediately/without delay/promptly" },
		{ "question": "昆虫", "answers": [ "こんちゅう" ], "comment": "(n) insect/bug" },
		{ "question": "昇る", "answers": [ "のぼる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to arise/to ascend/to go up" },
		{ "question": "昇進", "answers": [ "しょうしん" ], "comment": "(n) promotion" },
		{ "question": "明るい", "answers": [ "あかるい" ], "comment": "(adj) bright/cheerful" },
		{ "question": "明かす", "answers": [ "あかす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to pass/spend/to reveal/to divulge" },
		{ "question": "明かり", "answers": [ "あかり" ], "comment": "(n) lamplight/light (in general)/brightness" },
		{ "question": "明き", "answers": [ "あき" ], "comment": "(n) room/time to spare/emptiness/vacant" },
		{ "question": "明ける", "answers": [ "あける" ], "comment": "(v1) to dawn/to become daylight" },
		{ "question": "明け方", "answers": [ "あけがた" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n-t) dawn" },
		{ "question": "明らか", "answers": [ "あきらか" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) obvious/evident/clear/plain" },
		{ "question": "明後日", "answers": [ "みょうごにち" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n-t) day after tomorrow" },
		{ "question": "明日", "answers": [ "あす" ], "comment": "(n-t) tomorrow" },
		{ "question": "明朗", "answers": [ "めいろう" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) bright/clear/cheerful" },
		{ "question": "明白", "answers": [ "めいはく" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) (uk) obvious/overt/plainly/frankly" },
		{ "question": "明瞭", "answers": [ "めいりょう" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) clarity" },
		{ "question": "明確", "answers": [ "めいかく" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) clear up/clarify/define" },
		{ "question": "易しい", "answers": [ "やさしい" ], "comment": "(adj) easy/plain/simple" },
		{ "question": "昔", "answers": [ "むかし" ], "comment": "(adj-no,n-adv,n-t) olden days/former" },
		{ "question": "星", "answers": [ "ほし" ], "comment": "(n) star" },
		{ "question": "星座", "answers": [ "せいざ" ], "comment": "(n) constellation" },
		{ "question": "映える", "answers": [ "はえる" ], "comment": "(v1) to shine/to look attractive/to look pretty" },
		{ "question": "映す", "answers": [ "うつす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to project/to reflect/to cast (shadow)" },
		{ "question": "映る", "answers": [ "うつる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to be reflected/to harmonize with/to come out (photo)" },
		{ "question": "映像", "answers": [ "えいぞう" ], "comment": "(n) reflection/image" },
		{ "question": "映写", "answers": [ "えいしゃ" ], "comment": "(n) projection" },
		{ "question": "映画", "answers": [ "えいが" ], "comment": "(n) movie/film" },
		{ "question": "映画館", "answers": [ "えいがかん" ], "comment": "(n) movie theatre (theater)/cinema" },
		{ "question": "春", "answers": [ "はる" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n-t) spring" },
		{ "question": "昨", "answers": [ "さく" ], "comment": "(pref) last (year)/yesterday" },
		{ "question": "昨日", "answers": [ "きのう" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n-t) yesterday" },
		{ "question": "是正", "answers": [ "ぜせい" ], "comment": "(n) correction/revision" },
		{ "question": "是非", "answers": [ "ぜひ" ], "comment": "(adv,n) (uk) certainly/without fail" },
		{ "question": "昼", "answers": [ "ひる" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n-t) noon/daytime" },
		{ "question": "昼休み", "answers": [ "ひるやすみ" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n-t) lunch break/noon recess/noon rest period" },
		{ "question": "昼寝", "answers": [ "ひるね" ], "comment": "(n,vs) nap (at home)/siesta" },
		{ "question": "昼御飯", "answers": [ "ひるごはん" ], "comment": "(n) lunch/midday meal" },
		{ "question": "昼間", "answers": [ "ひるま" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n-t) daytime/during the day" },
		{ "question": "昼食", "answers": [ "ちゅうしょく" ], "comment": "(n) lunch/midday meal" },
		{ "question": "昼飯", "answers": [ "ひるめし" ], "comment": "(n) lunch (masc.)/midday meal" },
		{ "question": "時", "answers": [ "とき" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n) (1) time/hour/(2) occasion/moment" },
		{ "question": "時々", "answers": [ "ときどき" ], "comment": "(adv,n) sometimes" },
		{ "question": "時代", "answers": [ "じだい" ], "comment": "(n-t) period/epoch/era" },
		{ "question": "時刻", "answers": [ "じこく" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n-t) instant/time/moment" },
		{ "question": "時刻表", "answers": [ "じこくひょう" ], "comment": "(n) table/diagram/chart/timetable/schedule" },
		{ "question": "時差", "answers": [ "じさ" ], "comment": "(n) time difference" },
		{ "question": "時折", "answers": [ "ときおり" ], "comment": "(n-adv) sometimes" },
		{ "question": "時期", "answers": [ "じき" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n-t) time/season/period" },
		{ "question": "時計", "answers": [ "とけい" ], "comment": "(n) watch/clock" },
		{ "question": "時速", "answers": [ "じそく" ], "comment": "(n) speed (per hour)" },
		{ "question": "時間", "answers": [ "じかん" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n) time" },
		{ "question": "時間割", "answers": [ "じかんわり" ], "comment": "(n) timetable/schedule" },
		{ "question": "晩", "answers": [ "ばん" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n-t) evening" },
		{ "question": "晩年", "answers": [ "ばんねん" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n-t) (one's) last years" },
		{ "question": "晩御飯", "answers": [ "ばんごはん" ], "comment": "(n) dinner/evening meal" },
		{ "question": "普及", "answers": [ "ふきゅう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) diffusion/spread" },
		{ "question": "普段", "answers": [ "ふだん" ], "comment": "(adj-no,adj-na,n-adv,n) usually/habitually/ordinarily/always" },
		{ "question": "普通", "answers": [ "ふつう" ], "comment": "(adj-na,adj-no,adv,n) (1) generally/ordinarily/usually/(2) train that stops at every station" },
		{ "question": "普遍", "answers": [ "ふへん" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) universality/ubiquity/omnipresence" },
		{ "question": "景気", "answers": [ "けいき" ], "comment": "(n) condition/state/business (condition)" },
		{ "question": "景色", "answers": [ "けしき" ], "comment": "(n) scenery/scene/landscape" },
		{ "question": "晴れ", "answers": [ "はれ" ], "comment": "(n) clear weather" },
		{ "question": "晴れる", "answers": [ "はれる" ], "comment": "(v1) to be sunny/to clear away/to stop raining" },
		{ "question": "晴天", "answers": [ "せいてん" ], "comment": "(n) fine weather" },
		{ "question": "暇", "answers": [ "ひま" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) (1) free time/leisure/leave/spare time/(2) farewell" },
		{ "question": "暑い", "answers": [ "あつい" ], "comment": "(adj) hot/warm" },
		{ "question": "暖かい", "answers": [ "あたたかい" ], "comment": "(adj) warm/mild/genial" },
		{ "question": "暖まる", "answers": [ "あたたまる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to warm oneself/to sun oneself/to warm up/to get warm" },
		{ "question": "暖める", "answers": [ "あたためる" ], "comment": "(v1) to warm/to heat" },
		{ "question": "暖房", "answers": [ "だんぼう" ], "comment": "(n) heating" },
		{ "question": "暗い", "answers": [ "くらい" ], "comment": "(adj) (uk) dark/gloomy" },
		{ "question": "暗殺", "answers": [ "あんさつ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) assassination" },
		{ "question": "暗示", "answers": [ "あんじ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) hint/suggestion" },
		{ "question": "暗算", "answers": [ "あんざん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) mental arithmetic" },
		{ "question": "暗記", "answers": [ "あんき" ], "comment": "(n,vs) memorization/learning by heart" },
		{ "question": "暦", "answers": [ "こよみ" ], "comment": "(n) calendar/almanac" },
		{ "question": "暮らし", "answers": [ "くらし" ], "comment": "(n) living/livelihood/subsistence/circumstances" },
		{ "question": "暮らす", "answers": [ "くらす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to live/to get along" },
		{ "question": "暮れ", "answers": [ "くれ" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n) year end/sunset/nightfall/end" },
		{ "question": "暮れる", "answers": [ "くれる" ], "comment": "(v1) to get dark/to end/to come to an end/to close/to run out" },
		{ "question": "暴れる", "answers": [ "あばれる" ], "comment": "(v1) to act violently/to rage/to struggle/to be riotous" },
		{ "question": "暴力", "answers": [ "ぼうりょく" ], "comment": "(n) violence/mayhem" },
		{ "question": "暴動", "answers": [ "ぼうどう" ], "comment": "(n) insurrection/rebellion/revolt/riot/uprising" },
		{ "question": "暴露", "answers": [ "ばくろ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) disclosure/exposure/revelation" },
		{ "question": "暴風", "answers": [ "ぼうふう" ], "comment": "(n) storm/windstorm/gale" },
		{ "question": "曇", "answers": [ "くもり" ], "comment": "(n) cloudiness/cloudy weather/shadow" },
		{ "question": "曇る", "answers": [ "くもる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to become cloudy/to become dim" },
		{ "question": "曜日", "answers": [ "ようび" ], "comment": "(n) day of the week" },
		{ "question": "曲げる", "answers": [ "まげる" ], "comment": "(v1) to bend/to crook/to lean" },
		{ "question": "曲る", "answers": [ "まがる" ], "comment": "(uv) to turn/to bend" },
		{ "question": "曲線", "answers": [ "きょくせん" ], "comment": "(n) curve" },
		{ "question": "更ける", "answers": [ "ふける" ], "comment": "(v1) to get late/to advance/to wear on" },
		{ "question": "更に", "answers": [ "さらに" ], "comment": "(adv,conj) (uk) furthermore/again/after all/more and more/moreover" },
		{ "question": "書き取る", "answers": [ "かきとる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to write down/to take dictation/to take notes" },
		{ "question": "書く", "answers": [ "かく" ], "comment": "(v5k) to write" },
		{ "question": "書取", "answers": [ "かきとり" ], "comment": "(n) dictation" },
		{ "question": "書店", "answers": [ "しょてん" ], "comment": "(n) bookshop" },
		{ "question": "書斎", "answers": [ "しょさい" ], "comment": "(n) study" },
		{ "question": "書物", "answers": [ "しょもつ" ], "comment": "(n) books" },
		{ "question": "書留", "answers": [ "かきとめ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) writing down/putting on record/recording/making a note of/registration (of mail)" },
		{ "question": "書籍", "answers": [ "しょせき" ], "comment": "(n) book/publication" },
		{ "question": "書評", "answers": [ "しょひょう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) book review" },
		{ "question": "書道", "answers": [ "しょどう" ], "comment": "(n) calligraphy" },
		{ "question": "書類", "answers": [ "しょるい" ], "comment": "(n) documents/official papers" },
		{ "question": "替える", "answers": [ "かえる" ], "comment": "(v1) to exchange/to interchange/to substitute/to replace" },
		{ "question": "最も", "answers": [ "もっとも" ], "comment": "(adv) most/extremely" },
		{ "question": "最中", "answers": [ "さいちゅう","さなか" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n) in the middle of; height of; in course of; midst" },
		{ "question": "最低", "answers": [ "さいてい" ], "comment": "(adj-na,adv,n) (1) least/lowest/worst/(2) nasty/disgusting/horrible/yuck!" },
		{ "question": "最初", "answers": [ "さいしょ" ], "comment": "(adj-no,n-adv,n-t) beginning/outset/first/onset" },
		{ "question": "最善", "answers": [ "さいぜん" ], "comment": "(n) the very best" },
		{ "question": "最後", "answers": [ "さいご" ], "comment": "(n) last/end/conclusion" },
		{ "question": "最終", "answers": [ "さいしゅう" ], "comment": "(n) last/final/closing" },
		{ "question": "最近", "answers": [ "さいきん" ], "comment": "(adj-no,n-adv,n-t) latest/most recent/nowadays" },
		{ "question": "最高", "answers": [ "さいこう" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) highest/supreme/the most" },
		{ "question": "月", "answers": [ "つき" ], "comment": "(n-t) moon/month" },
		{ "question": "月並", "answers": [ "つきなみ" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) (1) every month/(2) trite/common" },
		{ "question": "月日", "answers": [ "つきひ" ], "comment": "(n) time/years/days" },
		{ "question": "月曜", "answers": [ "げつよう" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n-t) Monday" },
		{ "question": "月曜日", "answers": [ "げつようび" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n) Monday" },
		{ "question": "月末", "answers": [ "げつまつ" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n-t) end of the month" },
		{ "question": "月給", "answers": [ "げっきゅう" ], "comment": "(n) monthly salary" },
		{ "question": "月謝", "answers": [ "げっしゃ" ], "comment": "(n) monthly tuition fee" },
		{ "question": "月賦", "answers": [ "げっぷ" ], "comment": "(n) monthly installment" },
		{ "question": "有する", "answers": [ "ゆうする" ], "comment": "(vs-s) to own/to be endowed with" },
		{ "question": "有る", "answers": [ "ある" ], "comment": "(v5r-i) (uk) to be/to have" },
		{ "question": "有利", "answers": [ "ゆうり" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) advantageous/better/profitable/lucrative" },
		{ "question": "有力", "answers": [ "ゆうりょく" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) (1) influence/prominence/(2) potent" },
		{ "question": "有効", "answers": [ "ゆうこう" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) validity/availability/effectiveness" },
		{ "question": "有名", "answers": [ "ゆうめい" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) fame" },
		{ "question": "有料", "answers": [ "ゆうりょう" ], "comment": "(n) admission-paid/toll" },
		{ "question": "有望", "answers": [ "ゆうぼう" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) good prospects/full of hope/promising" },
		{ "question": "有様", "answers": [ "ありさま" ], "comment": "(n) state/condition/circumstances/the way things are or should be/truth" },
		{ "question": "有機", "answers": [ "ゆうき" ], "comment": "(n) organic" },
		{ "question": "有無", "answers": [ "うむ" ], "comment": "(n) yes or no/existence/flag indicator (comp)/presence or absence marker" },
		{ "question": "有益", "answers": [ "ゆうえき" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) beneficial/profitable" },
		{ "question": "有能", "answers": [ "ゆうのう" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) able/capable/efficient/skill" },
		{ "question": "有難い", "answers": [ "ありがたい" ], "comment": "(adj) grateful/thankful/welcome/appreciated/evoking gratitude" },
		{ "question": "服", "answers": [ "ふく" ], "comment": "(n,n-suf) clothes" },
		{ "question": "服装", "answers": [ "ふくそう" ], "comment": "(n) garments" },
		{ "question": "朗らか", "answers": [ "ほがらか" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) brightness/cheerfulness/melodious" },
		{ "question": "朗読", "answers": [ "ろうどく" ], "comment": "(n) reading aloud/recitation" },
		{ "question": "望ましい", "answers": [ "のぞましい" ], "comment": "(adj) desirable/hoped for" },
		{ "question": "望み", "answers": [ "のぞみ" ], "comment": "(n) wish/desire/(a) hope" },
		{ "question": "望む", "answers": [ "のぞむ" ], "comment": "(v5m) to desire/to wish for/to see/to command (a view of)" },
		{ "question": "望遠鏡", "answers": [ "ぼうえんきょう" ], "comment": "(n) telescope" },
		{ "question": "朝", "answers": [ "あさ" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n-t) morning" },
		{ "question": "朝寝坊", "answers": [ "あさねぼう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) oversleeping/late riser" },
		{ "question": "朝御飯", "answers": [ "あさごはん" ], "comment": "(n) breakfast" },
		{ "question": "期待", "answers": [ "きたい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) expectation/anticipation/hope" },
		{ "question": "期日", "answers": [ "きじつ" ], "comment": "(n) fixed date/settlement date" },
		{ "question": "期間", "answers": [ "きかん" ], "comment": "(n) period/term" },
		{ "question": "期限", "answers": [ "きげん" ], "comment": "(n) term/period" },
		{ "question": "木", "answers": [ "き" ], "comment": "(n) tree/wood/timber" },
		{ "question": "木曜", "answers": [ "もくよう" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n) Thursday" },
		{ "question": "木曜日", "answers": [ "もくようび" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n) Thursday" },
		{ "question": "木材", "answers": [ "もくざい" ], "comment": "(n) lumber/timber/wood" },
		{ "question": "木綿", "answers": [ "もめん" ], "comment": "(n) cotton" },
		{ "question": "未だ", "answers": [ "いまだ","まだ" ], "comment": "(adv) yet/still/more/besides" },
		{ "question": "未婚", "answers": [ "みこん" ], "comment": "(n) unmarried" },
		{ "question": "未定", "answers": [ "みてい" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) not yet fixed/undecided/pending" },
		{ "question": "未来", "answers": [ "みらい" ], "comment": "(n) future (life, tense)" },
		{ "question": "未満", "answers": [ "みまん" ], "comment": "(n-suf) less than/insufficient" },
		{ "question": "未熟", "answers": [ "みじゅく" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) inexperience/unripeness/raw/unskilled/immature/inexperienced" },
		{ "question": "未知", "answers": [ "みち" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) not yet known" },
		{ "question": "未練", "answers": [ "みれん" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) lingering affection/attachment/regret(s)/reluctance" },
		{ "question": "未開", "answers": [ "みかい" ], "comment": "(adj-na,adj-no,n) savage land/backward region/uncivilized" },
		{ "question": "末", "answers": [ "すえ","まつ" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n) the end of/powder" },
		{ "question": "末っ子", "answers": [ "すえっこ" ], "comment": "(n) youngest child" },
		{ "question": "末期", "answers": [ "まっき" ], "comment": "(n) deathbed/hour of death" },
		{ "question": "本", "answers": [ "ほん" ], "comment": "(n,n-suf,n-t) (1) origin/original" },
		{ "question": "本人", "answers": [ "ほんにん" ], "comment": "(n) the person himself" },
		{ "question": "本体", "answers": [ "ほんたい" ], "comment": "(n) substance/real form/object of worship" },
		{ "question": "本名", "answers": [ "ほんみょう" ], "comment": "(n) real name" },
		{ "question": "本国", "answers": [ "ほんごく" ], "comment": "(n) one's own country" },
		{ "question": "本場", "answers": [ "ほんば" ], "comment": "(n) home/habitat/center/best place/genuine" },
		{ "question": "本当", "answers": [ "ほんと","ほんとう" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) truth/reality" },
		{ "question": "本文", "answers": [ "ほんぶん" ], "comment": "(n) text (of document)/body (of letter)" },
		{ "question": "本来", "answers": [ "ほんらい" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n-t,adj-no) essentially/naturally/by nature/in (and of) itself/originally" },
		{ "question": "本格", "answers": [ "ほんかく" ], "comment": "(n) propriety/fundamental rules" },
		{ "question": "本棚", "answers": [ "ほんだな" ], "comment": "(n) bookshelves" },
		{ "question": "本気", "answers": [ "ほんき" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) seriousness/truth/sanctity" },
		{ "question": "本物", "answers": [ "ほんもの" ], "comment": "(n) genuine article" },
		{ "question": "本能", "answers": [ "ほんのう" ], "comment": "(n) instinct" },
		{ "question": "本質", "answers": [ "ほんしつ" ], "comment": "(n) essence/true nature/reality" },
		{ "question": "本部", "answers": [ "ほんぶ" ], "comment": "(n) headquarters" },
		{ "question": "本音", "answers": [ "ほんね" ], "comment": "(n) real intention/motive" },
		{ "question": "本館", "answers": [ "ほんかん" ], "comment": "(n) main building" },
		{ "question": "札", "answers": [ "さつ","ふだ" ], "comment": "(n) (1) token/label/(2) ticket/card/(3) charm/talisman" },
		{ "question": "机", "answers": [ "つくえ" ], "comment": "(n) desk" },
		{ "question": "朽ちる", "answers": [ "くちる" ], "comment": "(v1) to rot" },
		{ "question": "杉", "answers": [ "すぎ" ], "comment": "(n) Japanese cedar" },
		{ "question": "材料", "answers": [ "ざいりょう" ], "comment": "(n) ingredients/material" },
		{ "question": "材木", "answers": [ "ざいもく" ], "comment": "(n) lumber/timber" },
		{ "question": "村", "answers": [ "むら" ], "comment": "(n) village" },
		{ "question": "杖", "answers": [ "つえ" ], "comment": "(n) cane" },
		{ "question": "束", "answers": [ "たば" ], "comment": "(n) handbreadth/bundle" },
		{ "question": "束ねる", "answers": [ "たばねる" ], "comment": "(v1) to tie up in a bundle/to govern/to manage/to control/to fold (one's arms)/to administer" },
		{ "question": "束縛", "answers": [ "そくばく" ], "comment": "(n,vs) restraint/shackles/restriction/confinement/binding" },
		{ "question": "条件", "answers": [ "じょうけん" ], "comment": "(n) conditions/terms" },
		{ "question": "条約", "answers": [ "じょうやく" ], "comment": "(n) treaty/pact" },
		{ "question": "来", "answers": [ "らい" ], "comment": "since (last month)/for (10 days)/next (year)" },
		{ "question": "来る", "answers": [ "きたる","くる" ], "comment": "(vk) to come/to come to hand/to arrive/to approach/to call on/to come on (rain)/to set in/to be due/to become/to grow/to get/to come from/to be caused by/to derive from" },
		{ "question": "来場", "answers": [ "らいじょう" ], "comment": "(n) attendance" },
		{ "question": "来年", "answers": [ "らいねん" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n-t) next year" },
		{ "question": "来日", "answers": [ "らいにち" ], "comment": "(n) arrival in Japan/coming to Japan/visit to Japan" },
		{ "question": "来月", "answers": [ "らいげつ" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n-t) next month" },
		{ "question": "来週", "answers": [ "らいしゅう" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n-t) next week" },
		{ "question": "杯", "answers": [ "さかずき" ], "comment": "(n) wine cups" },
		{ "question": "東", "answers": [ "ひがし" ], "comment": "(n) east" },
		{ "question": "東洋", "answers": [ "とうよう" ], "comment": "(n) Orient" },
		{ "question": "東西", "answers": [ "とうざい" ], "comment": "(n) East and West/whole country/Orient and Occident/Your attention please" },
		{ "question": "松", "answers": [ "まつ" ], "comment": "(n) (1) pine tree/(2) highest (of a three-tier ranking system)" },
		{ "question": "板", "answers": [ "いた" ], "comment": "(n) board/plank" },
		{ "question": "枕", "answers": [ "まくら" ], "comment": "(n,n-suf) pillow/bolster" },
		{ "question": "林", "answers": [ "はやし" ], "comment": "(n) woods/forest" },
		{ "question": "林業", "answers": [ "りんぎょう" ], "comment": "(n) forestry" },
		{ "question": "枚数", "answers": [ "まいすう" ], "comment": "(n) the number of flat things" },
		{ "question": "果して", "answers": [ "はたして" ], "comment": "(adv) as was expected/really" },
		{ "question": "果たす", "answers": [ "はたす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to accomplish/to fulfill/to carry out/to achieve" },
		{ "question": "果て", "answers": [ "はて" ], "comment": "(n) the end/the extremity/the limit(s)/the result" },
		{ "question": "果てる", "answers": [ "はてる" ], "comment": "(v1) to end/to be finished/to be exhausted/to die/to perish" },
		{ "question": "果実", "answers": [ "かじつ" ], "comment": "(n) fruit/nut/berry." },
		{ "question": "果物", "answers": [ "くだもの" ], "comment": "(n) fruit" },
		{ "question": "枝", "answers": [ "えだ" ], "comment": "(n) branch/bow/twig/limb" },
		{ "question": "枠", "answers": [ "わく" ], "comment": "(n,n-suf) frame/slide" },
		{ "question": "枯れる", "answers": [ "かれる" ], "comment": "(v1) to wither/to die (plant)/to be blasted (plant)" },
		{ "question": "架空", "answers": [ "かくう" ], "comment": "(adj-na,adj-no,n) aerial/overhead/fiction/fanciful" },
		{ "question": "柄", "answers": [ "え","がら" ], "comment": "(n) hilt (of a sword)/haft (of a dagger)/handgrip" },
		{ "question": "染まる", "answers": [ "そまる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to dye" },
		{ "question": "染みる", "answers": [ "しみる" ], "comment": "(aux-v,v1) to have a touch of/to look like" },
		{ "question": "染める", "answers": [ "そめる" ], "comment": "(v1) to dye/to colour" },
		{ "question": "柔らかい", "answers": [ "やわらかい" ], "comment": "(adj) soft/tender/limp" },
		{ "question": "柔軟", "answers": [ "じゅうなん" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) flexible/lithe" },
		{ "question": "柔道", "answers": [ "じゅうどう" ], "comment": "(n) judo" },
		{ "question": "柵", "answers": [ "さく" ], "comment": "(n) fence/paling" },
		{ "question": "栄える", "answers": [ "さかえる" ], "comment": "(v1) to shine/to look attractive/to look pretty" },
		{ "question": "栄養", "answers": [ "えいよう" ], "comment": "(n) nutrition/nourishment" },
		{ "question": "栓", "answers": [ "せん" ], "comment": "(n) stopper/cork/stopcock" },
		{ "question": "校庭", "answers": [ "こうてい" ], "comment": "(n) campus" },
		{ "question": "校舎", "answers": [ "こうしゃ" ], "comment": "(n) school building" },
		{ "question": "校長", "answers": [ "こうちょう" ], "comment": "(n) principal/headmaster" },
		{ "question": "株", "answers": [ "かぶ" ], "comment": "(n) share/stock/stump (of tree)" },
		{ "question": "株式", "answers": [ "かぶしき" ], "comment": "(n) stock (company)" },
		{ "question": "核", "answers": [ "かく" ], "comment": "(n) nucleus/kernel" },
		{ "question": "根", "answers": [ "ね" ], "comment": "(n) root" },
		{ "question": "根回し", "answers": [ "ねまわし" ], "comment": "(n) making necessary arrangements" },
		{ "question": "根底", "answers": [ "こんてい" ], "comment": "(n) root/basis/foundation" },
		{ "question": "根拠", "answers": [ "こんきょ" ], "comment": "(n) basis/foundation" },
		{ "question": "根本", "answers": [ "こんぽん" ], "comment": "(n) origin/source/foundation/root/base/principle" },
		{ "question": "根気", "answers": [ "こんき" ], "comment": "(n) (1) patience/(2) perseverance/energy" },
		{ "question": "格", "answers": [ "かく" ], "comment": "(n,n-suf) status/character/case" },
		{ "question": "格別", "answers": [ "かくべつ" ], "comment": "(adj-na,adv,n) exceptional" },
		{ "question": "格好", "answers": [ "かっこう" ], "comment": "(adj-no,adj-na,n) shape/form/posture/suitability/moderateness (in price)/appearance/manner" },
		{ "question": "格差", "answers": [ "かくさ" ], "comment": "(n) qualitative difference/disparity" },
		{ "question": "栽培", "answers": [ "さいばい" ], "comment": "(n) cultivation" },
		{ "question": "桁", "answers": [ "けた" ], "comment": "(n) column/beam/digit" },
		{ "question": "案", "answers": [ "あん" ], "comment": "(n,n-suf) plan/suffix meaning draft" },
		{ "question": "案じる", "answers": [ "あんじる" ], "comment": "(v1) to be anxious/to ponder" },
		{ "question": "案内", "answers": [ "あんない" ], "comment": "(n,vs) information/guidance/leading" },
		{ "question": "案外", "answers": [ "あんがい" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n-adv) unexpectedly" },
		{ "question": "桜", "answers": [ "さくら" ], "comment": "(n) cherry blossom/cherry tree" },
		{ "question": "桟橋", "answers": [ "さんばし" ], "comment": "(n) wharf/bridge/jetty/pier" },
		{ "question": "梅", "answers": [ "うめ" ], "comment": "(n) plum/plum-tree/lowest (of a three-tier ranking system)" },
		{ "question": "梅干し", "answers": [ "うめぼし" ], "comment": "(n) dried plum" },
		{ "question": "梅雨", "answers": [ "つゆ","ばいう" ], "comment": "(n) rainy season/rain during the rainy season" },
		{ "question": "梢", "answers": [ "こずえ" ], "comment": "(n) treetop" },
		{ "question": "梯子", "answers": [ "はしご" ], "comment": "(n) ladder/stairs" },
		{ "question": "棄権", "answers": [ "きけん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) abstain from voting/renunciation of a right" },
		{ "question": "棒", "answers": [ "ぼう" ], "comment": "(n) pole/rod/stick" },
		{ "question": "棚", "answers": [ "たな" ], "comment": "(n) shelves/rack" },
		{ "question": "棟", "answers": [ "とう" ], "comment": "(n) ridge (of roof)" },
		{ "question": "森", "answers": [ "もり" ], "comment": "(n) forest" },
		{ "question": "森林", "answers": [ "しんりん" ], "comment": "(n) forest/woods" },
		{ "question": "椀", "answers": [ "わん" ], "comment": "(n) Japanese soup bowl/wooden bowl" },
		{ "question": "椅子", "answers": [ "いす" ], "comment": "(n) chair" },
		{ "question": "植える", "answers": [ "うえる" ], "comment": "(v1) to plant/to grow" },
		{ "question": "植わる", "answers": [ "うわる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to be planted" },
		{ "question": "植木", "answers": [ "うえき" ], "comment": "(n) garden shrubs/trees/potted plant" },
		{ "question": "植民地", "answers": [ "しょくみんち" ], "comment": "(n) colony" },
		{ "question": "植物", "answers": [ "しょくぶつ" ], "comment": "(n) plant/vegetation" },
		{ "question": "検事", "answers": [ "けんじ" ], "comment": "(n) public prosecutor" },
		{ "question": "検査", "answers": [ "けんさ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) inspection (e.g. customs, factory)/examination" },
		{ "question": "検討", "answers": [ "けんとう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) consideration/examination/investigation/study/scrutiny" },
		{ "question": "楕円", "answers": [ "だえん" ], "comment": "(n) ellipse" },
		{ "question": "業務", "answers": [ "ぎょうむ" ], "comment": "(n) business/affairs/duties/work" },
		{ "question": "業績", "answers": [ "ぎょうせき" ], "comment": "(n) achievement/performance/results/work/contribution" },
		{ "question": "業者", "answers": [ "ぎょうしゃ" ], "comment": "(n) trader/merchant" },
		{ "question": "極", "answers": [ "ごく" ], "comment": "(adv,n) quite/very" },
		{ "question": "極めて", "answers": [ "きわめて" ], "comment": "(adv) exceedingly/extremely" },
		{ "question": "極楽", "answers": [ "ごくらく" ], "comment": "(n) paradise" },
		{ "question": "極端", "answers": [ "きょくたん" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) extreme/extremity" },
		{ "question": "楽", "answers": [ "らく" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n,n-suf) comfort/ease" },
		{ "question": "楽しい", "answers": [ "たのしい" ], "comment": "(adj) enjoyable/fun" },
		{ "question": "楽しみ", "answers": [ "たのしみ" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) enjoyment/pleasure" },
		{ "question": "楽器", "answers": [ "がっき" ], "comment": "(n) musical instrument" },
		{ "question": "楽観", "answers": [ "らっかん" ], "comment": "(n) optimism" },
		{ "question": "楽譜", "answers": [ "がくふ" ], "comment": "(n) score (music)" },
		{ "question": "概念", "answers": [ "がいねん" ], "comment": "(n) general idea/concept/notion" },
		{ "question": "概略", "answers": [ "がいりゃく" ], "comment": "(n-t) outline/summary/gist/in brief" },
		{ "question": "概説", "answers": [ "がいせつ" ], "comment": "(n) general statement/outline" },
		{ "question": "概論", "answers": [ "がいろん" ], "comment": "(n) intro/outline/general remarks" },
		{ "question": "構う", "answers": [ "かまう" ], "comment": "(v5u) to mind/to care about/to be concerned about" },
		{ "question": "構える", "answers": [ "かまえる" ], "comment": "(v1) to set up" },
		{ "question": "構想", "answers": [ "こうそう" ], "comment": "(n) plan/plot/idea/conception" },
		{ "question": "構成", "answers": [ "こうせい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) organization/composition" },
		{ "question": "構造", "answers": [ "こうぞう" ], "comment": "(n) structure/construction" },
		{ "question": "様", "answers": [ "さま","よう" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n-adv,n) way/manner/kind/sort/appearance/like/such as/so as to/in order to/so that/yang" },
		{ "question": "様々", "answers": [ "さまざま" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) varied/various" },
		{ "question": "様子", "answers": [ "ようす" ], "comment": "(n) aspect/state/appearance" },
		{ "question": "様式", "answers": [ "ようしき" ], "comment": "(n) style/form/pattern" },
		{ "question": "様相", "answers": [ "ようそう" ], "comment": "(n) aspect" },
		{ "question": "標本", "answers": [ "ひょうほん" ], "comment": "(n) example/specimen" },
		{ "question": "標準", "answers": [ "ひょうじゅん" ], "comment": "(n) standard/level" },
		{ "question": "標語", "answers": [ "ひょうご" ], "comment": "(n) motto/slogan/catchword" },
		{ "question": "標識", "answers": [ "ひょうしき" ], "comment": "(n) sign/mark" },
		{ "question": "模倣", "answers": [ "もほう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) imitation/copying" },
		{ "question": "模型", "answers": [ "もけい" ], "comment": "(n) model/dummy/maquette" },
		{ "question": "模様", "answers": [ "もよう" ], "comment": "(n) pattern/figure/design" },
		{ "question": "模範", "answers": [ "もはん" ], "comment": "(n) exemplar/exemplification/exemplum/model/example" },
		{ "question": "模索", "answers": [ "もさく" ], "comment": "(n) groping (for)" },
		{ "question": "権利", "answers": [ "けんり" ], "comment": "(n) right/privilege" },
		{ "question": "権力", "answers": [ "けんりょく" ], "comment": "(n) (political) power/authority/influence" },
		{ "question": "権威", "answers": [ "けんい" ], "comment": "(n) authority/power/influence" },
		{ "question": "権限", "answers": [ "けんげん" ], "comment": "(n) power/authority/jurisdiction" },
		{ "question": "横", "answers": [ "よこ" ], "comment": "(n) beside/side/width" },
		{ "question": "横切る", "answers": [ "よこぎる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to cross (e.g. arms)/to traverse" },
		{ "question": "横断", "answers": [ "おうだん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) crossing" },
		{ "question": "横綱", "answers": [ "よこづな" ], "comment": "(n) sumo grand champion" },
		{ "question": "樹木", "answers": [ "じゅもく" ], "comment": "(n) trees and shrubs/arbour" },
		{ "question": "樹立", "answers": [ "じゅりつ" ], "comment": "(n) establish/create" },
		{ "question": "橋", "answers": [ "はし" ], "comment": "(n) bridge" },
		{ "question": "橋渡し", "answers": [ "はしわたし" ], "comment": "(n) 'bridge building'/mediation" },
		{ "question": "機会", "answers": [ "きかい" ], "comment": "(n) chance/opportunity" },
		{ "question": "機嫌", "answers": [ "きげん" ], "comment": "(n) humour/temper/mood" },
		{ "question": "機械", "answers": [ "きかい" ], "comment": "(n) machine/mechanism" },
		{ "question": "機構", "answers": [ "きこう" ], "comment": "(n) mechanism/organization" },
		{ "question": "機能", "answers": [ "きのう" ], "comment": "(n) function/faculty" },
		{ "question": "機関", "answers": [ "きかん" ], "comment": "(n) organ/mechanism/facility/engine" },
		{ "question": "機関車", "answers": [ "きかんしゃ" ], "comment": "(n) locomotive/engine" },
		{ "question": "檻", "answers": [ "おり" ], "comment": "(n) cage/pen/jail cell" },
		{ "question": "櫛", "answers": [ "くし" ], "comment": "(n) comb" },
		{ "question": "欄", "answers": [ "らん" ], "comment": "(n) column of text (e.g. as in a newspaper)" },
		{ "question": "欠く", "answers": [ "かく" ], "comment": "(v5k) to lack/to break/to crack/to chip" },
		{ "question": "欠ける", "answers": [ "かける" ], "comment": "(v1) to be lacking" },
		{ "question": "欠乏", "answers": [ "けつぼう" ], "comment": "(n) want/shortage/famine" },
		{ "question": "欠席", "answers": [ "けっせき" ], "comment": "(n,vs) absence/non-attendance" },
		{ "question": "欠点", "answers": [ "けってん" ], "comment": "(n) faults/defect/weakness" },
		{ "question": "欠陥", "answers": [ "けっかん" ], "comment": "(n) defect/fault/deficiency" },
		{ "question": "次", "answers": [ "つぎ" ], "comment": "(n) next/stage station/stage/subsequent" },
		{ "question": "次々", "answers": [ "つぎつぎ" ], "comment": "(adv,n) in succession/one by one" },
		{ "question": "次ぐ", "answers": [ "つぐ" ], "comment": "(v5g) to rank next to/to come after" },
		{ "question": "次第", "answers": [ "しだい" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n) (1) order/precedence/(2) circumstances/(3) immediate(ly)/as soon as/dependent upon" },
		{ "question": "欧米", "answers": [ "おうべい" ], "comment": "Europe and America/the West" },
		{ "question": "欲", "answers": [ "よく" ], "comment": "(n) greed/wants" },
		{ "question": "欲しい", "answers": [ "ほしい" ], "comment": "(adj) wanted/wished for/in need of/desired" },
		{ "question": "欲張り", "answers": [ "よくばり" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) avarice/covetousness/greed" },
		{ "question": "欲望", "answers": [ "よくぼう" ], "comment": "(n) desire/appetite" },
		{ "question": "欲深い", "answers": [ "よくふかい" ], "comment": "(adj) greedy" },
		{ "question": "欺く", "answers": [ "あざむく" ], "comment": "(v5k) to deceive" },
		{ "question": "歌", "answers": [ "うた" ], "comment": "(n) song/poetry" },
		{ "question": "歌う", "answers": [ "うたう" ], "comment": "(v5u) to sing" },
		{ "question": "歌手", "answers": [ "かしゅ" ], "comment": "(n) singer" },
		{ "question": "歌謡", "answers": [ "かよう" ], "comment": "(n) song/ballad" },
		{ "question": "歓声", "answers": [ "かんせい" ], "comment": "(n) cheer/shout of joy" },
		{ "question": "歓迎", "answers": [ "かんげい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) welcome/reception" },
		{ "question": "止す", "answers": [ "よす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to cease/to abolish/to resign/to give up" },
		{ "question": "止まる", "answers": [ "とまる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to come to a halt" },
		{ "question": "止む", "answers": [ "やむ" ], "comment": "(v5m,vi) to cease/to stop/to be over" },
		{ "question": "止める", "answers": [ "とどめる","とめる","やめる" ], "comment": "(v1,vt) to end/to stop/to cease/to resign" },
		{ "question": "正", "answers": [ "せい" ], "comment": "(n) (logical) true/regular" },
		{ "question": "正しい", "answers": [ "ただしい" ], "comment": "(adj) right/just/correct/righteous/honest/truthful/proper/straightforward/perfect" },
		{ "question": "正体", "answers": [ "しょうたい" ], "comment": "(n) natural shape/one's true colors/true character/consciousness/senses" },
		{ "question": "正午", "answers": [ "しょうご" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n-t) noon/mid-day" },
		{ "question": "正味", "answers": [ "しょうみ" ], "comment": "(n) net (weight)" },
		{ "question": "正常", "answers": [ "せいじょう" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) normalcy/normality/normal" },
		{ "question": "正式", "answers": [ "せいしき" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) due form/official/formality" },
		{ "question": "正当", "answers": [ "せいとう" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) just/justifiable/right/due/proper/equitable/reasonable/legitimate/lawful" },
		{ "question": "正方形", "answers": [ "せいほうけい" ], "comment": "(n) square" },
		{ "question": "正月", "answers": [ "しょうがつ" ], "comment": "(n) New Year/New Year's Day/the first month/January" },
		{ "question": "正直", "answers": [ "しょうじき" ], "comment": "(adj-na,adv,n) honesty/integrity/frankness" },
		{ "question": "正確", "answers": [ "せいかく" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) accurate/punctuality/exactness/authenticity/veracity" },
		{ "question": "正義", "answers": [ "せいぎ" ], "comment": "(n) justice/right/righteousness/correct meaning" },
		{ "question": "正規", "answers": [ "せいき" ], "comment": "(adj-na,adj-no,n) regular/legal/formal/established/legitimate" },
		{ "question": "正解", "answers": [ "せいかい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) correct/right/correct interpretation (answer, solution)" },
		{ "question": "正門", "answers": [ "せいもん" ], "comment": "(n) main gate/main entrance" },
		{ "question": "正面", "answers": [ "しょうめん" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) the front/honesty" },
		{ "question": "武力", "answers": [ "ぶりょく" ], "comment": "(n) armed might/military power/the sword/force" },
		{ "question": "武器", "answers": [ "ぶき" ], "comment": "(n) weapon/arms/ordinance" },
		{ "question": "武士", "answers": [ "ぶし" ], "comment": "(n) warrior/samurai" },
		{ "question": "武装", "answers": [ "ぶそう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) arms/armament/armed" },
		{ "question": "歩く", "answers": [ "あるく" ], "comment": "(v5k) to walk" },
		{ "question": "歩み", "answers": [ "あゆみ" ], "comment": "(n) walking" },
		{ "question": "歩む", "answers": [ "あゆむ" ], "comment": "(v5m) to walk/to go on foot" },
		{ "question": "歩道", "answers": [ "ほどう" ], "comment": "(n) footpath/walkway/sidewalk" },
		{ "question": "歪む", "answers": [ "ひずむ","ゆがむ" ], "comment": "(v5m) to warp/to swerve/to deflect/to be crooked/to be distorted/to be bent/to incline/to slant/to be perverted/to be gross-grained/to get bent/to be strained" },
		{ "question": "歯", "answers": [ "は" ], "comment": "(n) tooth" },
		{ "question": "歯医者", "answers": [ "はいしゃ" ], "comment": "(n) dentist" },
		{ "question": "歯磨き", "answers": [ "はみがき" ], "comment": "(n) dentifrice/toothpaste" },
		{ "question": "歯科", "answers": [ "しか" ], "comment": "(n) dentistry" },
		{ "question": "歯車", "answers": [ "はぐるま" ], "comment": "(n) gear/cog-wheel" },
		{ "question": "歴史", "answers": [ "れきし" ], "comment": "(n) history" },
		{ "question": "死", "answers": [ "し" ], "comment": "(n,n-suf) death/decease" },
		{ "question": "死ぬ", "answers": [ "しぬ" ], "comment": "(v5n) to die" },
		{ "question": "死亡", "answers": [ "しぼう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) death/mortality" },
		{ "question": "死体", "answers": [ "したい" ], "comment": "(n) corpse" },
		{ "question": "死刑", "answers": [ "しけい" ], "comment": "(n) death penalty/capital punishment" },
		{ "question": "殊に", "answers": [ "ことに" ], "comment": "(adv) especially/above all" },
		{ "question": "残す", "answers": [ "のこす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to leave (behind, over)/to bequeath/to save/to reserve" },
		{ "question": "残らず", "answers": [ "のこらず" ], "comment": "(adv) all/entirely/completely/without exception" },
		{ "question": "残り", "answers": [ "のこり" ], "comment": "(adj-no,n) remnant/residue/remaining/left-over" },
		{ "question": "残る", "answers": [ "のこる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to remain/to be left" },
		{ "question": "残念", "answers": [ "ざんねん" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) deplorable/bad luck/regret/disappointment" },
		{ "question": "残酷", "answers": [ "ざんこく" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) cruelty/harshness" },
		{ "question": "残金", "answers": [ "ざんきん" ], "comment": "(n) remaining money" },
		{ "question": "残高", "answers": [ "ざんだか" ], "comment": "(n) (bank) balance/remainder" },
		{ "question": "殖える", "answers": [ "ふえる" ], "comment": "(v1,vi) to increase/to multiply" },
		{ "question": "殖やす", "answers": [ "ふやす" ], "comment": "(v5s,vt) to increase/to add to/to augment" },
		{ "question": "段", "answers": [ "だん" ], "comment": "(n) step/stair/flight of steps/grade/rank/level" },
		{ "question": "段階", "answers": [ "だんかい" ], "comment": "(n) gradation/grade/stage" },
		{ "question": "殺す", "answers": [ "ころす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to kill" },
		{ "question": "殺人", "answers": [ "さつじん" ], "comment": "(n) murder" },
		{ "question": "殻", "answers": [ "から" ], "comment": "(n) shell/husk/hull/chaff" },
		{ "question": "殿様", "answers": [ "とのさま" ], "comment": "(n) feudal lord" },
		{ "question": "母", "answers": [ "はは" ], "comment": "(n) (hum) mother" },
		{ "question": "母国", "answers": [ "ぼこく" ], "comment": "(n) one's homeland" },
		{ "question": "母校", "answers": [ "ぼこう" ], "comment": "(n) alma mater" },
		{ "question": "母親", "answers": [ "ははおや" ], "comment": "(n) mother" },
		{ "question": "毎年", "answers": [ "まいとし","まいねん" ], "comment": "(n-t) every year/yearly/annually" },
		{ "question": "毎度", "answers": [ "まいど" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n-t) each time/common service-sector greeting" },
		{ "question": "毎日", "answers": [ "まいにち" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n-t) every day" },
		{ "question": "毎晩", "answers": [ "まいばん" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n-t) every night" },
		{ "question": "毎月", "answers": [ "まいげつ","まいつき" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n) every month/each month/monthly" },
		{ "question": "毎朝", "answers": [ "まいあさ" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n-t) every morning" },
		{ "question": "毎週", "answers": [ "まいしゅう" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n-t) every week" },
		{ "question": "毒", "answers": [ "どく" ], "comment": "(n) poison/toxicant" },
		{ "question": "比べる", "answers": [ "くらべる" ], "comment": "(v1) to compare" },
		{ "question": "比例", "answers": [ "ひれい" ], "comment": "(n) proportion" },
		{ "question": "比率", "answers": [ "ひりつ" ], "comment": "(n) ratio/proportion/percentage" },
		{ "question": "比較", "answers": [ "ひかく" ], "comment": "(n,vs) comparison" },
		{ "question": "比較的", "answers": [ "ひかくてき" ], "comment": "(adv) comparatively/relatively" },
		{ "question": "比重", "answers": [ "ひじゅう" ], "comment": "(n) specific gravity" },
		{ "question": "毛", "answers": [ "け" ], "comment": "(n) hair/fur" },
		{ "question": "毛布", "answers": [ "もうふ" ], "comment": "(n) blanket" },
		{ "question": "毛皮", "answers": [ "けがわ" ], "comment": "(n) fur/skin/pelt" },
		{ "question": "毛糸", "answers": [ "けいと" ], "comment": "(n) knitting wool" },
		{ "question": "氏", "answers": [ "し" ], "comment": "(n) family name/lineage/birth" },
		{ "question": "氏名", "answers": [ "しめい" ], "comment": "(n) full name/identity" },
		{ "question": "民俗", "answers": [ "みんぞく" ], "comment": "(n) people/race/nation/racial customs/folk customs" },
		{ "question": "民宿", "answers": [ "みんしゅく" ], "comment": "(n) private home providing lodging for travelers" },
		{ "question": "民族", "answers": [ "みんぞく" ], "comment": "(n) people/race/nation/racial customs/folk customs" },
		{ "question": "民謡", "answers": [ "みんよう" ], "comment": "(n) folk song/popular song" },
		{ "question": "民間", "answers": [ "みんかん" ], "comment": "(adj-no,n) private/civilian/civil/popular/folk/unofficial" },
		{ "question": "気", "answers": [ "き" ], "comment": "(n) spirit/mood" },
		{ "question": "気に入る", "answers": [ "きにいる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to be pleased with/to suit" },
		{ "question": "気の毒", "answers": [ "きのどく" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) pitiful/a pity" },
		{ "question": "気を付ける", "answers": [ "きをつける" ], "comment": "(exp) to be careful/to pay attention/to take care" },
		{ "question": "気付く", "answers": [ "きづく" ], "comment": "(v5k) to notice/to recognize/to become aware of/to perceive/to realize" },
		{ "question": "気体", "answers": [ "きたい" ], "comment": "(n) vapour/gas" },
		{ "question": "気候", "answers": [ "きこう" ], "comment": "(n) climate" },
		{ "question": "気兼ね", "answers": [ "きがね" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n,vs) hesitance/diffidence/feeling constraint/fear of troubling someone/having scruples about doing something" },
		{ "question": "気分", "answers": [ "きぶん" ], "comment": "(n) feeling/mood" },
		{ "question": "気味", "answers": [ "きみ" ], "comment": "(n-suf) -like/-looking/-looked" },
		{ "question": "気品", "answers": [ "きひん" ], "comment": "(n) aroma" },
		{ "question": "気圧", "answers": [ "きあつ" ], "comment": "(n) atmospheric pressure" },
		{ "question": "気持ち", "answers": [ "きもち" ], "comment": "(n) feeling/sensation/mood" },
		{ "question": "気流", "answers": [ "きりゅう" ], "comment": "(n) atmospheric current" },
		{ "question": "気温", "answers": [ "きおん" ], "comment": "(n) temperature" },
		{ "question": "気象", "answers": [ "きしょう" ], "comment": "(n) weather/climate" },
		{ "question": "気質", "answers": [ "きしつ" ], "comment": "(n) spirit/character/trait/temperament/disposition" },
		{ "question": "気軽", "answers": [ "きがる" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) cheerful/buoyant/lighthearted" },
		{ "question": "気配", "answers": [ "けはい" ], "comment": "(n) indication/market trend/worry" },
		{ "question": "気障", "answers": [ "きざ" ], "comment": "(adj-na) affectation/conceit/snobbery" },
		{ "question": "気風", "answers": [ "きふう" ], "comment": "(n) character/traits/ethos" },
		{ "question": "水", "answers": [ "みず" ], "comment": "(n) water" },
		{ "question": "水分", "answers": [ "すいぶん" ], "comment": "(n) moisture" },
		{ "question": "水平", "answers": [ "すいへい" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) water level/horizon" },
		{ "question": "水平線", "answers": [ "すいへいせん" ], "comment": "(n) horizon" },
		{ "question": "水曜", "answers": [ "すいよう" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n) Wednesday" },
		{ "question": "水曜日", "answers": [ "すいようび" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n) Wednesday" },
		{ "question": "水気", "answers": [ "みずけ" ], "comment": "(n) (1) moisture/dampness/vapor" },
		{ "question": "水泳", "answers": [ "すいえい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) swimming" },
		{ "question": "水洗", "answers": [ "すいせん" ], "comment": "(n) flushing" },
		{ "question": "水源", "answers": [ "すいげん" ], "comment": "(n) source of river/fountainhead" },
		{ "question": "水準", "answers": [ "すいじゅん" ], "comment": "(n) (1) water level/(2) level/standard" },
		{ "question": "水滴", "answers": [ "すいてき" ], "comment": "(n) drop of water" },
		{ "question": "水産", "answers": [ "すいさん" ], "comment": "(n) marine products/fisheries" },
		{ "question": "水田", "answers": [ "すいでん" ], "comment": "(n) (water-filled) paddy field" },
		{ "question": "水着", "answers": [ "みずぎ" ], "comment": "(n) bathing suit (woman's)" },
		{ "question": "水筒", "answers": [ "すいとう" ], "comment": "(n) canteen/flask/water bottle" },
		{ "question": "水素", "answers": [ "すいそ" ], "comment": "(n) hydrogen" },
		{ "question": "水蒸気", "answers": [ "すいじょうき" ], "comment": "(n) water vapour/steam" },
		{ "question": "水道", "answers": [ "すいどう" ], "comment": "(n) water service/water supply" },
		{ "question": "水面", "answers": [ "すいめん" ], "comment": "(n) water's surface" },
		{ "question": "氷", "answers": [ "こおり" ], "comment": "ice/hail" },
		{ "question": "永い", "answers": [ "ながい" ], "comment": "(adj) long/lengthy" },
		{ "question": "永久", "answers": [ "えいきゅう" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) eternity/perpetuity/immortality" },
		{ "question": "永遠", "answers": [ "えいえん" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) eternity/perpetuity/immortality/permanence" },
		{ "question": "氾濫", "answers": [ "はんらん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) overflowing/flood" },
		{ "question": "汁", "answers": [ "しる" ], "comment": "(n) juice/sap/soup/broth" },
		{ "question": "求める", "answers": [ "もとめる" ], "comment": "(v1) to seek/to request/to demand/to want/to wish for/to search for/to pursue (pleasure)/to hunt (a job)/to buy" },
		{ "question": "汗", "answers": [ "あせ" ], "comment": "(n) sweat/perspiration" },
		{ "question": "汚い", "answers": [ "きたない" ], "comment": "(adj) dirty/unclean/filthy" },
		{ "question": "汚す", "answers": [ "よごす" ], "comment": "(v5s) (1) to disgrace/to dishonour/(2) to pollute/to contaminate/to soil/to make dirty/to stain" },
		{ "question": "汚れ", "answers": [ "よごれ" ], "comment": "(n) dirt/filth" },
		{ "question": "汚れる", "answers": [ "よごれる" ], "comment": "(v1) to get dirty/to become dirty" },
		{ "question": "汚染", "answers": [ "おせん" ], "comment": "(n) pollution/contamination" },
		{ "question": "池", "answers": [ "いけ" ], "comment": "(n) pond" },
		{ "question": "汲む", "answers": [ "くむ" ], "comment": "(v5m) (1) to draw (water)/to ladle/to dip/to scoop/to pump/(2) to have a drink together/(3) to consider/to sympathize with" },
		{ "question": "決", "answers": [ "けつ" ], "comment": "(n) decision/vote" },
		{ "question": "決して", "answers": [ "けっして" ], "comment": "(adv) never/by no means" },
		{ "question": "決まり", "answers": [ "きまり" ], "comment": "(n) settlement/conclusion/regulation/rule/custom" },
		{ "question": "決める", "answers": [ "きめる" ], "comment": "(v1) to decide" },
		{ "question": "決る", "answers": [ "きまる" ], "comment": "(io) (v5r) to be decided/to be settled/to look good in (clothes)" },
		{ "question": "決勝", "answers": [ "けっしょう" ], "comment": "(n) decision of a contest/finals (in sports)" },
		{ "question": "決定", "answers": [ "けってい" ], "comment": "(n) decision/determination" },
		{ "question": "決心", "answers": [ "けっしん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) determination/resolution" },
		{ "question": "決意", "answers": [ "けつい" ], "comment": "(n) decision/determination" },
		{ "question": "決断", "answers": [ "けつだん" ], "comment": "(n) decision/determination" },
		{ "question": "決算", "answers": [ "けっさん" ], "comment": "(n) balance sheet/settlement of accounts" },
		{ "question": "決行", "answers": [ "けっこう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) doing (with resolve)/carrying out (i.e. a plan)" },
		{ "question": "決議", "answers": [ "けつぎ" ], "comment": "(n) resolution/vote/decision" },
		{ "question": "汽船", "answers": [ "きせん" ], "comment": "(n) steamship" },
		{ "question": "汽車", "answers": [ "きしゃ" ], "comment": "(n) train (steam)" },
		{ "question": "沈む", "answers": [ "しずむ" ], "comment": "(v5m) to sink/to feel depressed" },
		{ "question": "沈める", "answers": [ "しずめる" ], "comment": "(v1,vt) to sink/to submerge" },
		{ "question": "沈殿", "answers": [ "ちんでん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) precipitation/deposition/settlement (e.g. of sediment)" },
		{ "question": "沈没", "answers": [ "ちんぼつ" ], "comment": "(n) sinking/foundering" },
		{ "question": "沈黙", "answers": [ "ちんもく" ], "comment": "(n) silence/reticence" },
		{ "question": "沖", "answers": [ "おき" ], "comment": "(n) open sea" },
		{ "question": "没収", "answers": [ "ぼっしゅう" ], "comment": "(n) forfeited" },
		{ "question": "没落", "answers": [ "ぼつらく" ], "comment": "(n) ruin/fall/collapse" },
		{ "question": "河", "answers": [ "かわ" ], "comment": "(n) river/stream" },
		{ "question": "河川", "answers": [ "かせん" ], "comment": "(n) rivers" },
		{ "question": "沸かす", "answers": [ "わかす" ], "comment": "(v5s,vt) to boil/to heat" },
		{ "question": "沸く", "answers": [ "わく" ], "comment": "(v5k) to boil/to grow hot/to get excited/to gush forth" },
		{ "question": "沸騰", "answers": [ "ふっとう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) boiling/seething" },
		{ "question": "油", "answers": [ "あぶら" ], "comment": "(n) oil" },
		{ "question": "油断", "answers": [ "ゆだん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) negligence/unpreparedness" },
		{ "question": "油絵", "answers": [ "あぶらえ" ], "comment": "(n) oil painting" },
		{ "question": "治す", "answers": [ "なおす" ], "comment": "(v5s,vt) to cure/to heal/to fix/to correct/to repair" },
		{ "question": "治まる", "answers": [ "おさまる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to be at peace/to clamp down/to lessen (storm, terror, anger)" },
		{ "question": "治める", "answers": [ "おさめる" ], "comment": "(v1) (1) to govern/to manage/(2) to subdue" },
		{ "question": "治る", "answers": [ "なおる" ], "comment": "(v5r,vi) to be cured/to heal/to get mended/to get well/to be repaired/to be fixed" },
		{ "question": "治安", "answers": [ "ちあん" ], "comment": "(n) public order" },
		{ "question": "治療", "answers": [ "ちりょう" ], "comment": "(n) medical treatment" },
		{ "question": "沼", "answers": [ "ぬま" ], "comment": "(n,n-suf) swamp/bog/pond/lake" },
		{ "question": "沿う", "answers": [ "そう" ], "comment": "(v5u) to run along/to follow" },
		{ "question": "沿岸", "answers": [ "えんがん" ], "comment": "(n) coast/shore" },
		{ "question": "沿線", "answers": [ "えんせん" ], "comment": "(adj-no,n) along railway line" },
		{ "question": "泉", "answers": [ "いずみ" ], "comment": "(n) spring/fountain" },
		{ "question": "泊まる", "answers": [ "とまる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to stay at (e.g. hotel)" },
		{ "question": "泊める", "answers": [ "とめる" ], "comment": "(v1) to give shelter to/to lodge" },
		{ "question": "法", "answers": [ "ほう" ], "comment": "(n,n-suf) Act (law: the X Act)" },
		{ "question": "法則", "answers": [ "ほうそく" ], "comment": "(n) law/rule" },
		{ "question": "法学", "answers": [ "ほうがく" ], "comment": "(n) law/jurisprudence" },
		{ "question": "法廷", "answers": [ "ほうてい" ], "comment": "(n) courtroom" },
		{ "question": "法律", "answers": [ "ほうりつ" ], "comment": "(n) law" },
		{ "question": "法案", "answers": [ "ほうあん" ], "comment": "(n) bill (law)" },
		{ "question": "泡", "answers": [ "あわ" ], "comment": "(n) bubble/foam/froth/head on beer" },
		{ "question": "波", "answers": [ "なみ" ], "comment": "(n) wave" },
		{ "question": "泣く", "answers": [ "なく" ], "comment": "(v5k) to cry/to sing (bird)" },
		{ "question": "泥", "answers": [ "どろ" ], "comment": "(n) mud" },
		{ "question": "泥棒", "answers": [ "どろぼう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) thief/burglar/robber/theft" },
		{ "question": "注", "answers": [ "ちゅう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) annotation/explanatory note" },
		{ "question": "注ぐ", "answers": [ "そそぐ","つぐ" ], "comment": "(v5g) to pour (into)/to irrigate/to pay/to fill/to feed (e.g. a fire)" },
		{ "question": "注す", "answers": [ "さす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to pour (drink)/to serve (drinks)" },
		{ "question": "注射", "answers": [ "ちゅうしゃ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) injection" },
		{ "question": "注意", "answers": [ "ちゅうい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) caution/being careful/attention (heed)/warning/advice" },
		{ "question": "注文", "answers": [ "ちゅうもん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) order/request" },
		{ "question": "注目", "answers": [ "ちゅうもく" ], "comment": "(n,vs) notice/attention/observation" },
		{ "question": "泳ぎ", "answers": [ "およぎ" ], "comment": "(n) swimming" },
		{ "question": "泳ぐ", "answers": [ "およぐ" ], "comment": "(v5g) to swim" },
		{ "question": "洋品店", "answers": [ "ようひんてん" ], "comment": "(n) shop which handles Western-style apparel and accessories" },
		{ "question": "洋服", "answers": [ "ようふく" ], "comment": "(n) Western-style clothes" },
		{ "question": "洋風", "answers": [ "ようふう" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) western style" },
		{ "question": "洒落", "answers": [ "しゃれ" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) joke/pun/witticism" },
		{ "question": "洒落る", "answers": [ "しゃれる" ], "comment": "(v1) to joke/to play on words/to dress stylishly" },
		{ "question": "洗う", "answers": [ "あらう" ], "comment": "(v5u) to wash" },
		{ "question": "洗剤", "answers": [ "せんざい" ], "comment": "(n) detergent/washing material" },
		{ "question": "洗濯", "answers": [ "せんたく" ], "comment": "(n,vs) washing/laundry" },
		{ "question": "洗面", "answers": [ "せんめん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) wash up (one's face)/have a wash" },
		{ "question": "津波", "answers": [ "つなみ" ], "comment": "(n) tsunami/tidal wave" },
		{ "question": "洪水", "answers": [ "こうずい" ], "comment": "(n) flood" },
		{ "question": "活力", "answers": [ "かつりょく" ], "comment": "(n) vitality/energy" },
		{ "question": "活動", "answers": [ "かつどう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) action/activity" },
		{ "question": "活字", "answers": [ "かつじ" ], "comment": "(n) printing type" },
		{ "question": "活気", "answers": [ "かっき" ], "comment": "(n) energy/liveliness" },
		{ "question": "活用", "answers": [ "かつよう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) conjugation/practical use" },
		{ "question": "活発", "answers": [ "かっぱつ" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) vigor/active" },
		{ "question": "活躍", "answers": [ "かつやく" ], "comment": "(n) activity" },
		{ "question": "派手", "answers": [ "はで" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) showy/loud/gay/flashy/gaudy" },
		{ "question": "派遣", "answers": [ "はけん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) dispatch/send" },
		{ "question": "流し", "answers": [ "ながし" ], "comment": "(n) sink" },
		{ "question": "流す", "answers": [ "ながす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to drain/to float/to shed (blood, tears)/to cruise (e.g. taxi)" },
		{ "question": "流れ", "answers": [ "ながれ" ], "comment": "(n) stream/current" },
		{ "question": "流れる", "answers": [ "ながれる" ], "comment": "(v1) to stream/to flow/to run (ink)/to be washed away" },
		{ "question": "流域", "answers": [ "りゅういき" ], "comment": "(n) (river) basin" },
		{ "question": "流石", "answers": [ "さすが" ], "comment": "(adj-na,adv,n) (uk) clever/adept/good/expectations/as one would expect" },
		{ "question": "流行", "answers": [ "りゅうこう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) fashionable/fad/in vogue/prevailing" },
		{ "question": "流行る", "answers": [ "はやる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to flourish/to thrive/to be popular/to come into fashion" },
		{ "question": "流通", "answers": [ "りゅうつう" ], "comment": "(n) circulation of money or goods/flow of water or air/distribution" },
		{ "question": "浅い", "answers": [ "あさい" ], "comment": "(adj) shallow/superficial" },
		{ "question": "浜", "answers": [ "はま" ], "comment": "(n) beach/seashore" },
		{ "question": "浜辺", "answers": [ "はまべ" ], "comment": "(n) beach/foreshore" },
		{ "question": "浪費", "answers": [ "ろうひ" ], "comment": "(n) waste/extravagance" },
		{ "question": "浮かべる", "answers": [ "うかべる" ], "comment": "(v1) to float/to express/to look (sad, glad)" },
		{ "question": "浮く", "answers": [ "うく" ], "comment": "(v5k) to float/to become merry/to become loose" },
		{ "question": "浮ぶ", "answers": [ "うかぶ" ], "comment": "(io) (v5b) to float/to rise to surface/to come to mind" },
		{ "question": "浮力", "answers": [ "ふりょく" ], "comment": "(n) buoyancy/floating power" },
		{ "question": "浮気", "answers": [ "うわき" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) flighty/fickle/wanton/unfaithful" },
		{ "question": "浴びる", "answers": [ "あびる" ], "comment": "(v1) to bathe/to bask in the sun/to shower" },
		{ "question": "浴室", "answers": [ "よくしつ" ], "comment": "(n) bathroom/bath" },
		{ "question": "浴衣", "answers": [ "ゆかた" ], "comment": "(n) bathrobe/informal summer kimono/yukata" },
		{ "question": "海", "answers": [ "うみ" ], "comment": "(n) sea/beach" },
		{ "question": "海外", "answers": [ "かいがい" ], "comment": "(n) foreign/abroad/overseas" },
		{ "question": "海岸", "answers": [ "かいがん" ], "comment": "(n) coast/beach" },
		{ "question": "海峡", "answers": [ "かいきょう" ], "comment": "(n) channel" },
		{ "question": "海抜", "answers": [ "かいばつ" ], "comment": "(n) height above sea level" },
		{ "question": "海水浴", "answers": [ "かいすいよく" ], "comment": "(n) sea bathing/seawater bath" },
		{ "question": "海洋", "answers": [ "かいよう" ], "comment": "(n) ocean" },
		{ "question": "海流", "answers": [ "かいりゅう" ], "comment": "(n) ocean current" },
		{ "question": "海路", "answers": [ "かいろ" ], "comment": "(n-t) sea route" },
		{ "question": "海運", "answers": [ "かいうん" ], "comment": "(n) maritime/marine transportation" },
		{ "question": "浸ける", "answers": [ "つける" ], "comment": "(v1) to dip in/to soak" },
		{ "question": "浸す", "answers": [ "ひたす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to soak/to dip/to drench" },
		{ "question": "消える", "answers": [ "きえる" ], "comment": "(v1) to go out/to vanish/to disappear" },
		{ "question": "消しゴム", "answers": [ "けしゴム" ], "comment": "(n) eraser/India rubber" },
		{ "question": "消す", "answers": [ "けす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to erase/to delete/to turn off power" },
		{ "question": "消化", "answers": [ "しょうか" ], "comment": "(n,vs) digestion" },
		{ "question": "消去", "answers": [ "しょうきょ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) elimination/erasing/dying out/melting away" },
		{ "question": "消息", "answers": [ "しょうそく" ], "comment": "(n) news/letter/circumstances" },
		{ "question": "消極的", "answers": [ "しょうきょくてき" ], "comment": "(adj-na) passive" },
		{ "question": "消毒", "answers": [ "しょうどく" ], "comment": "(n,vs) disinfection/sterilization" },
		{ "question": "消耗", "answers": [ "しょうもう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) exhaustion/consumption" },
		{ "question": "消費", "answers": [ "しょうひ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) consumption/expenditure" },
		{ "question": "消防", "answers": [ "しょうぼう" ], "comment": "(n) fire fighting/fire department" },
		{ "question": "消防署", "answers": [ "しょうぼうしょ" ], "comment": "(n) fire station" },
		{ "question": "涙", "answers": [ "なみだ" ], "comment": "(n) tear" },
		{ "question": "液", "answers": [ "えき" ], "comment": "(n,n-suf) liquid/fluid" },
		{ "question": "液体", "answers": [ "えきたい" ], "comment": "(n) liquid/fluid" },
		{ "question": "涼しい", "answers": [ "すずしい" ], "comment": "(adj) cool/refreshing" },
		{ "question": "涼む", "answers": [ "すずむ" ], "comment": "(v5m) to cool oneself/to cool off/to enjoy evening cool" },
		{ "question": "淑やか", "answers": [ "しとやか" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) graceful" },
		{ "question": "淡水", "answers": [ "たんすい" ], "comment": "(n) fresh water" },
		{ "question": "深い", "answers": [ "ふかい" ], "comment": "(adj) deep/profound/thick/close" },
		{ "question": "深まる", "answers": [ "ふかまる" ], "comment": "(v5r,vi) to deepen/to heighten/to intensify" },
		{ "question": "深める", "answers": [ "ふかめる" ], "comment": "(v1,vt) to deepen/to heighten/to intensify" },
		{ "question": "深刻", "answers": [ "しんこく" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) serious" },
		{ "question": "深夜", "answers": [ "しんや" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n-t) late at night" },
		{ "question": "混ざる", "answers": [ "まざる" ], "comment": "(v5r,vi) to be mixed/to be blended with/to associate with/to mingle with/to join" },
		{ "question": "混じる", "answers": [ "まじる" ], "comment": "(v5r,vi) to be mixed/to be blended with/to associate with/to mingle with/to interest/to join" },
		{ "question": "混ぜる", "answers": [ "まぜる" ], "comment": "(v1) to mix/to stir" },
		{ "question": "混乱", "answers": [ "こんらん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) disorder/chaos/confusion/mayhem" },
		{ "question": "混合", "answers": [ "こんごう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) mixing/mixture" },
		{ "question": "混同", "answers": [ "こんどう" ], "comment": "(n) confusion/mixing/merger" },
		{ "question": "混血", "answers": [ "こんけつ" ], "comment": "(n) mixed race/mixed parentage" },
		{ "question": "混雑", "answers": [ "こんざつ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) confusion/congestion" },
		{ "question": "添う", "answers": [ "そう" ], "comment": "(v5u) to accompany/to become married/to comply with" },
		{ "question": "添える", "answers": [ "そえる" ], "comment": "(v1,vt) to add to/to attach/to append/to accompany/to garnish/to imitate/to annex" },
		{ "question": "清い", "answers": [ "きよい" ], "comment": "(adj) clear/pure/noble" },
		{ "question": "清らか", "answers": [ "きよらか" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) clean/pure/chaste" },
		{ "question": "清掃", "answers": [ "せいそう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) cleaning" },
		{ "question": "清書", "answers": [ "せいしょ" ], "comment": "(n) clean copy" },
		{ "question": "清潔", "answers": [ "せいけつ" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) clean" },
		{ "question": "清濁", "answers": [ "せいだく" ], "comment": "(n) good and evil/purity and impurity" },
		{ "question": "清純", "answers": [ "せいじゅん" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) purity/innocence" },
		{ "question": "渇く", "answers": [ "かわく" ], "comment": "(v5k) to be thirsty" },
		{ "question": "済ます", "answers": [ "すます" ], "comment": "(v5s) (1) to finish/to get it over with/to conclude/(2) to settle/to pay back/(3) to get along (without something)" },
		{ "question": "済ませる", "answers": [ "すませる" ], "comment": "(v1) to be finished" },
		{ "question": "済む", "answers": [ "すむ" ], "comment": "(v5m) to finish/to end/to be completed" },
		{ "question": "渋滞", "answers": [ "じゅうたい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) congestion (e.g. traffic)/delay/stagnation" },
		{ "question": "渚", "answers": [ "なぎさ" ], "comment": "(n) water's edge/beach/shore" },
		{ "question": "減らす", "answers": [ "へらす" ], "comment": "(v5s,vt) to abate/to decrease/to diminish/to shorten" },
		{ "question": "減る", "answers": [ "へる" ], "comment": "(v5r,vi) to decrease (in size or number)/to diminish/to abate" },
		{ "question": "減少", "answers": [ "げんしょう" ], "comment": "(n) decrease/reduction/decline" },
		{ "question": "渡す", "answers": [ "わたす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to pass over/to hand over" },
		{ "question": "渡り鳥", "answers": [ "わたりどり" ], "comment": "(n) migratory bird/bird of passage" },
		{ "question": "渡る", "answers": [ "わたる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to cross over/to go across" },
		{ "question": "渦", "answers": [ "うず" ], "comment": "(n) swirl" },
		{ "question": "温かい", "answers": [ "あたたかい" ], "comment": "(adj) warm/mild/genial" },
		{ "question": "温まる", "answers": [ "あたたまる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to warm oneself/to sun oneself/to warm up/to get warm" },
		{ "question": "温める", "answers": [ "あたためる" ], "comment": "(v1) to warm/to heat" },
		{ "question": "温和", "answers": [ "おんわ" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) gentle/mild/moderate" },
		{ "question": "温室", "answers": [ "おんしつ" ], "comment": "(n) greenhouse" },
		{ "question": "温帯", "answers": [ "おんたい" ], "comment": "(n) temperate zone" },
		{ "question": "温度", "answers": [ "おんど" ], "comment": "(n) temperature" },
		{ "question": "温暖", "answers": [ "おんだん" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) warmth" },
		{ "question": "温泉", "answers": [ "おんせん" ], "comment": "(n) spa/hot spring/onsen" },
		{ "question": "測る", "answers": [ "はかる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to measure/to weigh/to survey/to time (sound, gauge, estimate)" },
		{ "question": "測定", "answers": [ "そくてい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) measurement" },
		{ "question": "測量", "answers": [ "そくりょう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) measurement/surveying" },
		{ "question": "港", "answers": [ "みなと" ], "comment": "(n) harbour/port" },
		{ "question": "湖", "answers": [ "みずうみ" ], "comment": "(n) lake" },
		{ "question": "湧く", "answers": [ "わく" ], "comment": "(v5k) to boil/to grow hot/to get excited/to gush forth" },
		{ "question": "湯", "answers": [ "ゆ" ], "comment": "(n) hot water" },
		{ "question": "湯気", "answers": [ "ゆげ" ], "comment": "(n) steam/vapour" },
		{ "question": "湯飲み", "answers": [ "ゆのみ" ], "comment": "(n) teacup" },
		{ "question": "湾", "answers": [ "わん" ], "comment": "(n,n-suf) bay/gulf/inlet" },
		{ "question": "湿る", "answers": [ "しめる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to be wet/to become wet/to be damp" },
		{ "question": "湿度", "answers": [ "しつど" ], "comment": "(n) level of humidity" },
		{ "question": "湿気", "answers": [ "しっき","しっけ" ], "comment": "(n) moisture/humidity/dampness" },
		{ "question": "湿気る", "answers": [ "しける" ], "comment": "(v5r) to be damp/to be moist" },
		{ "question": "満たす", "answers": [ "みたす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to satisfy/to ingratiate/to fill/to fulfill" },
		{ "question": "満ちる", "answers": [ "みちる" ], "comment": "(v1) to be full/to rise (tide)/to mature/to expire" },
		{ "question": "満員", "answers": [ "まんいん" ], "comment": "(n) full house/no vacancy/sold out/standing room only/full (of people)/crowded" },
		{ "question": "満場", "answers": [ "まんじょう" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n-t) unanimous/whole audience" },
		{ "question": "満月", "answers": [ "まんげつ" ], "comment": "(n) full moon" },
		{ "question": "満点", "answers": [ "まんてん" ], "comment": "(n) perfect score" },
		{ "question": "満足", "answers": [ "まんぞく" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n,vs) satisfaction" },
		{ "question": "源", "answers": [ "みなもと" ], "comment": "(n) source/origin" },
		{ "question": "準じる", "answers": [ "じゅんじる" ], "comment": "(v1) to follow/to conform/to apply to" },
		{ "question": "準備", "answers": [ "じゅんび" ], "comment": "(n,vs) preparation/arrangements/provision/reserve" },
		{ "question": "準急", "answers": [ "じゅんきゅう" ], "comment": "(n) local express (train, slower than an express)" },
		{ "question": "溜まり", "answers": [ "たまり" ], "comment": "collected things/gathering place/arrears" },
		{ "question": "溜まる", "answers": [ "たまる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to collect/to gather/to save" },
		{ "question": "溜める", "answers": [ "ためる" ], "comment": "(v1) to amass/to accumulate" },
		{ "question": "溜息", "answers": [ "ためいき" ], "comment": "(io) (n) (uk) a sigh" },
		{ "question": "溝", "answers": [ "どぶ","みぞ" ], "comment": "(n) ditch/drain/gutter/gap" },
		{ "question": "溶かす", "answers": [ "とかす" ], "comment": "(v5s,vt) to melt/to dissolve" },
		{ "question": "溶く", "answers": [ "とく" ], "comment": "(v5k,vt) to dissolve (paint)" },
		{ "question": "溶ける", "answers": [ "とける" ], "comment": "(v1,vi) to melt/to thaw/to fuse/to dissolve" },
		{ "question": "溶け込む", "answers": [ "とけこむ" ], "comment": "(v5m) to melt into" },
		{ "question": "溶岩", "answers": [ "ようがん" ], "comment": "(n) lava" },
		{ "question": "溶液", "answers": [ "ようえき" ], "comment": "(n) solution (liquid)" },
		{ "question": "溺れる", "answers": [ "おぼれる" ], "comment": "(v1) to be drowned/to indulge in" },
		{ "question": "滅びる", "answers": [ "ほろびる" ], "comment": "(v1) to be ruined/to go under/to perish/to be destroyed" },
		{ "question": "滅ぼす", "answers": [ "ほろぼす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to destroy/to overthrow/to wreck/to ruin" },
		{ "question": "滅亡", "answers": [ "めつぼう" ], "comment": "(n) downfall/ruin/collapse/destruction" },
		{ "question": "滅多に", "answers": [ "めったに" ], "comment": "(adv) rarely (with neg. verb)/seldom" },
		{ "question": "滑らか", "answers": [ "なめらか" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) smoothness/glassiness" },
		{ "question": "滑る", "answers": [ "すべる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to glide/to slide/to slip" },
		{ "question": "滑稽", "answers": [ "こっけい" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) funny/humorous/comical/laughable/ridiculous/joking" },
		{ "question": "滝", "answers": [ "たき" ], "comment": "(n) waterfall" },
		{ "question": "滞る", "answers": [ "とどこおる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to stagnate/to be delayed" },
		{ "question": "滞在", "answers": [ "たいざい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) stay/sojourn" },
		{ "question": "滞納", "answers": [ "たいのう" ], "comment": "(n) non-payment/default" },
		{ "question": "滲む", "answers": [ "にじむ" ], "comment": "(v5m) to run/to blur/to spread/to blot/to ooze" },
		{ "question": "漁師", "answers": [ "りょうし" ], "comment": "(n) fisherman" },
		{ "question": "漁村", "answers": [ "ぎょそん" ], "comment": "(n) fishing village" },
		{ "question": "漁業", "answers": [ "ぎょぎょう" ], "comment": "(n) fishing (industry)" },
		{ "question": "漁船", "answers": [ "ぎょせん" ], "comment": "(n) fishing boat" },
		{ "question": "漂う", "answers": [ "ただよう" ], "comment": "(v5u) to drift about/to float/to hang in air" },
		{ "question": "漏らす", "answers": [ "もらす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to let leak/to reveal" },
		{ "question": "漏る", "answers": [ "もる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to leak/to run out" },
		{ "question": "漏れる", "answers": [ "もれる" ], "comment": "(v1) to leak out/to escape/to come through/to shine through/to filter out/to be omitted" },
		{ "question": "演じる", "answers": [ "えんじる" ], "comment": "(v1) to perform (a play)/to play (a part)/to act (a part)/to commit (a blunder)" },
		{ "question": "演ずる", "answers": [ "えんずる" ], "comment": "(v5z) to perform/to play" },
		{ "question": "演出", "answers": [ "えんしゅつ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) production (e.g. play)/direction" },
		{ "question": "演劇", "answers": [ "えんげき" ], "comment": "(n) play (theatrical)" },
		{ "question": "演奏", "answers": [ "えんそう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) musical performance" },
		{ "question": "演技", "answers": [ "えんぎ" ], "comment": "(n) acting/performance" },
		{ "question": "演説", "answers": [ "えんぜつ" ], "comment": "(n) speech/address" },
		{ "question": "漠然", "answers": [ "ばくぜん" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) obscure/vague/equivocal" },
		{ "question": "漢和", "answers": [ "かんわ" ], "comment": "(n) Chinese Character-Japanese (e.g. dictionary)" },
		{ "question": "漢字", "answers": [ "かんじ" ], "comment": "(n) Chinese characters/kanji" },
		{ "question": "漢語", "answers": [ "かんご" ], "comment": "(n) Chinese word/Sino-Japanese word" },
		{ "question": "漫画", "answers": [ "まんが" ], "comment": "(n) comic/cartoon" },
		{ "question": "漬ける", "answers": [ "つける" ], "comment": "(v1) to soak/to moisten/to pickle" },
		{ "question": "漸く", "answers": [ "ようやく" ], "comment": "(adv) gradually/finally/hardly" },
		{ "question": "潜る", "answers": [ "もぐる" ], "comment": "(v5r) (1) to drive/to pass through/(2) to evade/to hide/(3) to dive (into or under water)/to go underground" },
		{ "question": "潜入", "answers": [ "せんにゅう" ], "comment": "(n) infiltration/sneaking in" },
		{ "question": "潜水", "answers": [ "せんすい" ], "comment": "(n) diving" },
		{ "question": "潤う", "answers": [ "うるおう" ], "comment": "(v5u) to be moist/to be damp/to get wet/to profit by/to be watered/to receive benefits/to favor/to charm/to steepen" },
		{ "question": "潮", "answers": [ "しお" ], "comment": "(n) tide/ebb and flood/salt water/opportunity" },
		{ "question": "潰す", "answers": [ "つぶす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to smash/to waste" },
		{ "question": "潰れる", "answers": [ "つぶれる" ], "comment": "(v1) to be smashed/to go bankrupt" },
		{ "question": "澄ます", "answers": [ "すます" ], "comment": "(v5s) to clear/to make clear/to be unruffled/to look unconcerned/to look demure/look prim/put on airs" },
		{ "question": "澄む", "answers": [ "すむ" ], "comment": "(v5m) to clear (e.g. weather)/to become transparent" },
		{ "question": "激しい", "answers": [ "はげしい" ], "comment": "(adj) violent/vehement/intense/furious/tempestuous" },
		{ "question": "激励", "answers": [ "げきれい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) encouragement" },
		{ "question": "激増", "answers": [ "げきぞう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) sudden increase" },
		{ "question": "濁る", "answers": [ "にごる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to become muddy/to get impure" },
		{ "question": "濃い", "answers": [ "こい" ], "comment": "(adj) thick (as of color, liquid)/dense/strong" },
		{ "question": "濃度", "answers": [ "のうど" ], "comment": "(n) concentration/brightness" },
		{ "question": "濠", "answers": [ "ほり" ], "comment": "(n) moat" },
		{ "question": "濡らす", "answers": [ "ぬらす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to wet/to soak/to dip" },
		{ "question": "濡れる", "answers": [ "ぬれる" ], "comment": "(v1) to get wet" },
		{ "question": "濫用", "answers": [ "らんよう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) abuse/misuse/misappropriation/using to excess" },
		{ "question": "濯ぐ", "answers": [ "すすぐ","ゆすぐ" ], "comment": "(v5g) to rinse/to wash out" },
		{ "question": "瀬戸物", "answers": [ "せともの" ], "comment": "(n) earthenware/crockery/china" },
		{ "question": "灌漑", "answers": [ "かんがい" ], "comment": "(n) irrigation" },
		{ "question": "火", "answers": [ "ひ" ], "comment": "(n,n-suf) fire/flame/blaze" },
		{ "question": "火事", "answers": [ "かじ" ], "comment": "(n) fire/conflagration" },
		{ "question": "火傷", "answers": [ "やけど" ], "comment": "(n) burn/scald" },
		{ "question": "火口", "answers": [ "かこう" ], "comment": "(n) a burner/origin of a fire" },
		{ "question": "火山", "answers": [ "かざん" ], "comment": "(n) volcano" },
		{ "question": "火星", "answers": [ "かせい" ], "comment": "(n) Mars (planet)" },
		{ "question": "火曜", "answers": [ "かよう" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n) (abbr) Tuesday" },
		{ "question": "火曜日", "answers": [ "かようび" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n) Tuesday" },
		{ "question": "火災", "answers": [ "かさい" ], "comment": "(n) conflagration/fire" },
		{ "question": "火花", "answers": [ "ひばな" ], "comment": "(n) spark" },
		{ "question": "灯", "answers": [ "ひ" ], "comment": "(n) light" },
		{ "question": "灯台", "answers": [ "とうだい" ], "comment": "(n) lighthouse" },
		{ "question": "灯油", "answers": [ "とうゆ" ], "comment": "(n) lamp oil/kerosene" },
		{ "question": "灰", "answers": [ "はい" ], "comment": "(n) ash" },
		{ "question": "灰皿", "answers": [ "はいざら" ], "comment": "(n) ashtray" },
		{ "question": "灰色", "answers": [ "はいいろ" ], "comment": "(n) grey/gray/ashen" },
		{ "question": "災害", "answers": [ "さいがい" ], "comment": "(n) calamity/disaster/misfortune" },
		{ "question": "災難", "answers": [ "さいなん" ], "comment": "(n) calamity/misfortune" },
		{ "question": "炊く", "answers": [ "たく" ], "comment": "(v5k) to boil/to cook" },
		{ "question": "炊事", "answers": [ "すいじ" ], "comment": "(n) cooking/culinary arts" },
		{ "question": "炎", "answers": [ "ほのお" ], "comment": "(n) flame" },
		{ "question": "炒める", "answers": [ "いためる" ], "comment": "(v1) to stir-fry" },
		{ "question": "炭素", "answers": [ "たんそ" ], "comment": "(n) carbon (C)" },
		{ "question": "炭鉱", "answers": [ "たんこう" ], "comment": "(n) coal mine/coal pit" },
		{ "question": "点", "answers": [ "てん" ], "comment": "(n,n-suf) spot/mark/point/dot" },
		{ "question": "点々", "answers": [ "てんてん" ], "comment": "(adv,n) here and there/little by little/sporadically/scattered in drops/dot/spot" },
		{ "question": "点く", "answers": [ "つく" ], "comment": "(v5k) to catch fire/(electricity) comes on" },
		{ "question": "点ける", "answers": [ "つける" ], "comment": "(v1) (uk) to turn on/to switch on/to light up" },
		{ "question": "点数", "answers": [ "てんすう" ], "comment": "(n) marks/points/score/runs/number of items/credits" },
		{ "question": "点検", "answers": [ "てんけん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) inspection/examination/checking" },
		{ "question": "点線", "answers": [ "てんせん" ], "comment": "(n) dotted line/perforated line" },
		{ "question": "為", "answers": [ "ため" ], "comment": "(n) good/advantage/benefit/welfare/sake/to/in order to/because of/as a result of" },
		{ "question": "為す", "answers": [ "なす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to accomplish/to do" },
		{ "question": "為る", "answers": [ "する","なる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to change/to be of use/to reach to" },
		{ "question": "為替", "answers": [ "かわせ" ], "comment": "(n) money order/exchange" },
		{ "question": "焚く", "answers": [ "たく" ], "comment": "(v5k) to burn/to kindle/to build a fire" },
		{ "question": "焚火", "answers": [ "たきび" ], "comment": "(n) (open) fire" },
		{ "question": "無", "answers": [ "ぶ","む" ], "comment": "(n) nothing/naught/nil/zero" },
		{ "question": "無い", "answers": [ "ない" ], "comment": "(adj) there isn't/doesn't have" },
		{ "question": "無くす", "answers": [ "なくす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to lose something/to get rid of" },
		{ "question": "無くなる", "answers": [ "なくなる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to disappear/to get lost" },
		{ "question": "無し", "answers": [ "なし" ], "comment": "(n,n-suf) without" },
		{ "question": "無事", "answers": [ "ぶじ" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) safety/peace/quietness" },
		{ "question": "無効", "answers": [ "むこう" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) invalid/no effect/unavailable" },
		{ "question": "無口", "answers": [ "むくち" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) reticence" },
		{ "question": "無地", "answers": [ "むじ" ], "comment": "(n) plain/unfigured" },
		{ "question": "無念", "answers": [ "むねん" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) chagrin/regret" },
		{ "question": "無意味", "answers": [ "むいみ" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) nonsense/no meaning" },
		{ "question": "無数", "answers": [ "むすう" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) countless number/infinite number" },
		{ "question": "無料", "answers": [ "むりょう" ], "comment": "(adj-no,n) free/no charge" },
		{ "question": "無断", "answers": [ "むだん" ], "comment": "(n) without permission/without notice" },
		{ "question": "無沙汰", "answers": [ "ぶさた" ], "comment": "(n) neglecting to stay in contact" },
		{ "question": "無理", "answers": [ "むり" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n,vs) unreasonable/impossible/overdoing" },
		{ "question": "無用", "answers": [ "むよう" ], "comment": "(adj-na,adj-no,n) useless/futility/needlessness/unnecessariness" },
		{ "question": "無知", "answers": [ "むち" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) ignorance" },
		{ "question": "無礼", "answers": [ "ぶれい" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) impolite/rude" },
		{ "question": "無線", "answers": [ "むせん" ], "comment": "(n) wireless/radio" },
		{ "question": "無能", "answers": [ "むのう" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) inefficiency/incompetence" },
		{ "question": "無茶", "answers": [ "むちゃ" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) absurd/unreasonable/excessive/rash/absurdity/nonsense" },
		{ "question": "無茶苦茶", "answers": [ "むちゃくちゃ" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) (uk) confused/jumbled/mixed up/unreasonable" },
		{ "question": "無視", "answers": [ "むし" ], "comment": "(n,vs) disregard/ignore" },
		{ "question": "無言", "answers": [ "むごん" ], "comment": "(n) silence" },
		{ "question": "無論", "answers": [ "むろん" ], "comment": "(adv) of course/naturally" },
		{ "question": "無邪気", "answers": [ "むじゃき" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) innocence/simple-mindedness" },
		{ "question": "無闇に", "answers": [ "むやみに" ], "comment": "(uk) unreasonably/absurdly/recklessly/indiscreetly/at random" },
		{ "question": "無限", "answers": [ "むげん" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) infinite" },
		{ "question": "無難", "answers": [ "ぶなん" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) safety/security" },
		{ "question": "無駄", "answers": [ "むだ" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) futility/uselessness" },
		{ "question": "無駄遣い", "answers": [ "むだづかい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) waste money on/squander money on/flog a dead horse" },
		{ "question": "焦がす", "answers": [ "こがす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to burn/to scorch/to singe/to char" },
		{ "question": "焦げる", "answers": [ "こげる" ], "comment": "(v1,vi) to burn/to be burned" },
		{ "question": "焦げ茶", "answers": [ "こげちゃ" ], "comment": "(n) black tea" },
		{ "question": "焦る", "answers": [ "あせる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to be in a hurry/to be impatient" },
		{ "question": "焦点", "answers": [ "しょうてん" ], "comment": "(n) focus/point" },
		{ "question": "焼く", "answers": [ "やく" ], "comment": "(v5k) to bake/to grill" },
		{ "question": "焼ける", "answers": [ "やける" ], "comment": "(v1,vi) to burn/to be roasted/to be sunburnt" },
		{ "question": "煉瓦", "answers": [ "れんが" ], "comment": "(n) brick" },
		{ "question": "煌々と", "answers": [ "こうこうと" ], "comment": "brilliantly/brightly" },
		{ "question": "煎る", "answers": [ "いる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to parch/to fry/to fire/to broil/to roast/to boil down (in oil)" },
		{ "question": "煙", "answers": [ "けむり" ], "comment": "(n) smoke/fumes" },
		{ "question": "煙い", "answers": [ "けむい" ], "comment": "(adj) smoky" },
		{ "question": "煙たい", "answers": [ "けむたい" ], "comment": "(adj) smoky/feeling awkward" },
		{ "question": "煙る", "answers": [ "けむる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to smoke (e.g. fire)" },
		{ "question": "煙突", "answers": [ "えんとつ" ], "comment": "(n) chimney" },
		{ "question": "照らす", "answers": [ "てらす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to shine on/to illuminate" },
		{ "question": "照り返す", "answers": [ "てりかえす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to reflect/to throw back light" },
		{ "question": "照る", "answers": [ "てる" ], "comment": "(v5r,vi) to shine" },
		{ "question": "照合", "answers": [ "しょうごう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) collation/comparison" },
		{ "question": "照明", "answers": [ "しょうめい" ], "comment": "(n) illumination" },
		{ "question": "煩わしい", "answers": [ "わずらわしい" ], "comment": "(adj) troublesome/annoying/complicated" },
		{ "question": "煮える", "answers": [ "にえる" ], "comment": "(v1,vi) to boil/to cook/to be cooked" },
		{ "question": "煮る", "answers": [ "にる" ], "comment": "(v1,vt) to boil/to cook" },
		{ "question": "熟語", "answers": [ "じゅくご" ], "comment": "(n) idiom/idiomatic phrase/kanji compound" },
		{ "question": "熱", "answers": [ "ねつ" ], "comment": "(n,n-suf) fever/temperature" },
		{ "question": "熱い", "answers": [ "あつい" ], "comment": "(adj) hot (thing)" },
		{ "question": "熱する", "answers": [ "ねっする" ], "comment": "(vs-s) to heat" },
		{ "question": "熱中", "answers": [ "ねっちゅう" ], "comment": "(n) nuts!/enthusiasm/zeal/mania" },
		{ "question": "熱帯", "answers": [ "ねったい" ], "comment": "(n) tropics" },
		{ "question": "熱心", "answers": [ "ねっしん" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) zeal/enthusiasm" },
		{ "question": "熱意", "answers": [ "ねつい" ], "comment": "(n) zeal/enthusiasm" },
		{ "question": "熱湯", "answers": [ "ねっとう" ], "comment": "(n) boiling water" },
		{ "question": "熱量", "answers": [ "ねつりょう" ], "comment": "(n) temperature" },
		{ "question": "燃える", "answers": [ "もえる" ], "comment": "(v1) to burn" },
		{ "question": "燃やす", "answers": [ "もやす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to burn" },
		{ "question": "燃料", "answers": [ "ねんりょう" ], "comment": "(n) fuel" },
		{ "question": "燃焼", "answers": [ "ねんしょう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) burning/combustion" },
		{ "question": "爆弾", "answers": [ "ばくだん" ], "comment": "(n) bomb" },
		{ "question": "爆発", "answers": [ "ばくはつ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) explosion/detonation/eruption" },
		{ "question": "爆破", "answers": [ "ばくは" ], "comment": "(n,vs) blast/explosion/blow up" },
		{ "question": "爪", "answers": [ "つめ" ], "comment": "(n) fingernail or toenail/claw/talon/hoof" },
		{ "question": "父", "answers": [ "ちち" ], "comment": "(n) (hum) father" },
		{ "question": "父母", "answers": [ "ふぼ" ], "comment": "(n) father and mother/parents" },
		{ "question": "父親", "answers": [ "ちちおや" ], "comment": "(n) father" },
		{ "question": "片付く", "answers": [ "かたづく" ], "comment": "(v5k) to put in order/to dispose of/to solve/to finish/to get married" },
		{ "question": "片付け", "answers": [ "かたづけ" ], "comment": "(n) tidying up/finishing" },
		{ "question": "片付ける", "answers": [ "かたづける" ], "comment": "(v1) to tidy up/to put in order/to straighten up/to put away" },
		{ "question": "片仮名", "answers": [ "かたかな" ], "comment": "(n) katakana" },
		{ "question": "片寄る", "answers": [ "かたよる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to be one-sided/to incline/to be partial/to be prejudiced/to lean/to be biased" },
		{ "question": "片言", "answers": [ "かたこと" ], "comment": "(n) brief remark/few words" },
		{ "question": "片道", "answers": [ "かたみち" ], "comment": "(n) one-way (trip)" },
		{ "question": "版", "answers": [ "はん" ], "comment": "(n) edition" },
		{ "question": "版画", "answers": [ "はんが" ], "comment": "(n) art print" },
		{ "question": "牛", "answers": [ "うし" ], "comment": "(n) cattle/cow" },
		{ "question": "牛乳", "answers": [ "ぎゅうにゅう" ], "comment": "(n) (cow's) milk" },
		{ "question": "牛肉", "answers": [ "ぎゅうにく" ], "comment": "(n) beef" },
		{ "question": "牧場", "answers": [ "ぼくじょう" ], "comment": "(n) (1) farm (livestock)/(2) pasture land/meadow/grazing land" },
		{ "question": "牧師", "answers": [ "ぼくし" ], "comment": "(n) pastor/minister/clergyman" },
		{ "question": "牧畜", "answers": [ "ぼくちく" ], "comment": "(n) stock-farming" },
		{ "question": "物", "answers": [ "もの" ], "comment": "(n) thing/object" },
		{ "question": "物事", "answers": [ "ものごと" ], "comment": "(n) things/everything" },
		{ "question": "物体", "answers": [ "ぶったい" ], "comment": "(n) (1) superior airs/air of importance/(2) overemphasis" },
		{ "question": "物価", "answers": [ "ぶっか" ], "comment": "(n) prices of commodities/prices (in general)" },
		{ "question": "物凄い", "answers": [ "ものすごい" ], "comment": "(adj) earth-shattering/staggering/to a very great extent" },
		{ "question": "物好き", "answers": [ "ものずき" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) (idle) curiosity" },
		{ "question": "物差し", "answers": [ "ものさし" ], "comment": "(n) ruler/measure" },
		{ "question": "物理", "answers": [ "ぶつり" ], "comment": "(n) physics" },
		{ "question": "物置", "answers": [ "ものおき" ], "comment": "(n) storage room" },
		{ "question": "物語", "answers": [ "ものがたり" ], "comment": "(n) tale/story/legend" },
		{ "question": "物語る", "answers": [ "ものがたる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to tell/to indicate" },
		{ "question": "物議", "answers": [ "ぶつぎ" ], "comment": "(n) public discussion (criticism)" },
		{ "question": "物資", "answers": [ "ぶっし" ], "comment": "(n) goods/materials" },
		{ "question": "物質", "answers": [ "ぶっしつ" ], "comment": "(n) material/substance" },
		{ "question": "物足りない", "answers": [ "ものたりない" ], "comment": "(adj) unsatisfied/unsatisfactory" },
		{ "question": "物音", "answers": [ "ものおと" ], "comment": "(n) sounds" },
		{ "question": "物騒", "answers": [ "ぶっそう" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) dangerous/disturbed/insecure" },
		{ "question": "特に", "answers": [ "とくに" ], "comment": "(adv) particularly/especially" },
		{ "question": "特別", "answers": [ "とくべつ" ], "comment": "(adj-na,adv,n) special" },
		{ "question": "特売", "answers": [ "とくばい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) special sale" },
		{ "question": "特定", "answers": [ "とくてい" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n,vs) specific/special/particular" },
		{ "question": "特徴", "answers": [ "とくちょう" ], "comment": "(n) feature/characteristic" },
		{ "question": "特急", "answers": [ "とっきゅう" ], "comment": "(n) limited express (train, faster than an express)" },
		{ "question": "特技", "answers": [ "とくぎ" ], "comment": "(n) special skill" },
		{ "question": "特有", "answers": [ "とくゆう" ], "comment": "(adj-na,adj-no,n) characteristic (of)/peculiar (to)" },
		{ "question": "特権", "answers": [ "とっけん" ], "comment": "(n) privilege/special right" },
		{ "question": "特殊", "answers": [ "とくしゅ" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) special/unique" },
		{ "question": "特派", "answers": [ "とくは" ], "comment": "(n,vs) send specially/special envoy" },
		{ "question": "特産", "answers": [ "とくさん" ], "comment": "(n) specialty/special product" },
		{ "question": "特色", "answers": [ "とくしょく" ], "comment": "(n) characteristic/feature" },
		{ "question": "特許", "answers": [ "とっきょ" ], "comment": "(n) special permission/patent" },
		{ "question": "特長", "answers": [ "とくちょう" ], "comment": "(n) forte/merit" },
		{ "question": "特集", "answers": [ "とくしゅう" ], "comment": "(n) feature (e.g. newspaper)/special edition/report" },
		{ "question": "犠牲", "answers": [ "ぎせい" ], "comment": "(n) sacrifice" },
		{ "question": "犬", "answers": [ "いぬ" ], "comment": "(n) dog" },
		{ "question": "犯す", "answers": [ "おかす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to commit/to perpetrate/to violate/to rape" },
		{ "question": "犯人", "answers": [ "はんにん" ], "comment": "(n) offender/criminal" },
		{ "question": "犯罪", "answers": [ "はんざい" ], "comment": "(n) crime" },
		{ "question": "状態", "answers": [ "じょうたい" ], "comment": "(n) condition/situation/circumstances/state" },
		{ "question": "状況", "answers": [ "じょうきょう" ], "comment": "(n) state of affairs/situation/circumstances" },
		{ "question": "狂う", "answers": [ "くるう" ], "comment": "(v5u) to go mad/to get out of order" },
		{ "question": "狙い", "answers": [ "ねらい" ], "comment": "(n) aim" },
		{ "question": "狙う", "answers": [ "ねらう" ], "comment": "(v5u) to aim at" },
		{ "question": "狡い", "answers": [ "ずるい" ], "comment": "(adj) (uk) sly/cunning" },
		{ "question": "狩り", "answers": [ "かり" ], "comment": "(n) hunting" },
		{ "question": "独り", "answers": [ "ひとり" ], "comment": "(adv,n) alone/unmarried" },
		{ "question": "独り言", "answers": [ "ひとりごと" ], "comment": "(n) a soliloquy/a monologue/speaking to oneself" },
		{ "question": "独創", "answers": [ "どくそう" ], "comment": "(n) originality" },
		{ "question": "独占", "answers": [ "どくせん" ], "comment": "(n) monopoly" },
		{ "question": "独特", "answers": [ "どくとく" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) peculiarity/uniqueness/characteristic" },
		{ "question": "独立", "answers": [ "どくりつ" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) independence (e.g. Ind. Day)/self-support" },
		{ "question": "独自", "answers": [ "どくじ" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) original/peculiar/characteristic" },
		{ "question": "独裁", "answers": [ "どくさい" ], "comment": "(n) dictatorship/despotism" },
		{ "question": "独身", "answers": [ "どくしん" ], "comment": "(n) bachelorhood/single/unmarried/celibate" },
		{ "question": "狭い", "answers": [ "せまい" ], "comment": "(adj) narrow/confined/small" },
		{ "question": "猛烈", "answers": [ "もうれつ" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) violent/vehement/rage" },
		{ "question": "猫", "answers": [ "ねこ" ], "comment": "(n) cat" },
		{ "question": "献立", "answers": [ "こんだて" ], "comment": "(n) menu/program/schedule" },
		{ "question": "猿", "answers": [ "さる" ], "comment": "(n) monkey" },
		{ "question": "獣", "answers": [ "けだもの","けもの" ], "comment": "(n) beast/brute" },
		{ "question": "獲得", "answers": [ "かくとく" ], "comment": "(n,vs) acquisition/possession" },
		{ "question": "獲物", "answers": [ "えもの" ], "comment": "(n) game/spoils/trophy" },
		{ "question": "玄人", "answers": [ "くろうと" ], "comment": "(n) expert/professional/geisha/prostitute" },
		{ "question": "玄関", "answers": [ "げんかん" ], "comment": "(n) entranceway/entry hall" },
		{ "question": "率", "answers": [ "りつ" ], "comment": "(n,n-suf) rate/ratio/proportion/percentage" },
		{ "question": "率いる", "answers": [ "ひきいる" ], "comment": "(v1) to lead/to spearhead (a group)/to command (troops)" },
		{ "question": "玉", "answers": [ "たま" ], "comment": "(n,n-suf) ball/sphere/coin" },
		{ "question": "王", "answers": [ "おう" ], "comment": "(n,n-suf) (1) king/ruler/sovereign/monarch/(2) king (for senior player) (shogi)" },
		{ "question": "王女", "answers": [ "おうじょ" ], "comment": "(n) princess" },
		{ "question": "王子", "answers": [ "おうじ" ], "comment": "(n) prince" },
		{ "question": "王様", "answers": [ "おうさま" ], "comment": "(n) king" },
		{ "question": "玩具", "answers": [ "がんぐ" ], "comment": "(n) (uk) toy" },
		{ "question": "珍しい", "answers": [ "めずらしい" ], "comment": "(adj) unusual/rare" },
		{ "question": "班", "answers": [ "はん" ], "comment": "(n,suf) group/party/section (mil)" },
		{ "question": "現す", "answers": [ "あらわす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to show/to indicate/to display" },
		{ "question": "現に", "answers": [ "げんに" ], "comment": "(adv) actually/really" },
		{ "question": "現れ", "answers": [ "あらわれ" ], "comment": "(n) embodiment/materialization" },
		{ "question": "現れる", "answers": [ "あらわれる" ], "comment": "(v1) (1) to appear/to come in sight/to become visible/to come out/to embody/to materialize/(2) to express oneself" },
		{ "question": "現代", "answers": [ "げんだい" ], "comment": "(adj-no,n-adv,n) nowadays/modern times/present-day" },
		{ "question": "現像", "answers": [ "げんぞう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) developing (film)" },
		{ "question": "現在", "answers": [ "げんざい" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n-t) present/up to now/nowadays/modern times/current" },
		{ "question": "現地", "answers": [ "げんち" ], "comment": "(n) actual place/local" },
		{ "question": "現場", "answers": [ "げんば" ], "comment": "(n) actual spot/scene/scene of the crime" },
		{ "question": "現実", "answers": [ "げんじつ" ], "comment": "(n) reality" },
		{ "question": "現状", "answers": [ "げんじょう" ], "comment": "(n) present condition/existing state/status quo" },
		{ "question": "現行", "answers": [ "げんこう" ], "comment": "(n) present/current/in operation" },
		{ "question": "現象", "answers": [ "げんしょう" ], "comment": "(n) phenomenon" },
		{ "question": "現金", "answers": [ "げんきん" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) cash/ready money/mercenary/self-interested" },
		{ "question": "球", "answers": [ "きゅう","たま" ], "comment": "(n) globe/sphere/ball" },
		{ "question": "球根", "answers": [ "きゅうこん" ], "comment": "(n) (plant) bulb" },
		{ "question": "理屈", "answers": [ "りくつ" ], "comment": "(n) theory/reason" },
		{ "question": "理性", "answers": [ "りせい" ], "comment": "(n) reason/sense" },
		{ "question": "理想", "answers": [ "りそう" ], "comment": "(n) ideal" },
		{ "question": "理由", "answers": [ "りゆう" ], "comment": "(n) reason/pretext/motive" },
		{ "question": "理科", "answers": [ "りか" ], "comment": "(n) science" },
		{ "question": "理解", "answers": [ "りかい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) understanding/comprehension" },
		{ "question": "理論", "answers": [ "りろん" ], "comment": "(n) theory" },
		{ "question": "琴", "answers": [ "こと" ], "comment": "(n) Koto (Japanese harp)" },
		{ "question": "環境", "answers": [ "かんきょう" ], "comment": "(n) environment/circumstance" },
		{ "question": "瓦", "answers": [ "かわら" ], "comment": "(n) roof tile" },
		{ "question": "瓶", "answers": [ "びん" ], "comment": "(n) bottle" },
		{ "question": "瓶詰", "answers": [ "びんづめ" ], "comment": "(adj-no,n,vs) bottling/bottled" },
		{ "question": "甘い", "answers": [ "あまい" ], "comment": "(adj) delicious" },
		{ "question": "甘える", "answers": [ "あまえる" ], "comment": "(v1) to behave like a spoiled child/to fawn on" },
		{ "question": "甘やかす", "answers": [ "あまやかす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to pamper/to spoil" },
		{ "question": "甘口", "answers": [ "あまくち" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) sweet flavour/mildness/flattery/stupidity" },
		{ "question": "甚だ", "answers": [ "はなはだ" ], "comment": "(adv) very/greatly/exceedingly" },
		{ "question": "甚だしい", "answers": [ "はなはだしい" ], "comment": "(adj) extreme/excessive/terrible/intense/severe/serious/tremendous/heavy (damage)" },
		{ "question": "生", "answers": [ "せい","なま" ], "comment": "(adj-na,adj-no,n) (1) draft (beer)/(2) raw/unprocessed" },
		{ "question": "生える", "answers": [ "はえる" ], "comment": "(v1) (1) to grow/to spring up/(2) to cut (teeth)" },
		{ "question": "生かす", "answers": [ "いかす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to revive/to resuscitate/to make use of" },
		{ "question": "生きる", "answers": [ "いきる" ], "comment": "(v1) to live/to exist" },
		{ "question": "生き物", "answers": [ "いきもの" ], "comment": "(n) living thing/animal" },
		{ "question": "生き生き", "answers": [ "いきいき" ], "comment": "(adv,n) vividly/lively" },
		{ "question": "生き甲斐", "answers": [ "いきがい" ], "comment": "(n) something one lives for, very important" },
		{ "question": "生け花", "answers": [ "いけばな" ], "comment": "(n) (1) flower arrangement" },
		{ "question": "生じる", "answers": [ "しょうじる" ], "comment": "(v1) to produce/to yield/to result from/to arise/to be generated" },
		{ "question": "生ずる", "answers": [ "しょうずる" ], "comment": "(v5z) to cause/to arise/to be generated" },
		{ "question": "生まれ", "answers": [ "うまれ" ], "comment": "(n) birth/birth-place" },
		{ "question": "生まれる", "answers": [ "うまれる" ], "comment": "(v1) to be born" },
		{ "question": "生やす", "answers": [ "はやす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to grow/to cultivate/to wear beard" },
		{ "question": "生る", "answers": [ "なる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to bear fruit" },
		{ "question": "生命", "answers": [ "せいめい" ], "comment": "(n) life/existence" },
		{ "question": "生地", "answers": [ "きじ" ], "comment": "(n) birthplace" },
		{ "question": "生存", "answers": [ "せいぞん" ], "comment": "(n) existence/being/survival" },
		{ "question": "生年月日", "answers": [ "せいねんがっぴ" ], "comment": "(n) birth date" },
		{ "question": "生徒", "answers": [ "せいと" ], "comment": "(n) pupil" },
		{ "question": "生意気", "answers": [ "なまいき" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) impertinent/saucy/cheeky/conceit/audacious/brazen" },
		{ "question": "生死", "answers": [ "せいし" ], "comment": "(n) life and death" },
		{ "question": "生活", "answers": [ "せいかつ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) living/life (one's daily existence)/livelihood" },
		{ "question": "生涯", "answers": [ "しょうがい" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n-t) one's lifetime (i.e., one's existance until death)" },
		{ "question": "生物", "answers": [ "せいぶつ" ], "comment": "(n) raw food" },
		{ "question": "生理", "answers": [ "せいり" ], "comment": "(n) physiology/menses" },
		{ "question": "生産", "answers": [ "せいさん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) production/manufacture" },
		{ "question": "生真面目", "answers": [ "きまじめ" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) too serious/person who is too serious/honesty/sincerity" },
		{ "question": "生育", "answers": [ "せいいく" ], "comment": "(n) growth/development/breeding" },
		{ "question": "生臭い", "answers": [ "なまぐさい" ], "comment": "(adj) smelling of fish or blood/fish or meat" },
		{ "question": "生計", "answers": [ "せいけい" ], "comment": "(n) livelihood/living" },
		{ "question": "生身", "answers": [ "なまみ" ], "comment": "(n) living flesh/flesh and blood/the quick" },
		{ "question": "生長", "answers": [ "せいちょう" ], "comment": "(n) growth/increment" },
		{ "question": "産む", "answers": [ "うむ" ], "comment": "(v5m) to give birth/to deliver/to produce" },
		{ "question": "産休", "answers": [ "さんきゅう" ], "comment": "(n) maternity leave" },
		{ "question": "産出", "answers": [ "さんしゅつ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) yield/produce" },
		{ "question": "産地", "answers": [ "さんち" ], "comment": "(n) producing area" },
		{ "question": "産婦人科", "answers": [ "さんふじんか" ], "comment": "(n) maternity and gynecology department" },
		{ "question": "産後", "answers": [ "さんご" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n-t) postpartum/after childbirth" },
		{ "question": "産業", "answers": [ "さんぎょう" ], "comment": "(n) industry" },
		{ "question": "産物", "answers": [ "さんぶつ" ], "comment": "(n) product/result/fruit" },
		{ "question": "用", "answers": [ "よう" ], "comment": "(n,n-suf) task/business/use" },
		{ "question": "用いる", "answers": [ "もちいる" ], "comment": "(v1) to use/to make use of" },
		{ "question": "用事", "answers": [ "ようじ" ], "comment": "(n) tasks/things to do" },
		{ "question": "用件", "answers": [ "ようけん" ], "comment": "(n) business" },
		{ "question": "用品", "answers": [ "ようひん" ], "comment": "(n) articles/supplies/parts" },
		{ "question": "用心", "answers": [ "ようじん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) care/precaution/guarding/caution" },
		{ "question": "用意", "answers": [ "ようい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) preparation" },
		{ "question": "用法", "answers": [ "ようほう" ], "comment": "(n) directions/rules of use" },
		{ "question": "用紙", "answers": [ "ようし" ], "comment": "(n) blank form" },
		{ "question": "用語", "answers": [ "ようご" ], "comment": "(n) term/terminology" },
		{ "question": "用途", "answers": [ "ようと" ], "comment": "(n) use/usefulness" },
		{ "question": "田", "answers": [ "た" ], "comment": "(n) rice field" },
		{ "question": "田ぼ", "answers": [ "たんぼ" ], "comment": "(n) paddy field/farm" },
		{ "question": "田園", "answers": [ "でんえん" ], "comment": "(n) country/rural districts" },
		{ "question": "田植え", "answers": [ "たうえ" ], "comment": "(n) rice planting" },
		{ "question": "田舎", "answers": [ "いなか" ], "comment": "(gikun) (n) rural/not particularly urban/countryside/suburb" },
		{ "question": "甲", "answers": [ "こう" ], "comment": "(n) 1st in rank/first sign of the Chinese calendar/shell/instep/grade A" },
		{ "question": "申し上げる", "answers": [ "もうしあげる" ], "comment": "(v1) to say/to tell/to state" },
		{ "question": "申し入れる", "answers": [ "もうしいれる" ], "comment": "(v1) to propose/to suggest" },
		{ "question": "申し出る", "answers": [ "もうしでる" ], "comment": "(v1) to report to/to tell/to suggest/to submit/to request/to make an offer/to come forward with information" },
		{ "question": "申し分", "answers": [ "もうしぶん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) objection/shortcomings" },
		{ "question": "申し訳", "answers": [ "もうしわけ" ], "comment": "(n) apology/excuse" },
		{ "question": "申し訳ない", "answers": [ "もうしわけない" ], "comment": "(adj-na) inexcusable" },
		{ "question": "申し込む", "answers": [ "もうしこむ" ], "comment": "(v5m) to apply for/to make an application/to propose (marriage)/to offer (mediation)/to make an overture (of peace)/to challenge/to lodge (objections)/to request (an interview)/to subscribe for/to book/to reserve" },
		{ "question": "申す", "answers": [ "もうす" ], "comment": "(v5s) (hum) to be called/to say" },
		{ "question": "申出", "answers": [ "もうしで" ], "comment": "(n) proposal/request/claim/report/notice" },
		{ "question": "申告", "answers": [ "しんこく" ], "comment": "(n,vs) report/statement/filing a return/notification" },
		{ "question": "申請", "answers": [ "しんせい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) application/request/petition" },
		{ "question": "申込", "answers": [ "もうしこみ" ], "comment": "(n) application/entry/request/subscription/offer/proposal/overture/challenge" },
		{ "question": "男", "answers": [ "おとこ" ], "comment": "(n) man" },
		{ "question": "男の人", "answers": [ "おとこのひと" ], "comment": "man" },
		{ "question": "男の子", "answers": [ "おとこのこ" ], "comment": "(n) boy" },
		{ "question": "男子", "answers": [ "だんし" ], "comment": "(n) youth/young man" },
		{ "question": "男性", "answers": [ "だんせい" ], "comment": "(n) male/man" },
		{ "question": "町", "answers": [ "まち" ], "comment": "(n) (1) town/(2) street/road" },
		{ "question": "画家", "answers": [ "がか" ], "comment": "(n) painter/artist" },
		{ "question": "画期", "answers": [ "かっき" ], "comment": "(n) epoch-making" },
		{ "question": "畑", "answers": [ "はたけ" ], "comment": "(n) field" },
		{ "question": "留まる", "answers": [ "とどまる","とまる" ], "comment": "(v5r) (1) to be fixed/(2) to abide/to stay (in the one place)" },
		{ "question": "留める", "answers": [ "とめる" ], "comment": "(v1) to fasten/to turn off/to detain" },
		{ "question": "留学", "answers": [ "りゅうがく" ], "comment": "(n) studying abroad" },
		{ "question": "留学生", "answers": [ "りゅうがくせい" ], "comment": "(n) overseas student" },
		{ "question": "留守", "answers": [ "るす" ], "comment": "(n) absence/being away from home" },
		{ "question": "留守番", "answers": [ "るすばん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) care-taking/caretaker/house-watching" },
		{ "question": "畜生", "answers": [ "ちくしょう" ], "comment": "(int,n) beast/brute/damn" },
		{ "question": "畜産", "answers": [ "ちくさん" ], "comment": "(n) animal husbandry" },
		{ "question": "略す", "answers": [ "りゃくす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to abbreviate" },
		{ "question": "略奪", "answers": [ "りゃくだつ" ], "comment": "(n) pillage/plunder/looting/robbery" },
		{ "question": "略語", "answers": [ "りゃくご" ], "comment": "(n) abbreviation/acronym" },
		{ "question": "番号", "answers": [ "ばんごう" ], "comment": "(n) number/series of digits" },
		{ "question": "番地", "answers": [ "ばんち" ], "comment": "(n) house number/address" },
		{ "question": "番組", "answers": [ "ばんぐみ" ], "comment": "(n) program (e.g. TV)" },
		{ "question": "異なる", "answers": [ "ことなる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to differ/to vary/to disagree" },
		{ "question": "異動", "answers": [ "いどう" ], "comment": "(n) a change" },
		{ "question": "異常", "answers": [ "いじょう" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) strangeness/abnormality/disorder" },
		{ "question": "異性", "answers": [ "いせい" ], "comment": "(n) the opposite sex" },
		{ "question": "異見", "answers": [ "いけん" ], "comment": "(n) different opinion/objection" },
		{ "question": "異論", "answers": [ "いろん" ], "comment": "(n) different opinion/objection" },
		{ "question": "異議", "answers": [ "いぎ" ], "comment": "(n) objection/dissent/protest" },
		{ "question": "畳", "answers": [ "たたみ" ], "comment": "(n) tatami mat (Japanese straw floor coverings)" },
		{ "question": "畳む", "answers": [ "たたむ" ], "comment": "(v5m) to fold (clothes)" },
		{ "question": "疑う", "answers": [ "うたがう" ], "comment": "(v5u) to doubt/to distrust/to be suspicious of/to suspect" },
		{ "question": "疑問", "answers": [ "ぎもん" ], "comment": "(n) question/problem/doubt/guess" },
		{ "question": "疑惑", "answers": [ "ぎわく" ], "comment": "(n) doubt/misgivings/distrust/suspicion" },
		{ "question": "疲れ", "answers": [ "つかれ" ], "comment": "(n) tiredness/fatigue" },
		{ "question": "疲れる", "answers": [ "つかれる" ], "comment": "(v1) to get tired/to tire" },
		{ "question": "疲労", "answers": [ "ひろう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) fatigue/weariness" },
		{ "question": "病む", "answers": [ "やむ" ], "comment": "(v5m) to fall ill/to be ill" },
		{ "question": "病気", "answers": [ "びょうき" ], "comment": "(n) illness/disease/sickness" },
		{ "question": "病院", "answers": [ "びょういん" ], "comment": "(n) hospital" },
		{ "question": "症状", "answers": [ "しょうじょう" ], "comment": "(n) symptoms/condition" },
		{ "question": "痛い", "answers": [ "いたい" ], "comment": "(adj) painful" },
		{ "question": "痛み", "answers": [ "いたみ" ], "comment": "(n) pain/ache/sore/grief/distress" },
		{ "question": "痛切", "answers": [ "つうせつ" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) keen/acute" },
		{ "question": "痛感", "answers": [ "つうかん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) feeling keenly/fully realizing" },
		{ "question": "痩せる", "answers": [ "やせる" ], "comment": "(io) (v1) to become thin/to lose weight/to reduce (one's) weight/to slim" },
		{ "question": "癌", "answers": [ "がん" ], "comment": "(n) cancer" },
		{ "question": "癖", "answers": [ "くせ" ], "comment": "(n) a habit (often a bad habit, i.e. vice)/peculiarity" },
		{ "question": "発つ", "answers": [ "たつ" ], "comment": "(v5t) to depart (on a plane, train, etc.)" },
		{ "question": "発作", "answers": [ "ほっさ" ], "comment": "(n) fit/spasm" },
		{ "question": "発売", "answers": [ "はつばい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) sale" },
		{ "question": "発射", "answers": [ "はっしゃ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) firing/shooting/discharge/catapult" },
		{ "question": "発展", "answers": [ "はってん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) development/growth" },
		{ "question": "発想", "answers": [ "はっそう" ], "comment": "(n) expression (music)/conceptualization" },
		{ "question": "発掘", "answers": [ "はっくつ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) (1) excavation/exhumation/(2) discovery (e.g. new talent)" },
		{ "question": "発揮", "answers": [ "はっき" ], "comment": "(n,vs) exhibition/demonstration/utilization/display" },
		{ "question": "発明", "answers": [ "はつめい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) invention" },
		{ "question": "発生", "answers": [ "はっせい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) outbreak/spring forth/occurrence/incidence/origin" },
		{ "question": "発病", "answers": [ "はつびょう" ], "comment": "(n) attack (disease)" },
		{ "question": "発育", "answers": [ "はついく" ], "comment": "(n) (physical) growth/development" },
		{ "question": "発芽", "answers": [ "はつが" ], "comment": "(n,vs) burgeoning" },
		{ "question": "発行", "answers": [ "はっこう" ], "comment": "(n) issue (publications)" },
		{ "question": "発表", "answers": [ "はっぴょう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) announcement/publication" },
		{ "question": "発見", "answers": [ "はっけん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) discovery/detection/finding" },
		{ "question": "発言", "answers": [ "はつげん" ], "comment": "(n) utterance/speech/proposal" },
		{ "question": "発足", "answers": [ "ほっそく" ], "comment": "(n) starting/inauguration" },
		{ "question": "発車", "answers": [ "はっしゃ" ], "comment": "(n) departure of a vehicle" },
		{ "question": "発達", "answers": [ "はったつ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) development/growth" },
		{ "question": "発電", "answers": [ "はつでん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) generation (e.g. power)" },
		{ "question": "発音", "answers": [ "はつおん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) pronunciation" },
		{ "question": "登る", "answers": [ "のぼる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to climb" },
		{ "question": "登場", "answers": [ "とうじょう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) entry (on stage)" },
		{ "question": "登山", "answers": [ "とざん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) mountain-climbing" },
		{ "question": "登校", "answers": [ "とうこう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) attendance (at school)" },
		{ "question": "登録", "answers": [ "とうろく" ], "comment": "(n,vs) registration/register/entry/record" },
		{ "question": "白", "answers": [ "しろ" ], "comment": "(n) white" },
		{ "question": "白い", "answers": [ "しろい" ], "comment": "(adj) white" },
		{ "question": "白状", "answers": [ "はくじょう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) confession" },
		{ "question": "白髪", "answers": [ "しらが" ], "comment": "(n) white or grey hair/trendy hair bleaching" },
		{ "question": "百", "answers": [ "ひゃく" ], "comment": "(num) 100/hundred" },
		{ "question": "的確", "answers": [ "てきかく" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) precise/accurate" },
		{ "question": "皆", "answers": [ "みな","みんな" ], "comment": "(adv,n) all/everyone/everybody" },
		{ "question": "皆さん", "answers": [ "みなさん" ], "comment": "(n) everyone" },
		{ "question": "皇居", "answers": [ "こうきょ" ], "comment": "(n) Imperial Palace" },
		{ "question": "皮", "answers": [ "かわ" ], "comment": "(n) skin/hide/leather/fur/pelt/bark/shell" },
		{ "question": "皮肉", "answers": [ "ひにく" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) cynicism/sarcasm" },
		{ "question": "皮膚", "answers": [ "ひふ" ], "comment": "(n) skin" },
		{ "question": "皿", "answers": [ "さら" ], "comment": "(n) plate/dish" },
		{ "question": "盆", "answers": [ "ぼん" ], "comment": "(n) Lantern Festival/Festival of the Dead/tray" },
		{ "question": "盆地", "answers": [ "ぼんち" ], "comment": "(n) basin (e.g. between mountains)" },
		{ "question": "盗む", "answers": [ "ぬすむ" ], "comment": "(v5m) to steal" },
		{ "question": "盗難", "answers": [ "とうなん" ], "comment": "(n) theft/robbery" },
		{ "question": "盛り", "answers": [ "さかり" ], "comment": "(n) helping/serving" },
		{ "question": "盛り上がる", "answers": [ "もりあがる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to rouse/to swell/to rise" },
		{ "question": "盛る", "answers": [ "もる" ], "comment": "(v5r) (1) to serve (food, etc.)/(2) to fill up/(3) to prescribe" },
		{ "question": "盛ん", "answers": [ "さかん" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) popularity/prosperous" },
		{ "question": "盛大", "answers": [ "せいだい" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) grand/prosperous/magnificent" },
		{ "question": "盛装", "answers": [ "せいそう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) be dressed up/wear rich clothes" },
		{ "question": "監督", "answers": [ "かんとく" ], "comment": "(n,vs) supervision/control/superintendence" },
		{ "question": "監視", "answers": [ "かんし" ], "comment": "(n,vs) observation/guarding/inspection/surveillance" },
		{ "question": "目", "answers": [ "め" ], "comment": "(n) eye/eyeball" },
		{ "question": "目上", "answers": [ "めうえ" ], "comment": "(n) superior(s)/senior" },
		{ "question": "目下", "answers": [ "めした","もっか" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n-t) at present/now" },
		{ "question": "目付き", "answers": [ "めつき" ], "comment": "(n) look/expression of the eyes/eyes" },
		{ "question": "目印", "answers": [ "めじるし" ], "comment": "(n,vs) mark/sign/landmark" },
		{ "question": "目安", "answers": [ "めやす" ], "comment": "(n) criterion/aim" },
		{ "question": "目指す", "answers": [ "めざす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to aim at/to have an eye on" },
		{ "question": "目方", "answers": [ "めかた" ], "comment": "(n) weight" },
		{ "question": "目標", "answers": [ "もくひょう" ], "comment": "(n) mark/objective/target" },
		{ "question": "目次", "answers": [ "もくじ" ], "comment": "(n) table of contents" },
		{ "question": "目的", "answers": [ "もくてき" ], "comment": "(n) purpose/goal/aim/objective/intention" },
		{ "question": "目盛", "answers": [ "めもり" ], "comment": "(n) scale/gradations" },
		{ "question": "目立つ", "answers": [ "めだつ" ], "comment": "(v5t) to be conspicuous/to stand out" },
		{ "question": "目覚し", "answers": [ "めざまし" ], "comment": "(n) (abbr) alarm-clock" },
		{ "question": "目覚しい", "answers": [ "めざましい" ], "comment": "(adj) (arch) brilliant/splendid/striking/remarkable" },
		{ "question": "目覚める", "answers": [ "めざめる" ], "comment": "(v1) to wake up" },
		{ "question": "目論見", "answers": [ "もくろみ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) a plan/a scheme/a project/a program/intention/goal" },
		{ "question": "目途", "answers": [ "めど" ], "comment": "(n) goal/outlook" },
		{ "question": "目録", "answers": [ "もくろく" ], "comment": "(n) catalogue/catalog/list" },
		{ "question": "盲点", "answers": [ "もうてん" ], "comment": "(n) blind spot" },
		{ "question": "直", "answers": [ "じき" ], "comment": "earnestly/immediately/exactly" },
		{ "question": "直す", "answers": [ "なおす" ], "comment": "(v5s,vt) to cure/to heal/to fix/to correct/to repair" },
		{ "question": "直ちに", "answers": [ "ただちに" ], "comment": "(adv) at once/immediately/directly/in person" },
		{ "question": "直に", "answers": [ "じかに" ], "comment": "(adv) immediately/readily/directly" },
		{ "question": "直る", "answers": [ "なおる" ], "comment": "(v5r,vi) to be cured/to heal/to get mended/to get well/to be repaired/to be fixed" },
		{ "question": "直前", "answers": [ "ちょくぜん" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n-t) just before" },
		{ "question": "直径", "answers": [ "ちょっけい" ], "comment": "(n) diameter" },
		{ "question": "直後", "answers": [ "ちょくご" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n-t) immediately following" },
		{ "question": "直感", "answers": [ "ちょっかん" ], "comment": "(n) intuition/instinct/insight/hunch" },
		{ "question": "直接", "answers": [ "ちょくせつ" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n-adv) direct/immediate/personal/firsthand" },
		{ "question": "直流", "answers": [ "ちょくりゅう" ], "comment": "(n) direct current" },
		{ "question": "直線", "answers": [ "ちょくせん" ], "comment": "(n) straight line" },
		{ "question": "直角", "answers": [ "ちょっかく" ], "comment": "(n) right angle" },
		{ "question": "直通", "answers": [ "ちょくつう" ], "comment": "(n) direct communication" },
		{ "question": "直面", "answers": [ "ちょくめん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) confrontation" },
		{ "question": "相", "answers": [ "そう" ], "comment": "(n) aspect/phase/countenance" },
		{ "question": "相互", "answers": [ "そうご" ], "comment": "(n) mutual/reciprocal" },
		{ "question": "相場", "answers": [ "そうば" ], "comment": "(n) market price/speculation/estimation" },
		{ "question": "相対", "answers": [ "そうたい" ], "comment": "(n) relative" },
		{ "question": "相当", "answers": [ "そうとう" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n-adv) suitable/fair/tolerable/proper" },
		{ "question": "相応", "answers": [ "そうおう" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) suitability/fitness" },
		{ "question": "相手", "answers": [ "あいて" ], "comment": "(n) (1) companion/partner/company/(2) other party/addressee" },
		{ "question": "相撲", "answers": [ "すもう" ], "comment": "(n) sumo wrestling" },
		{ "question": "相続", "answers": [ "そうぞく" ], "comment": "(n) succession/inheritance" },
		{ "question": "相談", "answers": [ "そうだん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) consultation/discussion" },
		{ "question": "相違", "answers": [ "そうい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) difference/discrepancy/variation" },
		{ "question": "盾", "answers": [ "たて" ], "comment": "(n) shield/buckler/escutcheon/pretext" },
		{ "question": "省く", "answers": [ "はぶく" ], "comment": "(v5k) to omit/to eliminate/to curtail/to economize" },
		{ "question": "省みる", "answers": [ "かえりみる" ], "comment": "(v1) to reflect" },
		{ "question": "省略", "answers": [ "しょうりゃく" ], "comment": "(n,vs) omission/abbreviation/abridgment" },
		{ "question": "眉", "answers": [ "まゆ" ], "comment": "(n) eyebrow" },
		{ "question": "看板", "answers": [ "かんばん" ], "comment": "(n) sign/signboard/doorplate/poster/billboard/appearance/figurehead/policy/attraction/closing time" },
		{ "question": "看病", "answers": [ "かんびょう" ], "comment": "(n) nursing (a patient)" },
		{ "question": "看護", "answers": [ "かんご" ], "comment": "(n,vs) nursing/(army) nurse" },
		{ "question": "看護婦", "answers": [ "かんごふ" ], "comment": "(n) (female) nurse" },
		{ "question": "県", "answers": [ "けん" ], "comment": "(n) prefecture" },
		{ "question": "県庁", "answers": [ "けんちょう" ], "comment": "(n) prefectural office" },
		{ "question": "真っ二つ", "answers": [ "まっぷたつ" ], "comment": "(n) in two equal parts" },
		{ "question": "真っ先", "answers": [ "まっさき" ], "comment": "(n) the head/the foremost/beginning" },
		{ "question": "真っ暗", "answers": [ "まっくら" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) total darkness/shortsightedness/pitch dark" },
		{ "question": "真っ白", "answers": [ "まっしろ" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) pure white" },
		{ "question": "真っ直ぐ", "answers": [ "まっすぐ" ], "comment": "(adj-na,adv,n) straight (ahead)/direct/upright/erect/honest/frank" },
		{ "question": "真っ赤", "answers": [ "まっか" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) deep red/flushed (of face)" },
		{ "question": "真っ青", "answers": [ "まっさお" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) deep blue/ghastly pale" },
		{ "question": "真っ黒", "answers": [ "まっくろ" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) pitch black" },
		{ "question": "真ん丸い", "answers": [ "まんまるい" ], "comment": "(adj) perfectly circular" },
		{ "question": "真ん円い", "answers": [ "まんまるい" ], "comment": "(adj) perfectly round" },
		{ "question": "真ん前", "answers": [ "まんまえ" ], "comment": "(n) right in front/under the nose" },
		{ "question": "真上", "answers": [ "まうえ" ], "comment": "(n) just above/right overhead" },
		{ "question": "真下", "answers": [ "ました" ], "comment": "(adj-no,n) right under/directly below" },
		{ "question": "真中", "answers": [ "まんなか" ], "comment": "(n) middle/centre/mid-way" },
		{ "question": "真似", "answers": [ "まね" ], "comment": "(n) mimicry/imitation/behavior/pretense" },
		{ "question": "真似る", "answers": [ "まねる" ], "comment": "(v1) to mimic/to imitate" },
		{ "question": "真剣", "answers": [ "しんけん" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) seriousness/earnestness" },
		{ "question": "真実", "answers": [ "しんじつ" ], "comment": "(adj-na,adv,n) truth/reality" },
		{ "question": "真心", "answers": [ "まごころ" ], "comment": "(n) sincerity/devotion" },
		{ "question": "真珠", "answers": [ "しんじゅ" ], "comment": "(n) pearl" },
		{ "question": "真理", "answers": [ "しんり" ], "comment": "(n) truth" },
		{ "question": "真相", "answers": [ "しんそう" ], "comment": "(n) truth/real situation" },
		{ "question": "真空", "answers": [ "しんくう" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) vacuum/hollow/empty" },
		{ "question": "真面目", "answers": [ "まじめ" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) diligent/serious/honest" },
		{ "question": "眠い", "answers": [ "ねむい" ], "comment": "(adj) (1) aestivation/estivation/(2) sleepy/drowsy" },
		{ "question": "眠たい", "answers": [ "ねむたい" ], "comment": "(adj) sleepy" },
		{ "question": "眠る", "answers": [ "ねむる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to sleep" },
		{ "question": "眺め", "answers": [ "ながめ" ], "comment": "(n) scene/view/prospect/outlook" },
		{ "question": "眺める", "answers": [ "ながめる" ], "comment": "(v1) to view/to gaze at" },
		{ "question": "眼球", "answers": [ "がんきゅう" ], "comment": "(n) eyeball" },
		{ "question": "眼科", "answers": [ "がんか" ], "comment": "(n) ophthalmology" },
		{ "question": "眼鏡", "answers": [ "めがね" ], "comment": "(n) spectacles/glasses" },
		{ "question": "着々", "answers": [ "ちゃくちゃく" ], "comment": "(adv) steadily" },
		{ "question": "着く", "answers": [ "つく" ], "comment": "(v5k) to arrive at/to reach" },
		{ "question": "着ける", "answers": [ "つける" ], "comment": "(v1,vt) (1) to attach/to join/to add/to append/to affix/to stick/to glue/to fasten/to sew on/to apply (ointment)/(2) to furnish (a house with)/(3) to wear/to put on/(4) to keep a diary/to make an entry/(5) to appraise/to set (a price)/(6) to bring alongside/(7) to place (under guard or doctor)/(8) to follow/to shadow/(9) to load/to give (courage to)/(10) to keep (an eye on)/(11) to establish (relations or understanding)" },
		{ "question": "着せる", "answers": [ "きせる" ], "comment": "(v1) to put on clothes" },
		{ "question": "着る", "answers": [ "きる" ], "comment": "(v1) to wear/to put on (from shoulders down)" },
		{ "question": "着工", "answers": [ "ちゃっこう" ], "comment": "(n) start of (construction) work" },
		{ "question": "着席", "answers": [ "ちゃくせき" ], "comment": "(n,vs) sit down/seat" },
		{ "question": "着手", "answers": [ "ちゃくしゅ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) embarkation/launch" },
		{ "question": "着替え", "answers": [ "きがえ" ], "comment": "(n) changing clothes/change of clothes" },
		{ "question": "着替える", "answers": [ "きがえる" ], "comment": "(v1) to change one's clothes" },
		{ "question": "着物", "answers": [ "きもの" ], "comment": "(n) kimono" },
		{ "question": "着目", "answers": [ "ちゃくもく" ], "comment": "(n,vs) attention" },
		{ "question": "着色", "answers": [ "ちゃくしょく" ], "comment": "(n) colouring/coloring" },
		{ "question": "着陸", "answers": [ "ちゃくりく" ], "comment": "(n,vs) landing/alighting/touch down" },
		{ "question": "着飾る", "answers": [ "きかざる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to dress up" },
		{ "question": "睡眠", "answers": [ "すいみん" ], "comment": "(n) sleep" },
		{ "question": "睨む", "answers": [ "にらむ" ], "comment": "(v5m) to glare at/to scowl at/to keep an eye on" },
		{ "question": "瞬き", "answers": [ "まばたき" ], "comment": "(n) wink/twinkling (of stars)/flicker (of light)" },
		{ "question": "瞬間", "answers": [ "しゅんかん" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n-t) moment/second/instant" },
		{ "question": "瞳", "answers": [ "ひとみ" ], "comment": "(n) pupil (of eye)" },
		{ "question": "矛盾", "answers": [ "むじゅん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) contradiction/inconsistency" },
		{ "question": "矢", "answers": [ "や" ], "comment": "(n) arrow" },
		{ "question": "矢印", "answers": [ "やじるし" ], "comment": "(n) directing arrow" },
		{ "question": "知らせ", "answers": [ "しらせ" ], "comment": "(n) notice" },
		{ "question": "知らせる", "answers": [ "しらせる" ], "comment": "(v1) to notify/to advise" },
		{ "question": "知る", "answers": [ "しる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to know/to understand/to be acquainted with/to feel" },
		{ "question": "知事", "answers": [ "ちじ" ], "comment": "(n) prefectural governor" },
		{ "question": "知人", "answers": [ "ちじん" ], "comment": "(n) friend/acquaintance" },
		{ "question": "知合い", "answers": [ "しりあい" ], "comment": "(n) acquaintance" },
		{ "question": "知性", "answers": [ "ちせい" ], "comment": "(n) intelligence" },
		{ "question": "知恵", "answers": [ "ちえ" ], "comment": "(n) wisdom/wit/sagacity/sense/intelligence/advice" },
		{ "question": "知的", "answers": [ "ちてき" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) intellectual" },
		{ "question": "知能", "answers": [ "ちのう" ], "comment": "(n) intelligence/brains" },
		{ "question": "知識", "answers": [ "ちしき" ], "comment": "(n) knowledge/information" },
		{ "question": "短い", "answers": [ "みじかい" ], "comment": "(adj) short" },
		{ "question": "短大", "answers": [ "たんだい" ], "comment": "(n) junior college" },
		{ "question": "短所", "answers": [ "たんしょ" ], "comment": "(n) (1) defect/demerit/weak point/(2) disadvantage" },
		{ "question": "短期", "answers": [ "たんき" ], "comment": "(n) short term" },
		{ "question": "短歌", "answers": [ "たんか" ], "comment": "(n) tanka/31-syllable Japanese poem" },
		{ "question": "短気", "answers": [ "たんき" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) quick temper" },
		{ "question": "短波", "answers": [ "たんぱ" ], "comment": "(n) short wave" },
		{ "question": "短編", "answers": [ "たんぺん" ], "comment": "(n) short (e.g. story, film)" },
		{ "question": "短縮", "answers": [ "たんしゅく" ], "comment": "(n,vs) shortening/abbreviation/reduction" },
		{ "question": "石", "answers": [ "いし" ], "comment": "(n) volume measure (approx. 180l, 5 bushels, 10 cub.ft)" },
		{ "question": "石油", "answers": [ "せきゆ" ], "comment": "(n) oil/petroleum/kerosene" },
		{ "question": "石炭", "answers": [ "せきたん" ], "comment": "(n) coal" },
		{ "question": "石鹸", "answers": [ "せっけん" ], "comment": "(n) soap" },
		{ "question": "砂", "answers": [ "すな" ], "comment": "(n) sand/grit" },
		{ "question": "砂利", "answers": [ "じゃり" ], "comment": "(n) gravel/ballast/pebbles" },
		{ "question": "砂漠", "answers": [ "さばく" ], "comment": "(n) desert" },
		{ "question": "砂糖", "answers": [ "さとう" ], "comment": "(n) sugar" },
		{ "question": "研ぐ", "answers": [ "とぐ" ], "comment": "(v5g) to sharpen/to grind/to scour/to hone/to polish/to wash (rice)" },
		{ "question": "研修", "answers": [ "けんしゅう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) training" },
		{ "question": "研究", "answers": [ "けんきゅう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) study/research/investigation" },
		{ "question": "研究室", "answers": [ "けんきゅうしつ" ], "comment": "(n) seminar room/laboratory/prof's office" },
		{ "question": "砕く", "answers": [ "くだく" ], "comment": "(v5k,vt) to break/to smash" },
		{ "question": "砕ける", "answers": [ "くだける" ], "comment": "(v1,vi) to break/to be broken" },
		{ "question": "破る", "answers": [ "やぶる" ], "comment": "(v5r,vt) to tear/to violate/to defeat/to smash/to destroy" },
		{ "question": "破れる", "answers": [ "やぶれる" ], "comment": "(v1) to get torn/to wear out" },
		{ "question": "破壊", "answers": [ "はかい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) destruction" },
		{ "question": "破損", "answers": [ "はそん" ], "comment": "(n) damage" },
		{ "question": "破棄", "answers": [ "はき" ], "comment": "(n,vs) revocation/annulment/breaking (e.g. treaty)" },
		{ "question": "破片", "answers": [ "はへん" ], "comment": "(n) fragment/splinter/broken piece" },
		{ "question": "破産", "answers": [ "はさん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) (personal) bankruptcy" },
		{ "question": "破裂", "answers": [ "はれつ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) explosion/rupture/break off" },
		{ "question": "硬い", "answers": [ "かたい" ], "comment": "(adj) solid/hard (esp. metal, stone)/unpolished writing" },
		{ "question": "硬貨", "answers": [ "こうか" ], "comment": "(n) coin" },
		{ "question": "碁", "answers": [ "ご" ], "comment": "(n) Go (board game of capturing territory)" },
		{ "question": "碁盤", "answers": [ "ごばん" ], "comment": "(n) Go board" },
		{ "question": "碑", "answers": [ "ひ" ], "comment": "(n) stone monument bearing an inscription" },
		{ "question": "碗", "answers": [ "わん" ], "comment": "(n) bowl" },
		{ "question": "確か", "answers": [ "たしか" ], "comment": "(adj-na,adv,exp,n) certain/sure/definite/if I'm not mistaken/if I remember correctly" },
		{ "question": "確かめる", "answers": [ "たしかめる" ], "comment": "(v1) to ascertain" },
		{ "question": "確保", "answers": [ "かくほ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) guarantee/ensure/maintain/insure/secure" },
		{ "question": "確信", "answers": [ "かくしん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) conviction/confidence" },
		{ "question": "確定", "answers": [ "かくてい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) definition (math)/decision/settlement" },
		{ "question": "確実", "answers": [ "かくじつ" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) certainty/reliability/soundness" },
		{ "question": "確率", "answers": [ "かくりつ" ], "comment": "(n) probability" },
		{ "question": "確立", "answers": [ "かくりつ" ], "comment": "(n) establishment" },
		{ "question": "確認", "answers": [ "かくにん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) affirmation/confirmation" },
		{ "question": "磁器", "answers": [ "じき" ], "comment": "(n) porcelain/china" },
		{ "question": "磁気", "answers": [ "じき" ], "comment": "(n) magnetism" },
		{ "question": "磁石", "answers": [ "じしゃく" ], "comment": "(n) magnet" },
		{ "question": "磨く", "answers": [ "みがく" ], "comment": "(v5k) to polish/to shine/to brush/to refine/to improve" },
		{ "question": "示す", "answers": [ "しめす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to denote/to show/to point out/to indicate" },
		{ "question": "礼", "answers": [ "れい" ], "comment": "(n) expression of gratitude" },
		{ "question": "礼儀", "answers": [ "れいぎ" ], "comment": "(n) manners/courtesy/etiquette" },
		{ "question": "社交", "answers": [ "しゃこう" ], "comment": "(n) social life/social intercourse" },
		{ "question": "社会", "answers": [ "しゃかい" ], "comment": "(n) society/public" },
		{ "question": "社会科学", "answers": [ "しゃかいかがく" ], "comment": "social science" },
		{ "question": "社宅", "answers": [ "しゃたく" ], "comment": "(n) company owned house" },
		{ "question": "社説", "answers": [ "しゃせつ" ], "comment": "(n) editorial/leading article" },
		{ "question": "社長", "answers": [ "しゃちょう" ], "comment": "(n) company president/manager/director" },
		{ "question": "祈り", "answers": [ "いのり" ], "comment": "(n) prayer/supplication" },
		{ "question": "祈る", "answers": [ "いのる" ], "comment": "(v5r,vi) to pray/to wish" },
		{ "question": "祖先", "answers": [ "そせん" ], "comment": "(n) ancestor" },
		{ "question": "祖母", "answers": [ "そぼ" ], "comment": "(n) grandmother" },
		{ "question": "祖父", "answers": [ "そふ" ], "comment": "(n) grandfather" },
		{ "question": "祝い", "answers": [ "いわい" ], "comment": "(n) celebration/festival" },
		{ "question": "祝う", "answers": [ "いわう" ], "comment": "(v5u) to congratulate/to celebrate" },
		{ "question": "祝日", "answers": [ "しゅくじつ" ], "comment": "(n) national holiday" },
		{ "question": "祝賀", "answers": [ "しゅくが" ], "comment": "(n,vs) celebration/congratulations" },
		{ "question": "神", "answers": [ "かみ" ], "comment": "(n) god" },
		{ "question": "神様", "answers": [ "かみさま" ], "comment": "(n) god" },
		{ "question": "神殿", "answers": [ "しんでん" ], "comment": "(n) temple/sacred place" },
		{ "question": "神社", "answers": [ "じんじゃ" ], "comment": "(n) Shinto shrine" },
		{ "question": "神秘", "answers": [ "しんぴ" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) mystery" },
		{ "question": "神経", "answers": [ "しんけい" ], "comment": "(n) nerve/sensitivity" },
		{ "question": "神聖", "answers": [ "しんせい" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) holiness/sacredness/dignity" },
		{ "question": "神話", "answers": [ "しんわ" ], "comment": "(n) myth/legend" },
		{ "question": "票", "answers": [ "ひょう" ], "comment": "(n,n-suf) label/ballot/ticket/sign" },
		{ "question": "祭", "answers": [ "まつり" ], "comment": "(n) festival/feast" },
		{ "question": "祭る", "answers": [ "まつる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to deify/to enshrine" },
		{ "question": "祭日", "answers": [ "さいじつ" ], "comment": "(n) national holiday/festival day" },
		{ "question": "禁じる", "answers": [ "きんじる" ], "comment": "(v1) to prohibit" },
		{ "question": "禁止", "answers": [ "きんし" ], "comment": "(n,vs) prohibition/ban" },
		{ "question": "禁煙", "answers": [ "きんえん" ], "comment": "(exp) No Smoking!" },
		{ "question": "禁物", "answers": [ "きんもつ" ], "comment": "(n) taboo/forbidden thing" },
		{ "question": "禅", "answers": [ "ぜん" ], "comment": "(n) Zen (Buddhism)" },
		{ "question": "福", "answers": [ "ふく" ], "comment": "(n) good fortune" },
		{ "question": "福祉", "answers": [ "ふくし" ], "comment": "(n) welfare/well-being" },
		{ "question": "私", "answers": [ "わたくし","わたし" ], "comment": "(adj-no,n) I/myself/private affairs" },
		{ "question": "私有", "answers": [ "しゆう" ], "comment": "(n) private ownership" },
		{ "question": "私物", "answers": [ "しぶつ" ], "comment": "(n) private property/personal effects" },
		{ "question": "私用", "answers": [ "しよう" ], "comment": "(adj-no,n) personal use/private business" },
		{ "question": "私立", "answers": [ "しりつ" ], "comment": "(n) private (establishment)" },
		{ "question": "私鉄", "answers": [ "してつ" ], "comment": "(n) private railway" },
		{ "question": "秋", "answers": [ "あき" ], "comment": "(n-adv) autumn/fall" },
		{ "question": "科学", "answers": [ "かがく" ], "comment": "(n) science" },
		{ "question": "科目", "answers": [ "かもく" ], "comment": "(n) (school) subject/curriculum/course" },
		{ "question": "秒", "answers": [ "びょう" ], "comment": "(n) second (60th min)" },
		{ "question": "秘密", "answers": [ "ひみつ" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) secret/secrecy" },
		{ "question": "秘書", "answers": [ "ひしょ" ], "comment": "(n) (private) secretary" },
		{ "question": "秤", "answers": [ "はかり" ], "comment": "(n) scales/weighing machine" },
		{ "question": "秩序", "answers": [ "ちつじょ" ], "comment": "(n) order/regularity/system/method" },
		{ "question": "称する", "answers": [ "しょうする" ], "comment": "(vs-s) (1) to take the name of/to call oneself/(2) to pretend/to feign/to purport" },
		{ "question": "移す", "answers": [ "うつす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to remove/to transfer/to infect" },
		{ "question": "移る", "answers": [ "うつる" ], "comment": "(v5r) (1) to move (house)/to transfer (department)/(2) to be infected/to be contagious" },
		{ "question": "移住", "answers": [ "いじゅう" ], "comment": "(n) migration/immigration" },
		{ "question": "移動", "answers": [ "いどう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) removal/migration/movement" },
		{ "question": "移民", "answers": [ "いみん" ], "comment": "(n) emigration/immigration/emigrant/immigrant" },
		{ "question": "移行", "answers": [ "いこう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) switching over to" },
		{ "question": "移転", "answers": [ "いてん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) moving/transfer/demise" },
		{ "question": "稀", "answers": [ "まれ" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) rare/seldom" },
		{ "question": "程", "answers": [ "ほど" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n) degree/extent/bounds/limit" },
		{ "question": "程度", "answers": [ "ていど" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n,n-suf) degree/amount/grade/standard/of the order of (following a number)" },
		{ "question": "税務署", "answers": [ "ぜいむしょ" ], "comment": "(n) tax office" },
		{ "question": "税金", "answers": [ "ぜいきん" ], "comment": "(n) tax/duty" },
		{ "question": "税関", "answers": [ "ぜいかん" ], "comment": "(n) customs house" },
		{ "question": "種", "answers": [ "しゅ","たね" ], "comment": "(n) (1) seed/pip/kind/variety/quality/tone/(2) material/matter/subject/theme/(news) copy/(3) cause/source/trick/secret/inside story" },
		{ "question": "種々", "answers": [ "しゅじゅ","くさぐさ" ], "comment": "(adj-na,adj-no,adv,n) variety" },
		{ "question": "種類", "answers": [ "しゅるい" ], "comment": "(n) variety/kind/type/category/counter for different sorts of things" },
		{ "question": "稲", "answers": [ "いね" ], "comment": "(n) rice-plant" },
		{ "question": "稲光", "answers": [ "いなびかり" ], "comment": "(n) (flash of) lightning" },
		{ "question": "稼ぐ", "answers": [ "かせぐ" ], "comment": "(v5g) to earn income/to labor" },
		{ "question": "稽古", "answers": [ "けいこ" ], "comment": "(n) practice/training/study" },
		{ "question": "穀物", "answers": [ "こくもつ" ], "comment": "(n) grain/cereal/corn" },
		{ "question": "穂", "answers": [ "ほ" ], "comment": "(n) ear (of plant)/head (of plant)" },
		{ "question": "積む", "answers": [ "つむ" ], "comment": "(v5m) to pile up/to stack" },
		{ "question": "積もる", "answers": [ "つもる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to pile up" },
		{ "question": "積極的", "answers": [ "せっきょくてき" ], "comment": "(adj-na) positive/active/proactive" },
		{ "question": "穏やか", "answers": [ "おだやか" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) calm/gentle/quiet" },
		{ "question": "穴", "answers": [ "あな" ], "comment": "(n) (col) ass/arse/buttocks" },
		{ "question": "究極", "answers": [ "きゅうきょく" ], "comment": "(adj-no,n) ultimate/final/eventual" },
		{ "question": "空", "answers": [ "から","そら" ], "comment": "(n) sky" },
		{ "question": "空き", "answers": [ "あき" ], "comment": "(n) room/time to spare/emptiness/vacant" },
		{ "question": "空く", "answers": [ "あく","すく" ], "comment": "(v5k,vi) (1) to open/to become open/to become empty/(2) to be less crowded" },
		{ "question": "空しい", "answers": [ "むなしい" ], "comment": "(adj) vacant/futile/vain/void/empty/ineffective/lifeless" },
		{ "question": "空っぽ", "answers": [ "からっぽ" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) empty/vacant/hollow" },
		{ "question": "空ろ", "answers": [ "うつろ" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) blank/cavity/hollow/empty (space)" },
		{ "question": "空中", "answers": [ "くうちゅう" ], "comment": "(n) sky/air" },
		{ "question": "空想", "answers": [ "くうそう" ], "comment": "(n) daydream/fantasy/fancy/vision" },
		{ "question": "空気", "answers": [ "くうき" ], "comment": "(n) air/atmosphere" },
		{ "question": "空港", "answers": [ "くうこう" ], "comment": "(n) airport" },
		{ "question": "空腹", "answers": [ "くうふく" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) hunger" },
		{ "question": "空間", "answers": [ "くうかん" ], "comment": "(n) space/room/airspace" },
		{ "question": "突き当たり", "answers": [ "つきあたり" ], "comment": "(n) end (e.g. of street)" },
		{ "question": "突き当たる", "answers": [ "つきあたる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to run into/to collide with" },
		{ "question": "突く", "answers": [ "つく","つつく" ], "comment": "(v5k) (1) to thrust/to strike/to attack/(2) to poke/to nudge/to pick at" },
		{ "question": "突っ張る", "answers": [ "つっぱる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to support/to become stiff/to become taut/to thrust (ones opponent)/to stick to (ones opinion)/to insist on" },
		{ "question": "突っ突く", "answers": [ "つっつく" ], "comment": "(v5k) to prompt someone" },
		{ "question": "突っ込む", "answers": [ "つっこむ" ], "comment": "(v5m) to plunge into/to go into deeply" },
		{ "question": "突如", "answers": [ "とつじょ" ], "comment": "(adv) suddenly/all of a sudden" },
		{ "question": "突然", "answers": [ "とつぜん" ], "comment": "(adj-na,adj-no,adv) abruptly/suddenly/unexpectedly/all at once" },
		{ "question": "突破", "answers": [ "とっぱ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) breaking through/breakthrough/penetration" },
		{ "question": "窒息", "answers": [ "ちっそく" ], "comment": "(n,vs) suffocation" },
		{ "question": "窓", "answers": [ "まど" ], "comment": "(n) window" },
		{ "question": "窓口", "answers": [ "まどぐち" ], "comment": "(n) ticket window" },
		{ "question": "窮乏", "answers": [ "きゅうぼう" ], "comment": "(n) poverty" },
		{ "question": "窮屈", "answers": [ "きゅうくつ" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) narrow/tight/stiff/rigid/uneasy/formal/constrained" },
		{ "question": "立ち上がる", "answers": [ "たちあがる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to stand up" },
		{ "question": "立ち去る", "answers": [ "たちさる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to leave/to depart/to take one's leave" },
		{ "question": "立ち寄る", "answers": [ "たちよる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to stop by/to drop in for a short visit" },
		{ "question": "立ち止まる", "answers": [ "たちどまる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to stop/to halt/to stand still" },
		{ "question": "立つ", "answers": [ "たつ" ], "comment": "(v5t) to stand" },
		{ "question": "立てる", "answers": [ "たてる" ], "comment": "(v1) to stand (something) up/to erect (something)" },
		{ "question": "立て替える", "answers": [ "たてかえる" ], "comment": "(v1) to pay in advance/to pay for another/to pay someone else's debt as a loan to him" },
		{ "question": "立体", "answers": [ "りったい" ], "comment": "(n) solid body" },
		{ "question": "立場", "answers": [ "たちば" ], "comment": "(n) standpoint/position/situation" },
		{ "question": "立方", "answers": [ "りっぽう" ], "comment": "(n) cube" },
		{ "question": "立法", "answers": [ "りっぽう" ], "comment": "(n) legislation/lawmaking" },
		{ "question": "立派", "answers": [ "りっぱ" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) splendid/fine/handsome/elegant/imposing/prominent/legal/legitimate" },
		{ "question": "章", "answers": [ "しょう" ], "comment": "(n) (1) chapter/section/(2) medal" },
		{ "question": "童話", "answers": [ "どうわ" ], "comment": "(n) fairy tale" },
		{ "question": "童謡", "answers": [ "どうよう" ], "comment": "(n) children's song/nursery rhyme" },
		{ "question": "端", "answers": [ "はし" ], "comment": "(n) end (e.g. of street)/edge/tip/margin/point" },
		{ "question": "競争", "answers": [ "きょうそう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) competition/contest" },
		{ "question": "競技", "answers": [ "きょうぎ" ], "comment": "(n) game/match/contest" },
		{ "question": "競馬", "answers": [ "けいば" ], "comment": "(n) horse racing" },
		{ "question": "竹", "answers": [ "たけ" ], "comment": "(n) bamboo/middle (of a three-tier ranking system)" },
		{ "question": "竿", "answers": [ "さお" ], "comment": "(n) rod/pole (e.g. for drying laundry)" },
		{ "question": "笑い", "answers": [ "わらい" ], "comment": "(n) laugh/laughter/smile" },
		{ "question": "笑う", "answers": [ "わらう" ], "comment": "(v5u) to laugh/to smile" },
		{ "question": "笑顔", "answers": [ "えがお" ], "comment": "(n) smiling face" },
		{ "question": "笛", "answers": [ "ふえ" ], "comment": "(n) flute/pipe" },
		{ "question": "符号", "answers": [ "ふごう" ], "comment": "(n) sign/mark/symbol" },
		{ "question": "筆", "answers": [ "ふで" ], "comment": "(n) writing brush" },
		{ "question": "筆者", "answers": [ "ひっしゃ" ], "comment": "(n) writer/author" },
		{ "question": "筆記", "answers": [ "ひっき" ], "comment": "(n,vs) (taking) notes/copying" },
		{ "question": "等", "answers": [ "など" ], "comment": "(n,n-suf,prt) (uk) et cetera/etc./and the like" },
		{ "question": "等しい", "answers": [ "ひとしい" ], "comment": "(adj) equal" },
		{ "question": "等分", "answers": [ "とうぶん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) division into equal parts" },
		{ "question": "等級", "answers": [ "とうきゅう" ], "comment": "(n) grade/class" },
		{ "question": "筋", "answers": [ "すじ" ], "comment": "(n) muscle/string/line/stripe/plot/plan/sinew" },
		{ "question": "筋肉", "answers": [ "きんにく" ], "comment": "(n) muscle/sinew" },
		{ "question": "筒", "answers": [ "つつ" ], "comment": "(n) pipe/tube" },
		{ "question": "答", "answers": [ "こたえ" ], "comment": "(n) answer/response" },
		{ "question": "答える", "answers": [ "こたえる" ], "comment": "(v1) to answer/to reply" },
		{ "question": "答案", "answers": [ "とうあん" ], "comment": "(n) examination paper/examination script" },
		{ "question": "策", "answers": [ "さく" ], "comment": "(n,n-suf) plan/policy" },
		{ "question": "箇条書", "answers": [ "かじょうがき" ], "comment": "(n) itemized form/itemization" },
		{ "question": "箒", "answers": [ "ほうき" ], "comment": "(oK) (n) broom" },
		{ "question": "算数", "answers": [ "さんすう" ], "comment": "(n) arithmetic" },
		{ "question": "算盤", "answers": [ "そろばん" ], "comment": "(n) abacus" },
		{ "question": "管", "answers": [ "かん","くだ" ], "comment": "(n,n-suf) pipe/tube" },
		{ "question": "管理", "answers": [ "かんり" ], "comment": "(n,vs) control/management (e.g. of a business)" },
		{ "question": "箱", "answers": [ "はこ" ], "comment": "(n) box" },
		{ "question": "箸", "answers": [ "はし" ], "comment": "(n) chopsticks" },
		{ "question": "節", "answers": [ "せつ","ふし" ], "comment": "(n-suf) tune/tone/knot/knob/point" },
		{ "question": "節約", "answers": [ "せつやく" ], "comment": "(n,vs) economising/saving" },
		{ "question": "範囲", "answers": [ "はんい" ], "comment": "(n) extent/scope/sphere/range" },
		{ "question": "築く", "answers": [ "きずく" ], "comment": "(v5k) to build/to pile up/to amass" },
		{ "question": "簡単", "answers": [ "かんたん" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) simple" },
		{ "question": "簡易", "answers": [ "かんい" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) simplicity/easiness/quasi-" },
		{ "question": "簡潔", "answers": [ "かんけつ" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) brevity/conciseness/simplicity" },
		{ "question": "簡素", "answers": [ "かんそ" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) simplicity/plain" },
		{ "question": "籠", "answers": [ "かご" ], "comment": "(n) basket/cage" },
		{ "question": "籠もる", "answers": [ "こもる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to seclude oneself/to be confined in/to be implied/to be stuffy" },
		{ "question": "米", "answers": [ "こめ" ], "comment": "(n) uncooked rice" },
		{ "question": "粉", "answers": [ "こな" ], "comment": "(n) flour/meal/powder" },
		{ "question": "粉々", "answers": [ "こなごな" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) in very small pieces" },
		{ "question": "粉末", "answers": [ "ふんまつ" ], "comment": "(n) fine powder" },
		{ "question": "粋", "answers": [ "いき","すい" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) chic/style/purity/essence" },
		{ "question": "粒", "answers": [ "つぶ" ], "comment": "(n,n-suf) grain" },
		{ "question": "粗い", "answers": [ "あらい" ], "comment": "(adj) coarse/rough" },
		{ "question": "粗末", "answers": [ "そまつ" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) crude/rough/plain/humble" },
		{ "question": "粘り", "answers": [ "ねばり" ], "comment": "(n) stickiness/viscosity" },
		{ "question": "粘る", "answers": [ "ねばる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to be sticky/to be adhesive/to persevere/to persist/to stick to" },
		{ "question": "粥", "answers": [ "かゆ" ], "comment": "(n) (rice) gruel" },
		{ "question": "精々", "answers": [ "せいぜい" ], "comment": "(adv) at the most/at best/to the utmost/as much (far) as possible" },
		{ "question": "精密", "answers": [ "せいみつ" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) precise/exact/detailed/minute/close" },
		{ "question": "精巧", "answers": [ "せいこう" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) elaborate/delicate/exquisite" },
		{ "question": "精神", "answers": [ "せいしん" ], "comment": "(n) mind/soul/heart/spirit/intention" },
		{ "question": "精算", "answers": [ "せいさん" ], "comment": "(n) exact calculation/squaring of accounts" },
		{ "question": "糊", "answers": [ "のり" ], "comment": "(n) paste/starch" },
		{ "question": "糸", "answers": [ "いと" ], "comment": "(n,n-suf) thread/yarn/string" },
		{ "question": "系統", "answers": [ "けいとう" ], "comment": "(n) system/family line/geological formation/lineage/ancestry" },
		{ "question": "約", "answers": [ "やく" ], "comment": "(adv,n) approximately/about/some" },
		{ "question": "約束", "answers": [ "やくそく" ], "comment": "(n,vs) arrangement/promise" },
		{ "question": "紅茶", "answers": [ "こうちゃ" ], "comment": "(n) black tea" },
		{ "question": "紅葉", "answers": [ "こうよう","もみじ" ], "comment": "(n) (1) (Japanese) maple" },
		{ "question": "納まる", "answers": [ "おさまる" ], "comment": "(v5r) (1) to be in one's place/to be installed/to settle into/(2) to be obtained/to be settled/to be paid/to be delivered" },
		{ "question": "納める", "answers": [ "おさめる" ], "comment": "(v1) to obtain/to reap/to pay/to supply/to accept" },
		{ "question": "納入", "answers": [ "のうにゅう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) payment/supply" },
		{ "question": "納得", "answers": [ "なっとく" ], "comment": "(n,vs) consent/assent/understanding/agreement/comprehension/grasp" },
		{ "question": "紐", "answers": [ "ひも" ], "comment": "(n) (1) string/cord/(2) pimp" },
		{ "question": "純情", "answers": [ "じゅんじょう" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) pure heart/naivete/self-sacrificing devotion" },
		{ "question": "純粋", "answers": [ "じゅんすい" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) pure/true/genuine/unmixed" },
		{ "question": "紙", "answers": [ "かみ" ], "comment": "(n) paper" },
		{ "question": "紙屑", "answers": [ "かみくず" ], "comment": "(n) wastepaper" },
		{ "question": "紙幣", "answers": [ "しへい" ], "comment": "(n) paper money/notes/bills" },
		{ "question": "級", "answers": [ "きゅう" ], "comment": "(n,n-suf) class, grade, rank/school class, grade" },
		{ "question": "紛らわしい", "answers": [ "まぎらわしい" ], "comment": "(adj) confusing/misleading/equivocal/ambiguous" },
		{ "question": "紛れる", "answers": [ "まぎれる" ], "comment": "(v1) to be diverted/to slip into" },
		{ "question": "紛争", "answers": [ "ふんそう" ], "comment": "(n) dispute/trouble/strife" },
		{ "question": "紛失", "answers": [ "ふんしつ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) losing something" },
		{ "question": "素", "answers": [ "そ","す","もと" ], "comment": "(adj-na,adj-no,n) prime" },
		{ "question": "素人", "answers": [ "しろうと" ], "comment": "(n) amateur/novice" },
		{ "question": "素早い", "answers": [ "すばやい" ], "comment": "(adj) fast/quick/prompt/agile" },
		{ "question": "素晴らしい", "answers": [ "すばらしい" ], "comment": "(adj) wonderful/splendid/magnificent" },
		{ "question": "素朴", "answers": [ "そぼく" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) simplicity/artlessness/naivete" },
		{ "question": "素材", "answers": [ "そざい" ], "comment": "(n) raw materials/subject matter" },
		{ "question": "素直", "answers": [ "すなお" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) obedient/meek/docile/unaffected" },
		{ "question": "素質", "answers": [ "そしつ" ], "comment": "(n) character/qualities/genius" },
		{ "question": "紡績", "answers": [ "ぼうせき" ], "comment": "(n) spinning" },
		{ "question": "索引", "answers": [ "さくいん" ], "comment": "(n) index/indices" },
		{ "question": "紫", "answers": [ "むらさき" ], "comment": "(n) purple colour/violet" },
		{ "question": "細い", "answers": [ "ほそい" ], "comment": "(adj) thin/slender/fine" },
		{ "question": "細かい", "answers": [ "こまかい" ], "comment": "(adj) (1) small/(2) fine/minute" },
		{ "question": "細やか", "answers": [ "こまやか" ], "comment": "(adj-na) meagre/modest" },
		{ "question": "細工", "answers": [ "さいく" ], "comment": "(n) work/craftsmanship/tactics/trick" },
		{ "question": "細胞", "answers": [ "さいぼう" ], "comment": "(n) cell (biology)" },
		{ "question": "細菌", "answers": [ "さいきん" ], "comment": "(n) bacillus/bacterium/germ" },
		{ "question": "紳士", "answers": [ "しんし" ], "comment": "(n) gentleman" },
		{ "question": "紹介", "answers": [ "しょうかい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) introduction" },
		{ "question": "紺", "answers": [ "こん" ], "comment": "(n) navy blue/deep blue" },
		{ "question": "終える", "answers": [ "おえる" ], "comment": "(v1) to finish" },
		{ "question": "終わり", "answers": [ "おわり" ], "comment": "(n) the end" },
		{ "question": "終了", "answers": [ "しゅうりょう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) end/close/termination" },
		{ "question": "終始", "answers": [ "しゅうし" ], "comment": "(adv,n,vs) (1) beginning and end/from beginning to end/doing a thing from beginning to end/(2) consistent(ly)" },
		{ "question": "終日", "answers": [ "しゅうじつ" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n-t) all day" },
		{ "question": "終点", "answers": [ "しゅうてん" ], "comment": "(n) terminus/last stop (e.g train)" },
		{ "question": "組", "answers": [ "くみ" ], "comment": "(n) class/group/team/set" },
		{ "question": "組み合わせる", "answers": [ "くみあわせる" ], "comment": "(v1) to join together/to combine/to join up" },
		{ "question": "組み立てる", "answers": [ "くみたてる" ], "comment": "(v1) to assemble/to set up/to construct" },
		{ "question": "組み込む", "answers": [ "くみこむ" ], "comment": "(v5m) to insert/to include/to cut in (printing)" },
		{ "question": "組む", "answers": [ "くむ" ], "comment": "(v5m) to put together" },
		{ "question": "組合", "answers": [ "くみあい" ], "comment": "(n) association/union" },
		{ "question": "組合せ", "answers": [ "くみあわせ" ], "comment": "(n) combination" },
		{ "question": "組織", "answers": [ "そしき" ], "comment": "(n,vs) (1) organization/(2) structure/construction/(3) tissue/(4) system" },
		{ "question": "経つ", "answers": [ "たつ" ], "comment": "(v5t) to pass/to lapse" },
		{ "question": "経る", "answers": [ "へる" ], "comment": "(v1) to pass/to elapse/to experience" },
		{ "question": "経営", "answers": [ "けいえい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) management/administration" },
		{ "question": "経度", "answers": [ "けいど" ], "comment": "(n) longitude" },
		{ "question": "経歴", "answers": [ "けいれき" ], "comment": "(n) personal history/career" },
		{ "question": "経済", "answers": [ "けいざい" ], "comment": "(n) economics/business/finance/economy" },
		{ "question": "経由", "answers": [ "けいゆ" ], "comment": "(n) go by the way/via" },
		{ "question": "経緯", "answers": [ "けいい", "いきさつ" ], "comment": "(n) (1) details/whole story/sequence of events/particulars/how it started/how things got this way/(2) complications/position" },
		{ "question": "経費", "answers": [ "けいひ" ], "comment": "(n) expenses/cost/outlay" },
		{ "question": "経路", "answers": [ "けいろ" ], "comment": "(n) course/route/channel" },
		{ "question": "経過", "answers": [ "けいか" ], "comment": "(n) passage/expiration/progress" },
		{ "question": "経験", "answers": [ "けいけん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) experience" },
		{ "question": "結び", "answers": [ "むすび" ], "comment": "(n) ending/conclusion/union" },
		{ "question": "結び付き", "answers": [ "むすびつき" ], "comment": "(n) connection/relation" },
		{ "question": "結び付く", "answers": [ "むすびつく" ], "comment": "(v5k) to be connected or related/to join together" },
		{ "question": "結び付ける", "answers": [ "むすびつける" ], "comment": "(v1) to combine/to join/to tie on/to attach with a knot" },
		{ "question": "結ぶ", "answers": [ "むすぶ" ], "comment": "(v5b) to tie/to bind/to link" },
		{ "question": "結合", "answers": [ "けつごう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) combination/union" },
		{ "question": "結婚", "answers": [ "けっこん" ], "comment": "(adj-no,n,vs) marriage" },
		{ "question": "結局", "answers": [ "けっきょく" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n) after all/eventually" },
		{ "question": "結成", "answers": [ "けっせい" ], "comment": "(n) formation" },
		{ "question": "結晶", "answers": [ "けっしょう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) crystal/crystallization" },
		{ "question": "結束", "answers": [ "けっそく" ], "comment": "(n) union/unity" },
		{ "question": "結果", "answers": [ "けっか" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n-t) result/consequence" },
		{ "question": "結核", "answers": [ "けっかく" ], "comment": "(n) tuberculosis/tubercule" },
		{ "question": "結構", "answers": [ "けっこう" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n-adv,n) (1) (uk) splendid/nice/wonderful/delicious/sweet/(2) (arch) construction/architecture/(3) well enough/tolerably" },
		{ "question": "結論", "answers": [ "けつろん" ], "comment": "(n) conclusion" },
		{ "question": "絞る", "answers": [ "しぼる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to press/to wring/to squeeze" },
		{ "question": "絡む", "answers": [ "からむ" ], "comment": "(v5m) to entangle/to entwine" },
		{ "question": "給う", "answers": [ "たまう" ], "comment": "(v5u) to receive/to grant" },
		{ "question": "給与", "answers": [ "きゅうよ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) allowance/grant/supply" },
		{ "question": "給仕", "answers": [ "きゅうじ" ], "comment": "(n) office boy (girl)/page/waiter" },
		{ "question": "給料", "answers": [ "きゅうりょう" ], "comment": "(n) salary/wages" },
		{ "question": "給食", "answers": [ "きゅうしょく" ], "comment": "(n,vs) school lunch/providing a meal" },
		{ "question": "統一", "answers": [ "とういつ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) unity/consolidation/uniformity/unification/compatible" },
		{ "question": "統制", "answers": [ "とうせい" ], "comment": "(n) regulation/control" },
		{ "question": "統合", "answers": [ "とうごう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) integration/unification/synthesis" },
		{ "question": "統治", "answers": [ "とうち" ], "comment": "(n,vs) rule/reign/government/governing" },
		{ "question": "統率", "answers": [ "とうそつ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) command/lead/generalship/leadership" },
		{ "question": "統計", "answers": [ "とうけい" ], "comment": "scattering/a scatter/dispersion" },
		{ "question": "絵", "answers": [ "え" ], "comment": "(n,n-suf) picture/drawing/painting/sketch" },
		{ "question": "絵の具", "answers": [ "えのぐ" ], "comment": "(n) colors/paints" },
		{ "question": "絵画", "answers": [ "かいが" ], "comment": "(n) picture" },
		{ "question": "絶えず", "answers": [ "たえず" ], "comment": "(adv) constantly" },
		{ "question": "絶える", "answers": [ "たえる" ], "comment": "(v1) to die out/to peter out/to become extinct" },
		{ "question": "絶対", "answers": [ "ぜったい" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n-adv,n) absolute/unconditional/absoluteness" },
		{ "question": "絶滅", "answers": [ "ぜつめつ" ], "comment": "(n) destruction/extinction" },
		{ "question": "絶版", "answers": [ "ぜっぱん" ], "comment": "(n) out of print" },
		{ "question": "絹", "answers": [ "きぬ" ], "comment": "(n) silk" },
		{ "question": "継ぐ", "answers": [ "つぐ" ], "comment": "(v5g) to succeed (someone in a business or inheritence)" },
		{ "question": "継目", "answers": [ "つぎめ" ], "comment": "(n) joint/seam" },
		{ "question": "継続", "answers": [ "けいぞく" ], "comment": "(n,vs) continuation" },
		{ "question": "続々", "answers": [ "ぞくぞく" ], "comment": "(n-adv) successively/one after another" },
		{ "question": "続き", "answers": [ "つづき" ], "comment": "(n,n-suf) sequel/continuation/(also suffix) continuation (in time and space)/second series/succession/spell" },
		{ "question": "続く", "answers": [ "つづく" ], "comment": "(v5k,vi) to be continued" },
		{ "question": "続ける", "answers": [ "つづける" ], "comment": "(v1,vt) to continue/to keep up/to keep on" },
		{ "question": "維持", "answers": [ "いじ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) maintenance/preservation" },
		{ "question": "綱", "answers": [ "つな" ], "comment": "(n) rope" },
		{ "question": "網", "answers": [ "あみ" ], "comment": "(n) net/network" },
		{ "question": "綴じる", "answers": [ "とじる" ], "comment": "(v1) to bind/to file" },
		{ "question": "綻びる", "answers": [ "ほころびる" ], "comment": "(v1) to come apart at the seams/to begin to open/to smile broadly" },
		{ "question": "綿", "answers": [ "めん","わた" ], "comment": "(n) cotton/padding" },
		{ "question": "緊張", "answers": [ "きんちょう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) tension/mental strain/nervousness" },
		{ "question": "緊急", "answers": [ "きんきゅう" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) urgent/pressing/emergency" },
		{ "question": "総会", "answers": [ "そうかい" ], "comment": "(n) general meeting" },
		{ "question": "総合", "answers": [ "そうごう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) synthesis/coordination/putting together/integration/composite" },
		{ "question": "総理大臣", "answers": [ "そうりだいじん" ], "comment": "Prime Minister" },
		{ "question": "緑", "answers": [ "みどり" ], "comment": "(n) greenery" },
		{ "question": "線", "answers": [ "せん" ], "comment": "(n,n-suf) line (also telephone, railway)/wire/beam" },
		{ "question": "線路", "answers": [ "せんろ" ], "comment": "(n) line/track/roadbed" },
		{ "question": "締める", "answers": [ "しめる" ], "comment": "(v1) to tie/to fasten" },
		{ "question": "締め切る", "answers": [ "しめきる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to shut up" },
		{ "question": "締切", "answers": [ "しめきり" ], "comment": "(n) closing/cut-off/end/deadline/Closed/No Entrance" },
		{ "question": "編む", "answers": [ "あむ" ], "comment": "(v5m) to knit" },
		{ "question": "編物", "answers": [ "あみもの" ], "comment": "(n) knitting/web" },
		{ "question": "編集", "answers": [ "へんしゅう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) editing/compilation/editorial (e.g. committee)" },
		{ "question": "緩い", "answers": [ "ゆるい" ], "comment": "(adj) loose/lenient/slow" },
		{ "question": "緩む", "answers": [ "ゆるむ" ], "comment": "(v5m) to become loose/to slacken" },
		{ "question": "緩める", "answers": [ "ゆるめる" ], "comment": "(v1) to loosen/to slow down" },
		{ "question": "緩やか", "answers": [ "ゆるやか" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) lenient" },
		{ "question": "緩和", "answers": [ "かんわ" ], "comment": "(n) relief/mitigation" },
		{ "question": "緯度", "answers": [ "いど" ], "comment": "(n) latitude (nav.)" },
		{ "question": "練る", "answers": [ "ねる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to knead/to work over/to polish up" },
		{ "question": "練習", "answers": [ "れんしゅう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) practice" },
		{ "question": "縁", "answers": [ "えん","ふち","へり" ], "comment": "(n) a means, e.g. of living" },
		{ "question": "縁側", "answers": [ "えんがわ" ], "comment": "(n) veranda/porch/balcony/open corridor" },
		{ "question": "縁談", "answers": [ "えんだん" ], "comment": "(n) marriage proposal/engagement" },
		{ "question": "縄", "answers": [ "なわ" ], "comment": "(n) rope/hemp" },
		{ "question": "縛る", "answers": [ "しばる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to tie/to bind" },
		{ "question": "縞", "answers": [ "しま" ], "comment": "(n) stripe" },
		{ "question": "縦", "answers": [ "たて" ], "comment": "(n) length/height" },
		{ "question": "縫う", "answers": [ "ぬう" ], "comment": "(v5u) to sew" },
		{ "question": "縮まる", "answers": [ "ちぢまる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to be shortened/to be contracted/to shrink" },
		{ "question": "縮む", "answers": [ "ちぢむ" ], "comment": "(v5m) to shrink/to be contracted" },
		{ "question": "縮める", "answers": [ "ちぢめる" ], "comment": "(v1) to shorten/to reduce/to boil down/to shrink" },
		{ "question": "縮れる", "answers": [ "ちぢれる" ], "comment": "(v1) to be wavy/to be curled" },
		{ "question": "縮小", "answers": [ "しゅくしょう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) reduction/curtailment" },
		{ "question": "繁栄", "answers": [ "はんえい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) prospering/prosperity/thriving/flourishing" },
		{ "question": "繁殖", "answers": [ "はんしょく" ], "comment": "(n) breed/multiply/increase/propagation" },
		{ "question": "繁盛", "answers": [ "はんじょう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) prosperity/flourishing/thriving" },
		{ "question": "繊維", "answers": [ "せんい" ], "comment": "(n) fibre/fiber/textile" },
		{ "question": "繋がり", "answers": [ "つながり" ], "comment": "(n) connection/link/relationship" },
		{ "question": "繋がる", "answers": [ "つながる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to be tied together/to be connected to/to be related to" },
		{ "question": "繋ぐ", "answers": [ "つなぐ" ], "comment": "(v5g) (uk) to tie/to fasten/to connect/to transfer (phone call)" },
		{ "question": "繋げる", "answers": [ "つなげる" ], "comment": "(v1) to connect" },
		{ "question": "織る", "answers": [ "おる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to weave" },
		{ "question": "織物", "answers": [ "おりもの" ], "comment": "(n) textile/fabric" },
		{ "question": "繕う", "answers": [ "つくろう" ], "comment": "(v5u) to mend/to repair/to fix/to patch up/to darn/to tidy up/to adjust/to trim" },
		{ "question": "繰り返す", "answers": [ "くりかえす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to repeat/to do something over again" },
		{ "question": "纏まり", "answers": [ "まとまり" ], "comment": "(n) conclusion/settlement/consistency" },
		{ "question": "纏まる", "answers": [ "まとまる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to be collected/to be settled/to be in order" },
		{ "question": "纏め", "answers": [ "まとめ" ], "comment": "(n) settlement/conclusion" },
		{ "question": "纏める", "answers": [ "まとめる" ], "comment": "(v1,vt) to put in order/to collect/to bring to a conclusion" },
		{ "question": "缶", "answers": [ "かん" ], "comment": "(n) can/tin" },
		{ "question": "缶詰", "answers": [ "かんづめ" ], "comment": "(n) packing (in cans)/canning/canned goods/tin can" },
		{ "question": "罪", "answers": [ "つみ" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) crime/fault/indiscretion" },
		{ "question": "置く", "answers": [ "おく" ], "comment": "(v5k) to put/to place" },
		{ "question": "罰", "answers": [ "ばつ" ], "comment": "(n,n-suf) punishment/penalty" },
		{ "question": "罰する", "answers": [ "ばっする" ], "comment": "(vs-s) to punish/to penalize" },
		{ "question": "署名", "answers": [ "しょめい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) signature" },
		{ "question": "罵る", "answers": [ "ののしる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to speak ill of/to abuse" },
		{ "question": "罹る", "answers": [ "かかる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to suffer from" },
		{ "question": "羊毛", "answers": [ "ようもう" ], "comment": "(n) wool" },
		{ "question": "美", "answers": [ "び" ], "comment": "(n,n-suf) beauty" },
		{ "question": "美しい", "answers": [ "うつくしい" ], "comment": "(adj) beautiful/lovely" },
		{ "question": "美人", "answers": [ "びじん" ], "comment": "(n) beautiful person (woman)" },
		{ "question": "美容", "answers": [ "びよう" ], "comment": "(n) beauty of figure or form" },
		{ "question": "美術", "answers": [ "びじゅつ" ], "comment": "(n) art/fine arts" },
		{ "question": "美術館", "answers": [ "びじゅつかん" ], "comment": "(n) art gallery/art museum" },
		{ "question": "群", "answers": [ "ぐん" ], "comment": "(n,n-suf) group (math)" },
		{ "question": "群がる", "answers": [ "むらがる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to swarm/to gather" },
		{ "question": "群れ", "answers": [ "むれ" ], "comment": "(n) group/crowd/flock/herd/bevy/school/swarm/cluster (of stars)/clump" },
		{ "question": "群衆", "answers": [ "ぐんしゅう" ], "comment": "(n) (social) group/crowd/throng/mob/multitude" },
		{ "question": "群集", "answers": [ "ぐんしゅう" ], "comment": "(n) (social) group/crowd/throng/mob/multitude" },
		{ "question": "羨ましい", "answers": [ "うらやましい" ], "comment": "(adj) envious/enviable" },
		{ "question": "羨む", "answers": [ "うらやむ" ], "comment": "(v5m) to envy" },
		{ "question": "義務", "answers": [ "ぎむ" ], "comment": "(n) duty/obligation/responsibility" },
		{ "question": "義理", "answers": [ "ぎり" ], "comment": "(n) duty/sense of duty/honor/decency/courtesy/debt of gratitude/social obligation" },
		{ "question": "羽", "answers": [ "はね" ], "comment": "(n-suf) counter for birds/counter for rabbits" },
		{ "question": "羽根", "answers": [ "はね" ], "comment": "(n) shuttlecock" },
		{ "question": "習う", "answers": [ "ならう" ], "comment": "(v5u) to learn" },
		{ "question": "習字", "answers": [ "しゅうじ" ], "comment": "(n) penmanship" },
		{ "question": "習慣", "answers": [ "しゅうかん" ], "comment": "(n) custom/habit/manners" },
		{ "question": "翻訳", "answers": [ "ほんやく" ], "comment": "(n,vs) translation/de-encryption/deciphering" },
		{ "question": "翼", "answers": [ "つばさ" ], "comment": "(n) wings" },
		{ "question": "老いる", "answers": [ "おいる" ], "comment": "(v1) to age/to grow old" },
		{ "question": "老ける", "answers": [ "ふける" ], "comment": "(v1) to age" },
		{ "question": "老人", "answers": [ "ろうじん" ], "comment": "(n) the aged/old person" },
		{ "question": "老衰", "answers": [ "ろうすい" ], "comment": "(n) senility/senile decay" },
		{ "question": "考え", "answers": [ "かんがえ" ], "comment": "(n) thinking/thought/ideas/intention" },
		{ "question": "考える", "answers": [ "かんがえる" ], "comment": "(v1) to consider" },
		{ "question": "考古学", "answers": [ "こうこがく" ], "comment": "(adj-no,n) archaeology" },
		{ "question": "考慮", "answers": [ "こうりょ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) consideration/taking into account" },
		{ "question": "者", "answers": [ "もの" ], "comment": "(n) person" },
		{ "question": "耐える", "answers": [ "たえる" ], "comment": "(v1) to bear/to stand/to endure/to put up with/to support/to withstand/to resist/to brave/to be fit for/to be equal to" },
		{ "question": "耕す", "answers": [ "たがやす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to till/to plow/to cultivate" },
		{ "question": "耕作", "answers": [ "こうさく" ], "comment": "(n,vs) cultivation/farming" },
		{ "question": "耕地", "answers": [ "こうち" ], "comment": "(n) arable land" },
		{ "question": "耳", "answers": [ "みみ" ], "comment": "(n) ear" },
		{ "question": "耳鼻科", "answers": [ "じびか" ], "comment": "(n) otolaryngology" },
		{ "question": "耽る", "answers": [ "ふける" ], "comment": "(v5r) to indulge in/to give oneself up to/to be obsessed by/to be engrossed in/to be lost in/to be absorbed in" },
		{ "question": "聖書", "answers": [ "せいしょ" ], "comment": "(n) Bible/scriptures" },
		{ "question": "聞き取り", "answers": [ "ききとり" ], "comment": "(n) listening comprehension" },
		{ "question": "聞く", "answers": [ "きく" ], "comment": "(v5k) to hear/to listen/to ask" },
		{ "question": "聞こえる", "answers": [ "きこえる" ], "comment": "(v1) to be heard/to be audible" },
		{ "question": "聳える", "answers": [ "そびえる" ], "comment": "(v1) to rise/to tower/to soar" },
		{ "question": "聴覚", "answers": [ "ちょうかく" ], "comment": "(n) the sense of hearing" },
		{ "question": "聴診器", "answers": [ "ちょうしんき" ], "comment": "(n) stethoscope" },
		{ "question": "聴講", "answers": [ "ちょうこう" ], "comment": "(n) lecture attendance/auditing" },
		{ "question": "職", "answers": [ "しょく" ], "comment": "(n,n-suf) employment" },
		{ "question": "職人", "answers": [ "しょくにん" ], "comment": "(n) worker/mechanic/artisan/craftsman" },
		{ "question": "職務", "answers": [ "しょくむ" ], "comment": "(n) professional duties" },
		{ "question": "職員", "answers": [ "しょくいん" ], "comment": "(n) staff member/personnel" },
		{ "question": "職場", "answers": [ "しょくば" ], "comment": "(n) one's post/place of work/workplace" },
		{ "question": "職業", "answers": [ "しょくぎょう" ], "comment": "(n) occupation/business" },
		{ "question": "肉", "answers": [ "にく" ], "comment": "(n) meat" },
		{ "question": "肉体", "answers": [ "にくたい" ], "comment": "(n) the body/the flesh" },
		{ "question": "肉親", "answers": [ "にくしん" ], "comment": "(n) blood relationship/blood relative" },
		{ "question": "肌", "answers": [ "はだ" ], "comment": "(n) skin/body/grain/texture/disposition" },
		{ "question": "肌着", "answers": [ "はだぎ" ], "comment": "(n) underwear/lingerie/singlet/chemise" },
		{ "question": "肘", "answers": [ "ひじ" ], "comment": "(n) (uk) elbow" },
		{ "question": "肝心", "answers": [ "かんじん" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) essential/fundamental/crucial/vital/main" },
		{ "question": "肝腎", "answers": [ "かんじん" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) essential/fundamental/crucial/vital/main" },
		{ "question": "股", "answers": [ "また","もも" ], "comment": "(n) thigh/femur" },
		{ "question": "肩", "answers": [ "かた" ], "comment": "(n) shoulder" },
		{ "question": "肯定", "answers": [ "こうてい" ], "comment": "(n) positive/affirmation" },
		{ "question": "育ち", "answers": [ "そだち" ], "comment": "(n) breeding/growth" },
		{ "question": "育つ", "answers": [ "そだつ" ], "comment": "(v5t,vi) to raise (child)/to be brought up/to grow (up)" },
		{ "question": "育てる", "answers": [ "そだてる" ], "comment": "(v1,vt) to raise/to rear/to bring up" },
		{ "question": "育児", "answers": [ "いくじ" ], "comment": "(n) childcare/nursing/upbringing" },
		{ "question": "育成", "answers": [ "いくせい" ], "comment": "(n) rearing/training/nurture/cultivation/promotion" },
		{ "question": "肺", "answers": [ "はい" ], "comment": "(n) lung" },
		{ "question": "胃", "answers": [ "い" ], "comment": "(n) stomach" },
		{ "question": "背", "answers": [ "せ","せい" ], "comment": "(n) height/stature" },
		{ "question": "背く", "answers": [ "そむく" ], "comment": "(v5k) to run counter to/to go against/to disobey/to infringe" },
		{ "question": "背中", "answers": [ "せなか" ], "comment": "(n) back (of body)" },
		{ "question": "背広", "answers": [ "せびろ" ], "comment": "(n) business suit" },
		{ "question": "背後", "answers": [ "はいご" ], "comment": "(n) back/rear" },
		{ "question": "背景", "answers": [ "はいけい" ], "comment": "(n) background/scenery/setting/circumstance" },
		{ "question": "背負う", "answers": [ "せおう" ], "comment": "(v5u) to be burdened with/to carry on back or shoulder" },
		{ "question": "胡椒", "answers": [ "こしょう" ], "comment": "(n) pepper" },
		{ "question": "胴", "answers": [ "どう" ], "comment": "(n) trunk/body/frame" },
		{ "question": "胸", "answers": [ "むね" ], "comment": "(n) breast/chest" },
		{ "question": "能", "answers": [ "のう" ], "comment": "(adv,n,vs) being skilled in/nicely/properly/well/skillfully/thoroughly" },
		{ "question": "能力", "answers": [ "のうりょく" ], "comment": "(n) ability/faculty" },
		{ "question": "能率", "answers": [ "のうりつ" ], "comment": "(n) efficiency" },
		{ "question": "脂", "answers": [ "あぶら" ], "comment": "(n) nicotine/resin/sleep in one's eyes (eye mucus)" },
		{ "question": "脂肪", "answers": [ "しぼう" ], "comment": "(n) fat/grease/blubber" },
		{ "question": "脅かす", "answers": [ "おどかす", "おびやかす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to threaten/to coerce" },
		{ "question": "脅迫", "answers": [ "きょうはく" ], "comment": "(n) threat/menace/coercion/terrorism" },
		{ "question": "脆い", "answers": [ "もろい" ], "comment": "(adj) brittle/fragile/tender-hearted" },
		{ "question": "脇", "answers": [ "わき" ], "comment": "(n) side" },
		{ "question": "脈", "answers": [ "みゃく" ], "comment": "(n) pulse" },
		{ "question": "脚本", "answers": [ "きゃくほん" ], "comment": "(n) scenario" },
		{ "question": "脚色", "answers": [ "きゃくしょく" ], "comment": "(n) dramatization (e.g. film)" },
		{ "question": "脱ぐ", "answers": [ "ぬぐ" ], "comment": "(v5g) to take off clothes" },
		{ "question": "脱する", "answers": [ "だっする" ], "comment": "(vs-s) to escape from/to get out" },
		{ "question": "脱出", "answers": [ "だっしゅつ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) escape" },
		{ "question": "脱線", "answers": [ "だっせん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) derailment/digression" },
		{ "question": "脱退", "answers": [ "だったい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) secession/retirement/withdrawal (e.g. from a lawsuit)" },
		{ "question": "脳", "answers": [ "のう" ], "comment": "(n) brain/memory" },
		{ "question": "腐る", "answers": [ "くさる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to rot/to go bad" },
		{ "question": "腐敗", "answers": [ "ふはい" ], "comment": "(n) decay/depravity" },
		{ "question": "腕", "answers": [ "うで" ], "comment": "(n) (1) arm/(2) skill" },
		{ "question": "腕前", "answers": [ "うでまえ" ], "comment": "(n) ability/skill/facility" },
		{ "question": "腫れる", "answers": [ "はれる" ], "comment": "(v1) to swell (from inflammation)/to become swollen" },
		{ "question": "腰", "answers": [ "こし" ], "comment": "(n) hip" },
		{ "question": "腰掛け", "answers": [ "こしかけ" ], "comment": "(n) seat/bench" },
		{ "question": "腰掛ける", "answers": [ "こしかける" ], "comment": "(v1) to sit (down)" },
		{ "question": "腸", "answers": [ "ちょう" ], "comment": "(n) guts/bowels/intestines" },
		{ "question": "腹", "answers": [ "はら" ], "comment": "(n) abdomen/belly/stomach" },
		{ "question": "腹立ち", "answers": [ "はらだち" ], "comment": "(n) anger" },
		{ "question": "腿", "answers": [ "もも" ], "comment": "(n) thigh/femur" },
		{ "question": "膜", "answers": [ "まく" ], "comment": "(n) membrane/film" },
		{ "question": "膝", "answers": [ "ひざ" ], "comment": "(n) knee/lap" },
		{ "question": "膨らます", "answers": [ "ふくらます" ], "comment": "(v5s) to swell/to expand/to inflate/to bulge" },
		{ "question": "膨らむ", "answers": [ "ふくらむ" ], "comment": "(v5m) to expand/to swell (out)/to get big/to become inflated" },
		{ "question": "膨れる", "answers": [ "ふくれる" ], "comment": "(v1) to get cross/to get sulky/to swell (out)/to expand/to be inflated/to distend/to bulge" },
		{ "question": "膨大", "answers": [ "ぼうだい" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) huge/bulky/enormous/extensive/swelling/expansion" },
		{ "question": "膨張", "answers": [ "ぼうちょう" ], "comment": "(n) expansion/swelling/increase/growth" },
		{ "question": "膳", "answers": [ "ぜん" ], "comment": "(n) (small) table/tray/meal" },
		{ "question": "臆病", "answers": [ "おくびょう" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) cowardice/timidity" },
		{ "question": "臨む", "answers": [ "のぞむ" ], "comment": "(v5m) to look out on/to face/to deal with/to attend (function)" },
		{ "question": "臨時", "answers": [ "りんじ" ], "comment": "(n) temporary/special/extraordinary" },
		{ "question": "自ずから", "answers": [ "おのずから" ], "comment": "(adv) naturally/as a matter of course" },
		{ "question": "自ら", "answers": [ "みずから" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n) for one's self/personally" },
		{ "question": "自主", "answers": [ "じしゅ" ], "comment": "(n) independence/autonomy" },
		{ "question": "自分", "answers": [ "じぶん" ], "comment": "(n) myself/oneself" },
		{ "question": "自動", "answers": [ "じどう" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) automatic/self-motion" },
		{ "question": "自動車", "answers": [ "じどうしゃ" ], "comment": "(n) automobile" },
		{ "question": "自在", "answers": [ "じざい" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) freely/at will" },
		{ "question": "自宅", "answers": [ "じたく" ], "comment": "(n) one's home" },
		{ "question": "自尊心", "answers": [ "じそんしん" ], "comment": "(n) self-respect/conceit" },
		{ "question": "自己", "answers": [ "じこ" ], "comment": "(n) self/oneself" },
		{ "question": "自慢", "answers": [ "じまん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) pride/boast" },
		{ "question": "自我", "answers": [ "じが" ], "comment": "(n) self/the ego" },
		{ "question": "自殺", "answers": [ "じさつ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) suicide" },
		{ "question": "自治", "answers": [ "じち" ], "comment": "(n) self-government/autonomy" },
		{ "question": "自然", "answers": [ "しぜん" ], "comment": "(adj-na,adv,n) nature/spontaneous" },
		{ "question": "自然科学", "answers": [ "しぜんかがく" ], "comment": "natural science" },
		{ "question": "自由", "answers": [ "じゆう" ], "comment": "(adj-na,exp,n) freedom/liberty/as it pleases you" },
		{ "question": "自立", "answers": [ "じりつ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) independence/self-reliance" },
		{ "question": "自習", "answers": [ "じしゅう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) self-study" },
		{ "question": "自衛", "answers": [ "じえい" ], "comment": "(n) self-defense" },
		{ "question": "自覚", "answers": [ "じかく" ], "comment": "(n) self-conscious" },
		{ "question": "自身", "answers": [ "じしん" ], "comment": "(n) by oneself/personally" },
		{ "question": "自転", "answers": [ "じてん" ], "comment": "(n) rotation/spin" },
		{ "question": "自転車", "answers": [ "じてんしゃ" ], "comment": "(n) bicycle" },
		{ "question": "自首", "answers": [ "じしゅ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) surrender/give oneself up" },
		{ "question": "臭い", "answers": [ "くさい" ], "comment": "(n) odour/scent/smell/stench/fragrance/aroma/perfume" },
		{ "question": "至る", "answers": [ "いたる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to come/to arrive" },
		{ "question": "至急", "answers": [ "しきゅう" ], "comment": "(adv,n) urgent/pressing" },
		{ "question": "致す", "answers": [ "いたす" ], "comment": "(v5s) (hum) to do" },
		{ "question": "興じる", "answers": [ "きょうじる" ], "comment": "(v1) to amuse oneself/to make merry" },
		{ "question": "興味", "answers": [ "きょうみ" ], "comment": "(n) interest (in something)" },
		{ "question": "興奮", "answers": [ "こうふん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) excitement/stimulation/agitation/arousal" },
		{ "question": "興業", "answers": [ "こうぎょう" ], "comment": "(n) industrial enterprise" },
		{ "question": "舌", "answers": [ "した" ], "comment": "(n) tongue" },
		{ "question": "舗装", "answers": [ "ほそう" ], "comment": "(n) pavement/road surface" },
		{ "question": "舞う", "answers": [ "まう" ], "comment": "(v5u,vi) to dance/to flutter about/to revolve" },
		{ "question": "舞台", "answers": [ "ぶたい" ], "comment": "(n) stage (theatre)" },
		{ "question": "舟", "answers": [ "ふね" ], "comment": "(n) ship/boat/watercraft/shipping/vessel/steamship" },
		{ "question": "航海", "answers": [ "こうかい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) sail/voyage" },
		{ "question": "航空", "answers": [ "こうくう" ], "comment": "(n) aviation/flying" },
		{ "question": "船", "answers": [ "ふね" ], "comment": "(n) ship/boat/watercraft/shipping/vessel/steamship" },
		{ "question": "船便", "answers": [ "ふなびん" ], "comment": "(n) surface mail (ship)" },
		{ "question": "船舶", "answers": [ "せんぱく" ], "comment": "(n) ship" },
		{ "question": "良い", "answers": [ "よい" ], "comment": "(adj) good/nice/pleasant/ok" },
		{ "question": "良し", "answers": [ "よし" ], "comment": "OK!/all right!" },
		{ "question": "良好", "answers": [ "りょうこう" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) favorable/satisfactory" },
		{ "question": "良心", "answers": [ "りょうしん" ], "comment": "(n) conscience" },
		{ "question": "良識", "answers": [ "りょうしき" ], "comment": "(n) good sense" },
		{ "question": "良質", "answers": [ "りょうしつ" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) good quality/superior quality" },
		{ "question": "色", "answers": [ "いろ" ], "comment": "(n) (1) colour/(2) sensuality/lust" },
		{ "question": "色彩", "answers": [ "しきさい" ], "comment": "(n) colour/hue/tints" },
		{ "question": "艶", "answers": [ "つや" ], "comment": "(n) gloss/glaze" },
		{ "question": "芝", "answers": [ "しば" ], "comment": "(n) lawn/sod/turf" },
		{ "question": "芝居", "answers": [ "しばい" ], "comment": "(n) play/drama" },
		{ "question": "芝生", "answers": [ "しばふ" ], "comment": "(n) lawn" },
		{ "question": "芯", "answers": [ "しん" ], "comment": "(n) core/heart/wick/marrow" },
		{ "question": "花", "answers": [ "はな" ], "comment": "(n) flower" },
		{ "question": "花びら", "answers": [ "はなびら" ], "comment": "(n) (flower) petal" },
		{ "question": "花壇", "answers": [ "かだん" ], "comment": "(n) flower bed" },
		{ "question": "花嫁", "answers": [ "はなよめ" ], "comment": "(n) bride" },
		{ "question": "花火", "answers": [ "はなび" ], "comment": "(n) fireworks" },
		{ "question": "花瓶", "answers": [ "かびん" ], "comment": "(n) (flower) vase" },
		{ "question": "花粉", "answers": [ "かふん" ], "comment": "(n) pollen" },
		{ "question": "花見", "answers": [ "はなみ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) cherry-blossom viewing/flower viewing" },
		{ "question": "芸", "answers": [ "げい" ], "comment": "(n) art/accomplishment/performance" },
		{ "question": "芸能", "answers": [ "げいのう" ], "comment": "(n) public entertainment/accomplishments/attainments" },
		{ "question": "芸術", "answers": [ "げいじゅつ" ], "comment": "(n) (fine) art/the arts" },
		{ "question": "芽", "answers": [ "め" ], "comment": "(n) sprout" },
		{ "question": "苗", "answers": [ "なえ" ], "comment": "(n) rice seedling" },
		{ "question": "若々しい", "answers": [ "わかわかしい" ], "comment": "(adj) youthful/young" },
		{ "question": "若い", "answers": [ "わかい" ], "comment": "(adj) young" },
		{ "question": "若干", "answers": [ "じゃっかん" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n) some/few/number of" },
		{ "question": "苦い", "answers": [ "にがい" ], "comment": "(adj) bitter" },
		{ "question": "苦しい", "answers": [ "くるしい" ], "comment": "(adj) painful/difficult" },
		{ "question": "苦しむ", "answers": [ "くるしむ" ], "comment": "(v5m) to suffer/to groan/to be worried" },
		{ "question": "苦労", "answers": [ "くろう" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n,vs) troubles/hardships" },
		{ "question": "苦心", "answers": [ "くしん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) pain/trouble/anxiety/diligence/hard work" },
		{ "question": "苦情", "answers": [ "くじょう" ], "comment": "(n) complaint/troubles/objection" },
		{ "question": "苦手", "answers": [ "にがて" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) poor (at)/weak (in)/dislike (of)" },
		{ "question": "苦痛", "answers": [ "くつう" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) pain/agony" },
		{ "question": "英和", "answers": [ "えいわ" ], "comment": "(n) English-Japanese (e.g. dictionary)" },
		{ "question": "英字", "answers": [ "えいじ" ], "comment": "(n) English letter (character)" },
		{ "question": "英文", "answers": [ "えいぶん" ], "comment": "(n) sentence in English" },
		{ "question": "英語", "answers": [ "えいご" ], "comment": "(n) the English language" },
		{ "question": "英雄", "answers": [ "えいゆう" ], "comment": "(n) hero/great man" },
		{ "question": "茂る", "answers": [ "しげる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to grow thick/to luxuriate/to be luxurious" },
		{ "question": "茎", "answers": [ "くき" ], "comment": "(n) stalk" },
		{ "question": "茶", "answers": [ "ちゃ" ], "comment": "(n) tea" },
		{ "question": "茶の湯", "answers": [ "ちゃのゆ" ], "comment": "(n) tea ceremony" },
		{ "question": "茶の間", "answers": [ "ちゃのま" ], "comment": "(n) living room (Japanese style)" },
		{ "question": "茶碗", "answers": [ "ちゃわん" ], "comment": "(n) rice bowl/tea cup/teacup" },
		{ "question": "茶色", "answers": [ "ちゃいろ" ], "comment": "(n) light brown/tawny" },
		{ "question": "草", "answers": [ "くさ" ], "comment": "(n) grass" },
		{ "question": "草履", "answers": [ "ぞうり" ], "comment": "(n) zoori (Japanese footwear)/sandals" },
		{ "question": "荒い", "answers": [ "あらい" ], "comment": "(adj) rough/rude/wild" },
		{ "question": "荒っぽい", "answers": [ "あらっぽい" ], "comment": "(adj) rough/rude" },
		{ "question": "荒らす", "answers": [ "あらす" ], "comment": "(v5s) (1) to lay waste/to devastate/to damage/(2) to invade/to break into" },
		{ "question": "荒れる", "answers": [ "あれる" ], "comment": "(v1) to be stormy/to be rough/to lose one's temper" },
		{ "question": "荒廃", "answers": [ "こうはい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) ruin" },
		{ "question": "荷", "answers": [ "に" ], "comment": "(n) load/baggage/cargo" },
		{ "question": "荷物", "answers": [ "にもつ" ], "comment": "(n) luggage" },
		{ "question": "荷造り", "answers": [ "にづくり" ], "comment": "(n,vs) packing/baling/crating" },
		{ "question": "莫大", "answers": [ "ばくだい" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) enormous/vast" },
		{ "question": "菌", "answers": [ "きん" ], "comment": "(n) germ/bacterium/bacillus" },
		{ "question": "菓子", "answers": [ "かし" ], "comment": "(n) pastry" },
		{ "question": "華々しい", "answers": [ "はなばなしい" ], "comment": "(adj) brilliant/magnificent/spectacular" },
		{ "question": "華やか", "answers": [ "はなやか" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) gay/showy/brilliant/gorgeous/florid" },
		{ "question": "華奢", "answers": [ "きゃしゃ" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) luxury/pomp/delicate/slender/gorgeous" },
		{ "question": "萎びる", "answers": [ "しなびる" ], "comment": "(v1) to wilt/to fade" },
		{ "question": "落し物", "answers": [ "おとしもの" ], "comment": "(n) lost property" },
		{ "question": "落す", "answers": [ "おとす" ], "comment": "(io) (v5s) to drop/to lose/to let fall" },
		{ "question": "落ち着き", "answers": [ "おちつき" ], "comment": "(n) calm/composure" },
		{ "question": "落ち込む", "answers": [ "おちこむ" ], "comment": "(v5m) to fall into/to feel down (sad)" },
		{ "question": "落下", "answers": [ "らっか" ], "comment": "(n,vs) fall/drop/come down" },
		{ "question": "落着く", "answers": [ "おちつく" ], "comment": "(v5k) to calm down/to settle down/to be steady/to settle in/to take up one's residence/to harmonize with/to match/to restore presence of mind" },
		{ "question": "落第", "answers": [ "らくだい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) failure/dropping out of a class" },
		{ "question": "落葉", "answers": [ "おちば" ], "comment": "(n,vs) fallen leaves/leaf litter/defoliation/shedding leaves" },
		{ "question": "葉", "answers": [ "は" ], "comment": "(n) leaf" },
		{ "question": "葉書", "answers": [ "はがき" ], "comment": "(n) postcard" },
		{ "question": "著しい", "answers": [ "いちじるしい" ], "comment": "(adj) remarkable/considerable" },
		{ "question": "著す", "answers": [ "あらわす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to write/to publish" },
		{ "question": "著名", "answers": [ "ちょめい" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) well-known/noted/celebrated" },
		{ "question": "著書", "answers": [ "ちょしょ" ], "comment": "(n) literary work/book" },
		{ "question": "著者", "answers": [ "ちょしゃ" ], "comment": "(n) author/writer" },
		{ "question": "葬る", "answers": [ "ほうむる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to bury/to inter/to entomb/to consign to oblivion/to shelve" },
		{ "question": "葬式", "answers": [ "そうしき" ], "comment": "(n) funeral" },
		{ "question": "蒔く", "answers": [ "まく" ], "comment": "(v5k) to sow (seeds)" },
		{ "question": "蒸し暑い", "answers": [ "むしあつい" ], "comment": "(adj) humid/sultry" },
		{ "question": "蒸す", "answers": [ "むす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to steam/to poultice/to be sultry" },
		{ "question": "蒸気", "answers": [ "じょうき" ], "comment": "(n) steam/vapour" },
		{ "question": "蒸溜", "answers": [ "じょうりゅう" ], "comment": "(n) distillation" },
		{ "question": "蒸発", "answers": [ "じょうはつ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) evaporation/unexplained disappearance" },
		{ "question": "蓄える", "answers": [ "たくわえる" ], "comment": "(v1) to store/to lay in stock" },
		{ "question": "蓄積", "answers": [ "ちくせき" ], "comment": "(n,vs) accumulation/accumulate/store" },
		{ "question": "蓋", "answers": [ "ふた" ], "comment": "(n) cover/lid/cap" },
		{ "question": "蔵", "answers": [ "くら" ], "comment": "(n) warehouse/cellar/magazine/granary/godown/depository/treasury/elevator" },
		{ "question": "蔵相", "answers": [ "ぞうしょう" ], "comment": "(n) Minister of Finance" },
		{ "question": "蕎麦", "answers": [ "そば" ], "comment": "(n) soba (buckwheat noodles)" },
		{ "question": "蕾", "answers": [ "つぼみ" ], "comment": "(n) bud/flower bud" },
		{ "question": "薄い", "answers": [ "うすい" ], "comment": "(adj) thin/weak/watery/diluted" },
		{ "question": "薄める", "answers": [ "うすめる" ], "comment": "(v1) to dilute/to water down" },
		{ "question": "薄弱", "answers": [ "はくじゃく" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) feebleness/weakness/weak" },
		{ "question": "薄暗い", "answers": [ "うすぐらい" ], "comment": "(adj) dim/gloomy" },
		{ "question": "薬", "answers": [ "くすり" ], "comment": "(n) medicine" },
		{ "question": "薬品", "answers": [ "やくひん" ], "comment": "(n) medicine(s)/chemical(s)" },
		{ "question": "薬局", "answers": [ "やっきょく" ], "comment": "(n) pharmacy/drugstore" },
		{ "question": "薬指", "answers": [ "くすりゆび" ], "comment": "(n) ring finger" },
		{ "question": "薬缶", "answers": [ "やかん" ], "comment": "(n) kettle" },
		{ "question": "藁", "answers": [ "わら" ], "comment": "(n) straw" },
		{ "question": "蘇る", "answers": [ "よみがえる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to be resurrected/to be revived/to be resuscitated/to be rehabilitated" },
		{ "question": "虎", "answers": [ "とら" ], "comment": "(n) tiger" },
		{ "question": "虫", "answers": [ "むし" ], "comment": "(n) insect" },
		{ "question": "虫歯", "answers": [ "むしば" ], "comment": "(n) cavity/tooth decay/decayed tooth/caries" },
		{ "question": "虹", "answers": [ "にじ" ], "comment": "(n) rainbow" },
		{ "question": "蚊", "answers": [ "か" ], "comment": "(n) mosquito" },
		{ "question": "蛇口", "answers": [ "じゃぐち" ], "comment": "(n) faucet/tap" },
		{ "question": "蛋白質", "answers": [ "たんぱくしつ" ], "comment": "(n) protein" },
		{ "question": "蛍光灯", "answers": [ "けいこうとう" ], "comment": "(n) fluorescent lamp/person who is slow to react" },
		{ "question": "蜂蜜", "answers": [ "はちみつ" ], "comment": "(n) honey" },
		{ "question": "蝋燭", "answers": [ "ろうそく" ], "comment": "(n) (uk) candle" },
		{ "question": "蝶", "answers": [ "ちょう" ], "comment": "(n) butterfly" },
		{ "question": "融資", "answers": [ "ゆうし" ], "comment": "(n) financing/loan" },
		{ "question": "融通", "answers": [ "ゆうずう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) lending (money)/accommodation/adaptability/versatility/finance" },
		{ "question": "血", "answers": [ "ち" ], "comment": "(n) blood/consanguinity" },
		{ "question": "血圧", "answers": [ "けつあつ" ], "comment": "(n) blood pressure" },
		{ "question": "血液", "answers": [ "けつえき" ], "comment": "(n) blood" },
		{ "question": "血管", "answers": [ "けっかん" ], "comment": "(n) blood vessel" },
		{ "question": "衆", "answers": [ "しゅう" ], "comment": "(n) masses/great number/the people" },
		{ "question": "衆議院", "answers": [ "しゅうぎいん" ], "comment": "(n) Lower House/House of Representatives" },
		{ "question": "行い", "answers": [ "おこない" ], "comment": "(io) (n) deed/conduct/behavior/action/asceticism" },
		{ "question": "行う", "answers": [ "おこなう" ], "comment": "(v5u) to perform/to do/to conduct oneself/to carry out" },
		{ "question": "行き", "answers": [ "いき","ゆき" ], "comment": "(n) going" },
		{ "question": "行き違い", "answers": [ "いきちがい" ], "comment": "(n) misunderstanding/estrangement/disagreement/crossing without meeting/going astray" },
		{ "question": "行く", "answers": [ "いく","ゆく" ], "comment": "(v5k-s) to go" },
		{ "question": "行事", "answers": [ "ぎょうじ" ], "comment": "(n) event/function" },
		{ "question": "行儀", "answers": [ "ぎょうぎ" ], "comment": "(n) manners" },
		{ "question": "行列", "answers": [ "ぎょうれつ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) (1) line/procession/(2) matrix (math)" },
		{ "question": "行動", "answers": [ "こうどう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) action/conduct/behaviour/mobilization" },
		{ "question": "行政", "answers": [ "ぎょうせい" ], "comment": "(n) administration" },
		{ "question": "行方", "answers": [ "ゆくえ" ], "comment": "(n) one's whereabouts" },
		{ "question": "行為", "answers": [ "こうい" ], "comment": "(n) act/deed/conduct" },
		{ "question": "行進", "answers": [ "こうしん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) march/parade" },
		{ "question": "街", "answers": [ "まち" ], "comment": "(n) (1) town/(2) street/road" },
		{ "question": "街角", "answers": [ "まちかど" ], "comment": "(n) street corner" },
		{ "question": "街道", "answers": [ "かいどう" ], "comment": "(n) highway" },
		{ "question": "街頭", "answers": [ "がいとう" ], "comment": "(n) in the street" },
		{ "question": "衛星", "answers": [ "えいせい" ], "comment": "(n) satellite" },
		{ "question": "衝撃", "answers": [ "しょうげき" ], "comment": "(n) shock/crash/impact/ballistic" },
		{ "question": "衝突", "answers": [ "しょうとつ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) collision/conflict" },
		{ "question": "衣料", "answers": [ "いりょう" ], "comment": "(n) clothing" },
		{ "question": "衣服", "answers": [ "いふく" ], "comment": "(n) clothes" },
		{ "question": "衣装", "answers": [ "いしょう" ], "comment": "(n) clothing/costume/outfit/garment/dress" },
		{ "question": "衣類", "answers": [ "いるい" ], "comment": "(n) clothes/clothing/garments" },
		{ "question": "衣食住", "answers": [ "いしょくじゅう" ], "comment": "(n) necessities of life (food, clothing, etc.)" },
		{ "question": "表", "answers": [ "おもて","ひょう" ], "comment": "(n,n-suf) table (e.g. Tab 1)/chart/list" },
		{ "question": "表す", "answers": [ "あらわす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to express/to show/to reveal" },
		{ "question": "表情", "answers": [ "ひょうじょう" ], "comment": "(n) facial expression" },
		{ "question": "表現", "answers": [ "ひょうげん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) expression/presentation/representation (math)" },
		{ "question": "表紙", "answers": [ "ひょうし" ], "comment": "(n) front cover/binding" },
		{ "question": "表面", "answers": [ "ひょうめん" ], "comment": "(n) surface/outside/face/appearance" },
		{ "question": "衰える", "answers": [ "おとろえる" ], "comment": "(v1) to become weak/to decline/to wear/to abate/to decay/to wither/to waste away" },
		{ "question": "袋", "answers": [ "ふくろ" ], "comment": "(n) bag/sack" },
		{ "question": "袖", "answers": [ "そで" ], "comment": "(n) sleeve" },
		{ "question": "被せる", "answers": [ "かぶせる" ], "comment": "(v1) to cover (with something)/to plate something (with a metal)/to pour or dash a liquid (on something)/to charge (a person with a guilt)" },
		{ "question": "被る", "answers": [ "かぶる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to suffer" },
		{ "question": "被害", "answers": [ "ひがい" ], "comment": "(n) damage" },
		{ "question": "裁く", "answers": [ "さばく" ], "comment": "(v5k) to judge" },
		{ "question": "裁判", "answers": [ "さいばん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) trial/judgement" },
		{ "question": "裁縫", "answers": [ "さいほう" ], "comment": "(n) sewing" },
		{ "question": "裂く", "answers": [ "さく" ], "comment": "(v5k) to tear/to split" },
		{ "question": "裂ける", "answers": [ "さける" ], "comment": "(v1) to split/to tear/to burst" },
		{ "question": "装備", "answers": [ "そうび" ], "comment": "(n) equipment" },
		{ "question": "装置", "answers": [ "そうち" ], "comment": "(n,vs) equipment/installation/apparatus" },
		{ "question": "装飾", "answers": [ "そうしょく" ], "comment": "(n) ornament" },
		{ "question": "裏", "answers": [ "うら" ], "comment": "(n) reverse side/wrong side/back/undersurface/inside/palm/sole/opposite/rear/lining/last half (of an inning)" },
		{ "question": "裏切る", "answers": [ "うらぎる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to betray/to turn traitor to/to double-cross" },
		{ "question": "裏口", "answers": [ "うらぐち" ], "comment": "(n) backdoor/rear entrance" },
		{ "question": "裏返し", "answers": [ "うらがえし" ], "comment": "(n) inside out/upside down" },
		{ "question": "裏返す", "answers": [ "うらがえす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to turn inside out/to turn the other way/to turn (something) over" },
		{ "question": "補う", "answers": [ "おぎなう" ], "comment": "(v5u) to compensate for" },
		{ "question": "補償", "answers": [ "ほしょう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) compensation/reparation" },
		{ "question": "補充", "answers": [ "ほじゅう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) supplementation/supplement/replenishment/replenishing" },
		{ "question": "補助", "answers": [ "ほじょ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) assistance/support/aid/auxiliary" },
		{ "question": "補強", "answers": [ "ほきょう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) compensation/reinforcement" },
		{ "question": "補給", "answers": [ "ほきゅう" ], "comment": "(n) supply/supplying/replenishment" },
		{ "question": "補足", "answers": [ "ほそく" ], "comment": "(n) supplement/complement" },
		{ "question": "裸", "answers": [ "はだか" ], "comment": "(adj-no,n) naked/nude/bare" },
		{ "question": "裸足", "answers": [ "はだし" ], "comment": "(n) barefoot" },
		{ "question": "製作", "answers": [ "せいさく" ], "comment": "(n,vs) manufacture/production" },
		{ "question": "製品", "answers": [ "せいひん" ], "comment": "(n) manufactured goods/finished goods" },
		{ "question": "製法", "answers": [ "せいほう" ], "comment": "(n) manufacturing method/recipe/formula" },
		{ "question": "製造", "answers": [ "せいぞう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) manufacture/production" },
		{ "question": "製鉄", "answers": [ "せいてつ" ], "comment": "(n) iron manufacture" },
		{ "question": "裾", "answers": [ "すそ" ], "comment": "(n) (trouser) cuff/(skirt) hem/cut edge of a hairdo/foot of mountain" },
		{ "question": "複写", "answers": [ "ふくしゃ" ], "comment": "(n) copy/duplicate" },
		{ "question": "複合", "answers": [ "ふくごう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) composite/complex" },
		{ "question": "複数", "answers": [ "ふくすう" ], "comment": "(n) plural/multiple" },
		{ "question": "複雑", "answers": [ "ふくざつ" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) complexity/complication" },
		{ "question": "褒める", "answers": [ "ほめる" ], "comment": "(v1) to praise/to admire/to speak well" },
		{ "question": "褒美", "answers": [ "ほうび" ], "comment": "(n) reward/prize" },
		{ "question": "襖", "answers": [ "ふすま" ], "comment": "(n) sliding screen" },
		{ "question": "襟", "answers": [ "えり" ], "comment": "(n) neck/collar/lapel/neckband" },
		{ "question": "襲う", "answers": [ "おそう" ], "comment": "(v5u) to attack" },
		{ "question": "襲撃", "answers": [ "しゅうげき" ], "comment": "(n) attack/charge/raid" },
		{ "question": "西", "answers": [ "にし" ], "comment": "(n) west" },
		{ "question": "西日", "answers": [ "にしび" ], "comment": "(n) westering sun" },
		{ "question": "西暦", "answers": [ "せいれき" ], "comment": "(n) Christian Era/anno domini (A.D.)" },
		{ "question": "西洋", "answers": [ "せいよう" ], "comment": "(n) the west/Western countries" },
		{ "question": "要する", "answers": [ "ようする" ], "comment": "(vs-s) to demand/to require/to take" },
		{ "question": "要するに", "answers": [ "ようするに" ], "comment": "(adv,exp) in a word/after all/the point is ../in short .." },
		{ "question": "要る", "answers": [ "いる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to need" },
		{ "question": "要因", "answers": [ "よういん" ], "comment": "(n) primary factor/main cause" },
		{ "question": "要旨", "answers": [ "ようし" ], "comment": "(n) gist/essentials/summary/fundamentals" },
		{ "question": "要望", "answers": [ "ようぼう" ], "comment": "(n) demand for/request" },
		{ "question": "要求", "answers": [ "ようきゅう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) request/demand/requisition" },
		{ "question": "要点", "answers": [ "ようてん" ], "comment": "(n) gist/main point" },
		{ "question": "要素", "answers": [ "ようそ" ], "comment": "(n) element" },
		{ "question": "要請", "answers": [ "ようせい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) claim/demand/request/application" },
		{ "question": "要領", "answers": [ "ようりょう" ], "comment": "(n) point/gist/essentials/outline" },
		{ "question": "覆う", "answers": [ "おおう" ], "comment": "(v5u) to cover/to hide/to conceal/to wrap/to disguise" },
		{ "question": "覆す", "answers": [ "くつがえす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to overturn/to upset/to overthrow/to undermine" },
		{ "question": "覆面", "answers": [ "ふくめん" ], "comment": "(n) mask/veil/disguise" },
		{ "question": "見える", "answers": [ "みえる" ], "comment": "(v1) to be seen/to be in sight/to look/to seem/to appear" },
		{ "question": "見せびらかす", "answers": [ "みせびらかす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to show off/to flaunt" },
		{ "question": "見せる", "answers": [ "みせる" ], "comment": "(v1) to show/to display" },
		{ "question": "見せ物", "answers": [ "みせもの" ], "comment": "(n) show/exhibition" },
		{ "question": "見つかる", "answers": [ "みつかる" ], "comment": "(v5r) (uk) to be found/to be discovered" },
		{ "question": "見つける", "answers": [ "みつける" ], "comment": "(v1) to be familiar/to discover/to find fault/to detect/to find out/to locate" },
		{ "question": "見る", "answers": [ "みる" ], "comment": "(v1) to see/to watch" },
		{ "question": "見上げる", "answers": [ "みあげる" ], "comment": "(v1) to look up at/to raise one's eyes/to admire" },
		{ "question": "見下ろす", "answers": [ "みおろす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to overlook/to command a view of/to look down on something" },
		{ "question": "見事", "answers": [ "みごと" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) splendid/magnificent/beautiful/admirable" },
		{ "question": "見付かる", "answers": [ "みつかる" ], "comment": "(v5r) (uk) to be found/to be discovered" },
		{ "question": "見付ける", "answers": [ "みつける" ], "comment": "(v1) to be familiar/to discover/to find fault/to detect/to find out/to locate" },
		{ "question": "見出し", "answers": [ "みだし" ], "comment": "(n) heading/caption/subtitle/index" },
		{ "question": "見合い", "answers": [ "みあい" ], "comment": "(n) formal marriage interview" },
		{ "question": "見合わせる", "answers": [ "みあわせる" ], "comment": "(v1) to exchange glances/to postpone/to suspend operations/to refrain from performing an action" },
		{ "question": "見地", "answers": [ "けんち" ], "comment": "(n) point of view" },
		{ "question": "見学", "answers": [ "けんがく" ], "comment": "(n,vs) inspection/study by observation/field trip" },
		{ "question": "見当", "answers": [ "けんとう" ], "comment": "(n) be found/aim/mark/estimate/guess/approx/direction" },
		{ "question": "見慣れる", "answers": [ "みなれる" ], "comment": "(v1) to become used to seeing/to be familiar with" },
		{ "question": "見掛け", "answers": [ "みかけ" ], "comment": "(n) outward appearance" },
		{ "question": "見掛ける", "answers": [ "みかける" ], "comment": "(v1) to (happen to) see/to notice/to catch sight of" },
		{ "question": "見晴らし", "answers": [ "みはらし" ], "comment": "(n) view" },
		{ "question": "見本", "answers": [ "みほん" ], "comment": "(n) sample" },
		{ "question": "見渡す", "answers": [ "みわたす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to look out over/to survey (scene)/to take an extensive view of" },
		{ "question": "見物", "answers": [ "けんぶつ" ], "comment": "(n) a sight/an attraction/something worth seeing" },
		{ "question": "見直す", "answers": [ "みなおす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to look again/to get a better opinion of" },
		{ "question": "見積もり", "answers": [ "みつもり" ], "comment": "(n) estimation/quotation" },
		{ "question": "見習う", "answers": [ "みならう" ], "comment": "(v5u) to follow another's example" },
		{ "question": "見舞い", "answers": [ "みまい" ], "comment": "(n) enquiry/expression of sympathy/expression of concern" },
		{ "question": "見舞う", "answers": [ "みまう" ], "comment": "(v5u) to ask after (health)/to visit" },
		{ "question": "見苦しい", "answers": [ "みぐるしい" ], "comment": "(adj) unsightly/ugly" },
		{ "question": "見落とす", "answers": [ "みおとす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to overlook/to fail to notice" },
		{ "question": "見解", "answers": [ "けんかい" ], "comment": "(n) opinion/point of view" },
		{ "question": "見計らう", "answers": [ "みはからう" ], "comment": "(v5u) to choose at one's own discretion" },
		{ "question": "見詰める", "answers": [ "みつめる" ], "comment": "(v1) (uk) to stare at/to gaze at/to look hard at/to watch intently/to fix one's eyes on" },
		{ "question": "見込み", "answers": [ "みこみ" ], "comment": "(n) forecast/prospects/expectation/hope" },
		{ "question": "見送り", "answers": [ "みおくり" ], "comment": "(n) seeing one off/farewell/escort" },
		{ "question": "見送る", "answers": [ "みおくる" ], "comment": "(v5r) (1) to see off/to farewell/(2) to escort/(3) to let pass/to wait and see/(4) to let a pitch go by (baseball)/to watch a batted ball go into the stands" },
		{ "question": "見逃す", "answers": [ "みのがす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to miss/to overlook/to leave at large" },
		{ "question": "見通し", "answers": [ "みとおし" ], "comment": "(n) perspective/unobstructed view/outlook/forecast/prospect/insight" },
		{ "question": "規制", "answers": [ "きせい" ], "comment": "(n) regulation" },
		{ "question": "規則", "answers": [ "きそく" ], "comment": "(n) rule/regulations" },
		{ "question": "規定", "answers": [ "きてい" ], "comment": "(adj-no,n,vs) regulation/provisions" },
		{ "question": "規律", "answers": [ "きりつ" ], "comment": "(n) order/rules/law" },
		{ "question": "規格", "answers": [ "きかく" ], "comment": "(n) standard/norm" },
		{ "question": "規模", "answers": [ "きぼ" ], "comment": "(n) scale/scope/plan/structure" },
		{ "question": "規準", "answers": [ "きじゅん" ], "comment": "(n) standard/basis/criteria/norm" },
		{ "question": "規範", "answers": [ "きはん" ], "comment": "(n) model/standard/pattern/norm/criterion/example" },
		{ "question": "規約", "answers": [ "きやく" ], "comment": "(n) agreement/rules/code" },
		{ "question": "視察", "answers": [ "しさつ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) inspection/observation" },
		{ "question": "視点", "answers": [ "してん" ], "comment": "(n) opinion/point of view/visual point" },
		{ "question": "視覚", "answers": [ "しかく" ], "comment": "(n) sense of sight/vision" },
		{ "question": "視野", "answers": [ "しや" ], "comment": "(n) field of vision/outlook" },
		{ "question": "覗く", "answers": [ "のぞく" ], "comment": "(v5k) to peep in/to look in/to peek in/to stick out" },
		{ "question": "覚え", "answers": [ "おぼえ" ], "comment": "(n) memory/sense/experience" },
		{ "question": "覚える", "answers": [ "おぼえる" ], "comment": "(v1) to remember/to memorize" },
		{ "question": "覚ます", "answers": [ "さます" ], "comment": "(v5s) to awaken" },
		{ "question": "覚める", "answers": [ "さめる" ], "comment": "(v1) to wake/to wake up" },
		{ "question": "覚悟", "answers": [ "かくご" ], "comment": "(n,vs) resolution/resignation/readiness/preparedness" },
		{ "question": "親", "answers": [ "おや" ], "comment": "(n) parents" },
		{ "question": "親しい", "answers": [ "したしい" ], "comment": "(adj) intimate/close (e.g. friend)" },
		{ "question": "親しむ", "answers": [ "したしむ" ], "comment": "(v5m) to be intimate with/to befriend" },
		{ "question": "親切", "answers": [ "しんせつ" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) kindness/gentleness" },
		{ "question": "親友", "answers": [ "しんゆう" ], "comment": "(n) close friend/bosom (old, intimate) friend/buddy/crony/chum" },
		{ "question": "親善", "answers": [ "しんぜん" ], "comment": "(n) friendship" },
		{ "question": "親戚", "answers": [ "しんせき" ], "comment": "(n) relative" },
		{ "question": "親指", "answers": [ "おやゆび" ], "comment": "(n) thumb" },
		{ "question": "親父", "answers": [ "おやじ" ], "comment": "(gikun) (n) one's father/old man/one's boss" },
		{ "question": "親類", "answers": [ "しんるい" ], "comment": "(n) relation/kin" },
		{ "question": "観光", "answers": [ "かんこう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) sightseeing" },
		{ "question": "観客", "answers": [ "かんきゃく" ], "comment": "(n) audience/spectator(s)" },
		{ "question": "観察", "answers": [ "かんさつ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) observation/survey" },
		{ "question": "観念", "answers": [ "かんねん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) (1) idea/notion/conception/(2) sense (e.g. of duty)/(3) resignation/preparedness/acceptance" },
		{ "question": "観測", "answers": [ "かんそく" ], "comment": "(n,vs) observation" },
		{ "question": "観点", "answers": [ "かんてん" ], "comment": "(n) point of view" },
		{ "question": "観衆", "answers": [ "かんしゅう" ], "comment": "(n) spectators/onlookers/members of the audience" },
		{ "question": "観覧", "answers": [ "かんらん" ], "comment": "(n) viewing" },
		{ "question": "角", "answers": [ "かく","かど","すみ","つの" ], "comment": "(n) horn" },
		{ "question": "角度", "answers": [ "かくど" ], "comment": "(n) angle" },
		{ "question": "解く", "answers": [ "とく" ], "comment": "(v5k) to unfasten" },
		{ "question": "解ける", "answers": [ "とける","ほどける" ], "comment": "(v1) to come untied/to come apart" },
		{ "question": "解剖", "answers": [ "かいぼう" ], "comment": "(n) dissection/autopsy" },
		{ "question": "解放", "answers": [ "かいほう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) release/liberation/emancipation" },
		{ "question": "解散", "answers": [ "かいさん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) breakup/dissolution" },
		{ "question": "解決", "answers": [ "かいけつ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) settlement/solution/resolution" },
		{ "question": "解答", "answers": [ "かいとう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) answer/solution" },
		{ "question": "解説", "answers": [ "かいせつ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) explanation/commentary" },
		{ "question": "解釈", "answers": [ "かいしゃく" ], "comment": "(n,vs) explanation/interpretation" },
		{ "question": "解除", "answers": [ "かいじょ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) cancellation/rescinding/release/calling off" },
		{ "question": "触る", "answers": [ "さわる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to touch/to feel" },
		{ "question": "触れる", "answers": [ "ふれる" ], "comment": "(v1) to touch/to be touched/to touch on a subject/to feel/to violate (law, copyright, etc.)/to perceive/to be emotionally moved" },
		{ "question": "言い付ける", "answers": [ "いいつける" ], "comment": "(v1) to tell/to tell on (someone)/to order/to charge/to direct" },
		{ "question": "言い出す", "answers": [ "いいだす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to start talking/to speak/to tell/to propose/to suggest/to break the ice" },
		{ "question": "言い訳", "answers": [ "いいわけ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) excuse/explanation" },
		{ "question": "言う", "answers": [ "いう","ゆう" ], "comment": "(v5u) to say" },
		{ "question": "言わば", "answers": [ "いわば" ], "comment": "(adv) so to speak" },
		{ "question": "言付け", "answers": [ "ことづけ" ], "comment": "(n) (verbal) message" },
		{ "question": "言付ける", "answers": [ "ことづける" ], "comment": "(v1) to send word/to send a message" },
		{ "question": "言葉", "answers": [ "ことば" ], "comment": "(n) word(s)/language/speech" },
		{ "question": "言葉遣い", "answers": [ "ことばづかい" ], "comment": "(n) speech/expression/wording" },
		{ "question": "言語", "answers": [ "げんご" ], "comment": "(n) language" },
		{ "question": "言論", "answers": [ "げんろん" ], "comment": "(n) discussion" },
		{ "question": "訂正", "answers": [ "ていせい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) correction/revision" },
		{ "question": "計", "answers": [ "けい" ], "comment": "(n,n-suf) plan" },
		{ "question": "計る", "answers": [ "はかる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to measure/to weigh/to survey/to time (sound, gauge, estimate)" },
		{ "question": "計器", "answers": [ "けいき" ], "comment": "(n) meter/gauge" },
		{ "question": "計画", "answers": [ "けいかく" ], "comment": "(n,vs) plan/project/schedule/scheme/program" },
		{ "question": "計算", "answers": [ "けいさん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) calculation/reckoning" },
		{ "question": "討つ", "answers": [ "うつ" ], "comment": "(v5t) to attack/to avenge" },
		{ "question": "討論", "answers": [ "とうろん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) debate/discussion" },
		{ "question": "討議", "answers": [ "とうぎ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) debate/discussion" },
		{ "question": "訓", "answers": [ "くん" ], "comment": "(n) native Japanese reading (rendering) of a Chinese character" },
		{ "question": "訓練", "answers": [ "くんれん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) practice/training" },
		{ "question": "記す", "answers": [ "しるす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to note/to write down" },
		{ "question": "記事", "answers": [ "きじ" ], "comment": "(n) article/news story/report/account" },
		{ "question": "記入", "answers": [ "きにゅう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) entry/filling in of forms" },
		{ "question": "記号", "answers": [ "きごう" ], "comment": "(n) symbol/code" },
		{ "question": "記名", "answers": [ "きめい" ], "comment": "(n) signature/register" },
		{ "question": "記念", "answers": [ "きねん" ], "comment": "(n) commemoration/memory" },
		{ "question": "記憶", "answers": [ "きおく" ], "comment": "(n,vs) memory/recollection/remembrance" },
		{ "question": "記者", "answers": [ "きしゃ" ], "comment": "(n) reporter" },
		{ "question": "記載", "answers": [ "きさい" ], "comment": "(n) mention/entry" },
		{ "question": "記述", "answers": [ "きじゅつ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) describing/descriptor" },
		{ "question": "記録", "answers": [ "きろく" ], "comment": "(n,vs) record/minutes/document" },
		{ "question": "訪ねる", "answers": [ "たずねる" ], "comment": "(v1) to visit" },
		{ "question": "訪れる", "answers": [ "おとずれる" ], "comment": "(v1) to visit" },
		{ "question": "訪問", "answers": [ "ほうもん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) call/visit" },
		{ "question": "設ける", "answers": [ "もうける" ], "comment": "(v1) to create/to establish" },
		{ "question": "設備", "answers": [ "せつび" ], "comment": "(n,vs) equipment/device/facilities/installation" },
		{ "question": "設定", "answers": [ "せってい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) establishment/creation" },
		{ "question": "設立", "answers": [ "せつりつ" ], "comment": "(n) establishment/foundation/institution" },
		{ "question": "設置", "answers": [ "せっち" ], "comment": "(n) establishment/institution" },
		{ "question": "設計", "answers": [ "せっけい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) plan/design" },
		{ "question": "許す", "answers": [ "ゆるす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to permit/to allow/to approve/to exempt (from fine)/to excuse (from)/to confide in/to forgive/to pardon/to excuse/to release/to let off" },
		{ "question": "許可", "answers": [ "きょか" ], "comment": "(n,vs) permission/approval" },
		{ "question": "許容", "answers": [ "きょよう" ], "comment": "(n) permission/pardon" },
		{ "question": "訳", "answers": [ "やく","わけ" ], "comment": "(n) (uk) meaning/reason/circumstances/can be deduced/situation" },
		{ "question": "訳す", "answers": [ "やくす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to translate" },
		{ "question": "訴え", "answers": [ "うったえ" ], "comment": "(n) lawsuit/complaint" },
		{ "question": "訴える", "answers": [ "うったえる" ], "comment": "(v1) to sue (a person)/to resort to/to appeal to" },
		{ "question": "訴訟", "answers": [ "そしょう" ], "comment": "(n) litigation/lawsuit" },
		{ "question": "診る", "answers": [ "みる" ], "comment": "(v1) to examine (medical)" },
		{ "question": "診察", "answers": [ "しんさつ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) medical examination" },
		{ "question": "診断", "answers": [ "しんだん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) diagnosis" },
		{ "question": "診療", "answers": [ "しんりょう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) medical examination and treatment/diagnosis" },
		{ "question": "証拠", "answers": [ "しょうこ" ], "comment": "(n) evidence/proof" },
		{ "question": "証明", "answers": [ "しょうめい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) proof/verification" },
		{ "question": "証言", "answers": [ "しょうげん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) evidence/testimony" },
		{ "question": "詐欺", "answers": [ "さぎ" ], "comment": "(n) fraud/swindle" },
		{ "question": "評価", "answers": [ "ひょうか" ], "comment": "(n,vs) valuation/estimation/assessment/evaluation" },
		{ "question": "評判", "answers": [ "ひょうばん" ], "comment": "(adj-no,n) fame/reputation/popularity/arrant" },
		{ "question": "評論", "answers": [ "ひょうろん" ], "comment": "(n) criticism/critique" },
		{ "question": "試し", "answers": [ "ためし" ], "comment": "(n) trial/test" },
		{ "question": "試す", "answers": [ "ためす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to attempt/to test" },
		{ "question": "試み", "answers": [ "こころみ" ], "comment": "(n) trial/experiment" },
		{ "question": "試みる", "answers": [ "こころみる" ], "comment": "(v1) to try/to test" },
		{ "question": "試合", "answers": [ "しあい" ], "comment": "(n) match/game/bout/contest" },
		{ "question": "試験", "answers": [ "しけん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) examination/test/study" },
		{ "question": "詩", "answers": [ "し" ], "comment": "(n) poem/verse of poetry" },
		{ "question": "詩人", "answers": [ "しじん" ], "comment": "(n) poet" },
		{ "question": "詫び", "answers": [ "わび" ], "comment": "(n) apology" },
		{ "question": "詫びる", "answers": [ "わびる" ], "comment": "(v1) to apologize" },
		{ "question": "詰まる", "answers": [ "つまる" ], "comment": "(v5r) (1) to be blocked/to be packed/(2) to hit the ball near the handle of the bat (baseball)" },
		{ "question": "詰める", "answers": [ "つめる" ], "comment": "(v1) to pack/to shorten/to work out (details)" },
		{ "question": "詰る", "answers": [ "なじる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to rebuke/to scold/to tell off" },
		{ "question": "話", "answers": [ "はなし" ], "comment": "(io) (n) talk/speech/chat/story/conversation" },
		{ "question": "話し合う", "answers": [ "はなしあう" ], "comment": "(v5u) to discuss/to talk together" },
		{ "question": "話し掛ける", "answers": [ "はなしかける" ], "comment": "(v1) to accost a person/to talk (to someone)" },
		{ "question": "話す", "answers": [ "はなす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to speak" },
		{ "question": "話中", "answers": [ "はなしちゅう" ], "comment": "(n) while talking/the line is busy" },
		{ "question": "話合い", "answers": [ "はなしあい" ], "comment": "(n) discussion/conference" },
		{ "question": "話題", "answers": [ "わだい" ], "comment": "(n) topic/subject" },
		{ "question": "該当", "answers": [ "がいとう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) corresponding/answering to/coming under" },
		{ "question": "詳しい", "answers": [ "くわしい" ], "comment": "(adj) knowing very well/detailed/full/accurate" },
		{ "question": "詳細", "answers": [ "しょうさい" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) detail/particulars" },
		{ "question": "誇り", "answers": [ "ほこり" ], "comment": "(n) pride" },
		{ "question": "誇る", "answers": [ "ほこる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to boast of/to be proud of" },
		{ "question": "誇張", "answers": [ "こちょう" ], "comment": "(n) exaggeration" },
		{ "question": "認める", "answers": [ "みとめる" ], "comment": "(v1,vt) to recognize/to appreciate/to approve/to admit/to notice" },
		{ "question": "認識", "answers": [ "にんしき" ], "comment": "(n,vs) recognition/cognizance" },
		{ "question": "誓う", "answers": [ "ちかう" ], "comment": "(v5u) to swear/to vow/to take an oath/to pledge" },
		{ "question": "誕生", "answers": [ "たんじょう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) birth" },
		{ "question": "誕生日", "answers": [ "たんじょうび" ], "comment": "(n) birthday" },
		{ "question": "誘う", "answers": [ "さそう" ], "comment": "(v5u) (1) to invite/to ask/to call (for)/(2) to tempt/to lure/to induce" },
		{ "question": "誘導", "answers": [ "ゆうどう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) guidance/leading/induction/introduction/incitement/inducement" },
		{ "question": "誘惑", "answers": [ "ゆうわく" ], "comment": "(n,vs) temptation/allurement/lure" },
		{ "question": "語", "answers": [ "ご" ], "comment": "(n,n-suf) language/word" },
		{ "question": "語る", "answers": [ "かたる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to talk/to tell/to recite" },
		{ "question": "語句", "answers": [ "ごく" ], "comment": "(n) words/phrases" },
		{ "question": "語学", "answers": [ "ごがく" ], "comment": "(n) language study" },
		{ "question": "語彙", "answers": [ "ごい" ], "comment": "(n) vocabulary/glossary" },
		{ "question": "語源", "answers": [ "ごげん" ], "comment": "(n) word root/word derivation/etymology" },
		{ "question": "誠", "answers": [ "まこと" ], "comment": "(adv,n) truth/faith/fidelity/sincerity/trust/confidence/reliance/devotion" },
		{ "question": "誠実", "answers": [ "せいじつ" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) sincere/honest/faithful" },
		{ "question": "誤り", "answers": [ "あやまり" ], "comment": "(n) error" },
		{ "question": "誤る", "answers": [ "あやまる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to make a mistake" },
		{ "question": "誤差", "answers": [ "ごさ" ], "comment": "(n) error" },
		{ "question": "誤解", "answers": [ "ごかい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) misunderstanding" },
		{ "question": "説", "answers": [ "せつ" ], "comment": "(n,n-suf) theory" },
		{ "question": "説く", "answers": [ "とく" ], "comment": "(v5k) to explain/to advocate/to preach/to persuade" },
		{ "question": "説得", "answers": [ "せっとく" ], "comment": "(n) persuasion" },
		{ "question": "説明", "answers": [ "せつめい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) explanation/exposition" },
		{ "question": "読み", "answers": [ "よみ" ], "comment": "(n) reading" },
		{ "question": "読み上げる", "answers": [ "よみあげる" ], "comment": "(v1) to read out loud (and clearly)/to call a roll" },
		{ "question": "読む", "answers": [ "よむ" ], "comment": "(v5m) to read" },
		{ "question": "読書", "answers": [ "どくしょ" ], "comment": "(n) reading" },
		{ "question": "誰", "answers": [ "だれ" ], "comment": "(n) who" },
		{ "question": "誰か", "answers": [ "だれか" ], "comment": "(n) (uk) someone/somebody" },
		{ "question": "課", "answers": [ "か" ], "comment": "(n,n-suf) counter for chapters (of a book)" },
		{ "question": "課外", "answers": [ "かがい" ], "comment": "(n) extracurricular" },
		{ "question": "課程", "answers": [ "かてい" ], "comment": "(n) course/curriculum" },
		{ "question": "課税", "answers": [ "かぜい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) taxation" },
		{ "question": "課題", "answers": [ "かだい" ], "comment": "(n) subject/theme/task" },
		{ "question": "調べ", "answers": [ "しらべ" ], "comment": "(n,n-suf) preparation/investigation/inspection" },
		{ "question": "調べる", "answers": [ "しらべる" ], "comment": "(v1,vt) to investigate/to check up" },
		{ "question": "調停", "answers": [ "ちょうてい" ], "comment": "(n) arbitration/conciliation/mediation" },
		{ "question": "調印", "answers": [ "ちょういん" ], "comment": "(n) signature/sign/sealing" },
		{ "question": "調味料", "answers": [ "ちょうみりょう" ], "comment": "(n) condiment/seasoning" },
		{ "question": "調和", "answers": [ "ちょうわ" ], "comment": "(n) harmony" },
		{ "question": "調子", "answers": [ "ちょうし" ], "comment": "(n) tune/tone/key/pitch/time/rhythm/vein/mood/way/manner/style/knack/condition/state of health/strain/impetus/spur of the moment/trend" },
		{ "question": "調整", "answers": [ "ちょうせい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) regulation/adjustment/tuning" },
		{ "question": "調査", "answers": [ "ちょうさ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) investigation/examination/inquiry/survey" },
		{ "question": "調理", "answers": [ "ちょうり" ], "comment": "(n,vs) cooking" },
		{ "question": "調節", "answers": [ "ちょうせつ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) regulation/adjustment/control" },
		{ "question": "請求", "answers": [ "せいきゅう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) claim/demand/application/request" },
		{ "question": "論じる", "answers": [ "ろんじる" ], "comment": "(v1) to argue/to discuss/to debate" },
		{ "question": "論ずる", "answers": [ "ろんずる" ], "comment": "(v5z) to argue/to discuss/to debate" },
		{ "question": "論争", "answers": [ "ろんそう" ], "comment": "(n) controversy/dispute" },
		{ "question": "論文", "answers": [ "ろんぶん" ], "comment": "(n) thesis/essay/treatise/paper" },
		{ "question": "論理", "answers": [ "ろんり" ], "comment": "(n) logic" },
		{ "question": "論議", "answers": [ "ろんぎ" ], "comment": "(n) discussion" },
		{ "question": "諦め", "answers": [ "あきらめ" ], "comment": "(n) resignation/acceptance/consolation" },
		{ "question": "諦める", "answers": [ "あきらめる" ], "comment": "(v1) to give up/to abandon" },
		{ "question": "諮る", "answers": [ "はかる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to consult with/to confer" },
		{ "question": "諸君", "answers": [ "しょくん" ], "comment": "(n) Gentlemen!/Ladies!" },
		{ "question": "諺", "answers": [ "ことわざ" ], "comment": "(n) proverb/maxim" },
		{ "question": "謎", "answers": [ "なぞ" ], "comment": "(n) riddle/puzzle/enigma" },
		{ "question": "謎謎", "answers": [ "なぞなぞ" ], "comment": "(n) riddle/puzzle/enigma" },
		{ "question": "謙虚", "answers": [ "けんきょ" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) modesty/humility" },
		{ "question": "謙遜", "answers": [ "けんそん" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) humble/humility/modesty" },
		{ "question": "講堂", "answers": [ "こうどう" ], "comment": "(n) auditorium" },
		{ "question": "講師", "answers": [ "こうし" ], "comment": "(n) lecturer" },
		{ "question": "講演", "answers": [ "こうえん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) lecture/address" },
		{ "question": "講義", "answers": [ "こうぎ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) lecture" },
		{ "question": "講習", "answers": [ "こうしゅう" ], "comment": "(n) short course/training" },
		{ "question": "講読", "answers": [ "こうどく" ], "comment": "(n,vs) reading/translation" },
		{ "question": "謝る", "answers": [ "あやまる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to apologize" },
		{ "question": "謝絶", "answers": [ "しゃぜつ" ], "comment": "(n) refusal" },
		{ "question": "謹む", "answers": [ "つつしむ" ], "comment": "(v5m) to be careful/to be chaste or discreet/to abstain or refrain" },
		{ "question": "警備", "answers": [ "けいび" ], "comment": "(n,vs) defense/guard/policing/security" },
		{ "question": "警告", "answers": [ "けいこく" ], "comment": "(n,vs) warning/advice" },
		{ "question": "警官", "answers": [ "けいかん" ], "comment": "(n) policeman" },
		{ "question": "警察", "answers": [ "けいさつ" ], "comment": "(n) police" },
		{ "question": "警戒", "answers": [ "けいかい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) warning/admonition/vigilance" },
		{ "question": "警部", "answers": [ "けいぶ" ], "comment": "(n) police inspector" },
		{ "question": "議事堂", "answers": [ "ぎじどう" ], "comment": "(n) Diet building" },
		{ "question": "議会", "answers": [ "ぎかい" ], "comment": "(n) Diet/congress/parliament" },
		{ "question": "議員", "answers": [ "ぎいん" ], "comment": "(n) member of the Diet, congress or parliament" },
		{ "question": "議案", "answers": [ "ぎあん" ], "comment": "(n) legislative bill" },
		{ "question": "議決", "answers": [ "ぎけつ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) resolution/decision/vote" },
		{ "question": "議論", "answers": [ "ぎろん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) argument/discussion/dispute" },
		{ "question": "議長", "answers": [ "ぎちょう" ], "comment": "(n) chairman" },
		{ "question": "議題", "answers": [ "ぎだい" ], "comment": "(n) topic of discussion/agenda" },
		{ "question": "譲る", "answers": [ "ゆずる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to turn over/to assign/to hand over/to transmit/to convey/to sell/to dispose of/to yield/to surrender" },
		{ "question": "譲歩", "answers": [ "じょうほ" ], "comment": "(n) concession/conciliation/compromise" },
		{ "question": "護衛", "answers": [ "ごえい" ], "comment": "(n) guard/convoy/escort" },
		{ "question": "谷", "answers": [ "たに" ], "comment": "(n) valley" },
		{ "question": "豆", "answers": [ "まめ" ], "comment": "(n) beans/peas" },
		{ "question": "豊か", "answers": [ "ゆたか" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) abundant/wealthy/plentiful/rich" },
		{ "question": "豊作", "answers": [ "ほうさく" ], "comment": "(n) abundant harvest/bumper crop" },
		{ "question": "豊富", "answers": [ "ほうふ" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) abundance/wealth/plenty/bounty" },
		{ "question": "豚肉", "answers": [ "ぶたにく" ], "comment": "(n) pork" },
		{ "question": "象", "answers": [ "ぞう" ], "comment": "(n) elephant" },
		{ "question": "象徴", "answers": [ "しょうちょう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) symbol" },
		{ "question": "豪華", "answers": [ "ごうか" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) wonderful/gorgeous/splendor/pomp/extravagance" },
		{ "question": "貝", "answers": [ "かい" ], "comment": "(n) shell/shellfish" },
		{ "question": "貝殻", "answers": [ "かいがら" ], "comment": "(n) shell" },
		{ "question": "負う", "answers": [ "おう" ], "comment": "(v5u) to bear/to owe" },
		{ "question": "負かす", "answers": [ "まかす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to defeat" },
		{ "question": "負け", "answers": [ "まけ" ], "comment": "(n) defeat/loss/losing (a game)" },
		{ "question": "負ける", "answers": [ "まける" ], "comment": "(v1) to lose/to be defeated" },
		{ "question": "負債", "answers": [ "ふさい" ], "comment": "(n) debt/liabilities" },
		{ "question": "負傷", "answers": [ "ふしょう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) injury/wound" },
		{ "question": "負担", "answers": [ "ふたん" ], "comment": "(n) burden/charge/responsibility" },
		{ "question": "財", "answers": [ "ざい" ], "comment": "(n,n-suf) fortune/riches" },
		{ "question": "財布", "answers": [ "さいふ" ], "comment": "(n) purse/wallet" },
		{ "question": "財政", "answers": [ "ざいせい" ], "comment": "(n) economy/financial affairs" },
		{ "question": "財源", "answers": [ "ざいげん" ], "comment": "(n) source of funds/resources/finances" },
		{ "question": "財産", "answers": [ "ざいさん" ], "comment": "(n) property/fortune/assets" },
		{ "question": "貢献", "answers": [ "こうけん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) contribution/services" },
		{ "question": "貧しい", "answers": [ "まずしい" ], "comment": "(adj) poor/needy" },
		{ "question": "貧乏", "answers": [ "びんぼう" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) poverty/destitute/poor" },
		{ "question": "貧困", "answers": [ "ひんこん" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) poverty/lack" },
		{ "question": "貧弱", "answers": [ "ひんじゃく" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) poor/meagre/insubstantial" },
		{ "question": "貨幣", "answers": [ "かへい" ], "comment": "(n) money/currency/coinage" },
		{ "question": "貨物", "answers": [ "かもつ" ], "comment": "(n) cargo/freight" },
		{ "question": "販売", "answers": [ "はんばい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) sale/selling/marketing" },
		{ "question": "貫く", "answers": [ "つらぬく" ], "comment": "(v5k) to go through" },
		{ "question": "貫禄", "answers": [ "かんろく" ], "comment": "(n) presence/dignity" },
		{ "question": "責める", "answers": [ "せめる" ], "comment": "(v1) to condemn/to blame/to criticize" },
		{ "question": "責任", "answers": [ "せきにん" ], "comment": "(n) duty/responsibility" },
		{ "question": "責務", "answers": [ "せきむ" ], "comment": "(n) duty/obligation" },
		{ "question": "貯蓄", "answers": [ "ちょちく" ], "comment": "(n) savings" },
		{ "question": "貯蔵", "answers": [ "ちょぞう" ], "comment": "(n) storage/preservation" },
		{ "question": "貯金", "answers": [ "ちょきん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) (bank) savings" },
		{ "question": "貰う", "answers": [ "もらう" ], "comment": "(v5u) (uk) to receive" },
		{ "question": "貴い", "answers": [ "とうとい" ], "comment": "(adj) precious/valuable/priceless/noble/exalted/sacred" },
		{ "question": "貴族", "answers": [ "きぞく" ], "comment": "(adj-no,n) noble/aristocrat" },
		{ "question": "貴重", "answers": [ "きちょう" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) precious/valuable" },
		{ "question": "買い物", "answers": [ "かいもの" ], "comment": "(n) shopping" },
		{ "question": "買う", "answers": [ "かう" ], "comment": "(v5u) to buy" },
		{ "question": "貸し", "answers": [ "かし" ], "comment": "(n) loan/lending" },
		{ "question": "貸し出し", "answers": [ "かしだし" ], "comment": "(n,vs) lending/loaning" },
		{ "question": "貸す", "answers": [ "かす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to lend" },
		{ "question": "貸家", "answers": [ "かしや" ], "comment": "(n) house for rent" },
		{ "question": "貸間", "answers": [ "かしま" ], "comment": "(n) room to let" },
		{ "question": "費やす", "answers": [ "ついやす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to spend/to devote/to waste" },
		{ "question": "費用", "answers": [ "ひよう" ], "comment": "(n) cost/expense" },
		{ "question": "貼る", "answers": [ "はる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to stick/to paste" },
		{ "question": "貿易", "answers": [ "ぼうえき" ], "comment": "(n) trade (foreign)" },
		{ "question": "賃金", "answers": [ "ちんぎん" ], "comment": "(n) wages" },
		{ "question": "賄う", "answers": [ "まかなう" ], "comment": "(v5u) to give board to/to provide meals/to pay" },
		{ "question": "資料", "answers": [ "しりょう" ], "comment": "(n) materials/data" },
		{ "question": "資本", "answers": [ "しほん" ], "comment": "(n) funds/capital" },
		{ "question": "資格", "answers": [ "しかく" ], "comment": "(n) qualifications/requirements/capabilities" },
		{ "question": "資源", "answers": [ "しげん" ], "comment": "(n) resources" },
		{ "question": "資産", "answers": [ "しさん" ], "comment": "(n) property/fortune/means/assets" },
		{ "question": "資金", "answers": [ "しきん" ], "comment": "(n) funds/capital" },
		{ "question": "賑やか", "answers": [ "にぎやか" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) bustling/busy" },
		{ "question": "賑わう", "answers": [ "にぎわう" ], "comment": "(v5u) to prosper/to flourish/to do thriving business/to be crowded with people" },
		{ "question": "賛成", "answers": [ "さんせい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) approval/agreement/support/favour" },
		{ "question": "賛美", "answers": [ "さんび" ], "comment": "(n,vs) praise/adoration/glorification" },
		{ "question": "賜る", "answers": [ "たまわる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to grant/to bestow" },
		{ "question": "賞", "answers": [ "しょう" ], "comment": "(n,n-suf) prize/award" },
		{ "question": "賞品", "answers": [ "しょうひん" ], "comment": "(n) prize/trophy" },
		{ "question": "賞金", "answers": [ "しょうきん" ], "comment": "(n) prize/monetary award" },
		{ "question": "賠償", "answers": [ "ばいしょう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) reparations/indemnity/compensation" },
		{ "question": "賢い", "answers": [ "かしこい" ], "comment": "(adj) wise/clever/smart" },
		{ "question": "賢明", "answers": [ "けんめい" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) wisdom/intelligence/prudence" },
		{ "question": "質", "answers": [ "しつ" ], "comment": "(n) quality/nature (of person)" },
		{ "question": "質問", "answers": [ "しつもん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) question/inquiry" },
		{ "question": "質疑", "answers": [ "しつぎ" ], "comment": "(n) question" },
		{ "question": "質素", "answers": [ "しっそ" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) simplicity/modesty/frugality" },
		{ "question": "賭", "answers": [ "かけ" ], "comment": "(n) betting/gambling/a gamble" },
		{ "question": "賭ける", "answers": [ "かける" ], "comment": "(v1) to wager/to bet/to risk/to stake/to gamble" },
		{ "question": "購入", "answers": [ "こうにゅう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) purchase/buy" },
		{ "question": "購読", "answers": [ "こうどく" ], "comment": "(n,vs) subscription (e.g. magazine)" },
		{ "question": "購買", "answers": [ "こうばい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) purchase/buy" },
		{ "question": "贅沢", "answers": [ "ぜいたく" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) luxury/extravagance" },
		{ "question": "贈り物", "answers": [ "おくりもの" ], "comment": "(n) present/gift" },
		{ "question": "贈る", "answers": [ "おくる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to send/to give to/to award to/to confer on" },
		{ "question": "贋物", "answers": [ "にせもの" ], "comment": "(n) imitation/counterfeit/forgery/sham" },
		{ "question": "赤い", "answers": [ "あかい" ], "comment": "(adj) red" },
		{ "question": "赤らむ", "answers": [ "あからむ" ], "comment": "(v5m) to become red/to redden/to blush" },
		{ "question": "赤ん坊", "answers": [ "あかんぼう" ], "comment": "(n) baby" },
		{ "question": "赤字", "answers": [ "あかじ" ], "comment": "(n) deficit/go in the red" },
		{ "question": "赤道", "answers": [ "せきどう" ], "comment": "(n) equator" },
		{ "question": "走る", "answers": [ "はしる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to run" },
		{ "question": "走行", "answers": [ "そうこう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) running a wheeled vehicle (e.g. car)/traveling" },
		{ "question": "赴く", "answers": [ "おもむく" ], "comment": "(v5k) to go/to proceed/to repair to/to become" },
		{ "question": "赴任", "answers": [ "ふにん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) (proceeding to) new appointment" },
		{ "question": "起きる", "answers": [ "おきる" ], "comment": "(v1) to get up/to rise" },
		{ "question": "起こる", "answers": [ "おこる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to occur/to happen" },
		{ "question": "起す", "answers": [ "おこす" ], "comment": "(io) (v5s) to raise/to cause/to wake someone" },
		{ "question": "起伏", "answers": [ "きふく" ], "comment": "(n) undulation" },
		{ "question": "起床", "answers": [ "きしょう" ], "comment": "(n) rising/getting out of bed" },
		{ "question": "起源", "answers": [ "きげん" ], "comment": "(n) origin/beginning/rise" },
		{ "question": "起点", "answers": [ "きてん" ], "comment": "(n) starting point" },
		{ "question": "超", "answers": [ "ちょう" ], "comment": "(n,n-suf,pref) super-/ultra-/hyper-" },
		{ "question": "超える", "answers": [ "こえる" ], "comment": "(v1) to exceed/to cross over/to cross/to pass through/to pass over (out of)" },
		{ "question": "超す", "answers": [ "こす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to cross/to pass/to tide over" },
		{ "question": "超過", "answers": [ "ちょうか" ], "comment": "(n,vs) excess/being more than" },
		{ "question": "越える", "answers": [ "こえる" ], "comment": "(v1) to exceed/to cross over/to cross/to pass through/to pass over (out of)" },
		{ "question": "越す", "answers": [ "こす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to go over (e.g. with audience)" },
		{ "question": "趣", "answers": [ "おもむき" ], "comment": "(n) (1) meaning/tenor/gist/(2) effect/influence/(3) appearance/aspect/(4) taste/(5) grace/charm/refinement" },
		{ "question": "趣味", "answers": [ "しゅみ" ], "comment": "(n) hobby/tastes/preference" },
		{ "question": "趣旨", "answers": [ "しゅし" ], "comment": "(n) object/meaning" },
		{ "question": "足", "answers": [ "あし" ], "comment": "(n) foot/pace/gait/leg" },
		{ "question": "足し算", "answers": [ "たしざん" ], "comment": "(n) addition" },
		{ "question": "足す", "answers": [ "たす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to add (numbers)/to do (e.g. one's business)" },
		{ "question": "足りる", "answers": [ "たりる" ], "comment": "(v1) to be sufficient/to be enough" },
		{ "question": "足る", "answers": [ "たる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to be sufficient/to be enough" },
		{ "question": "足元", "answers": [ "あしもと" ], "comment": "(n) (1) at one's feet/underfoot/(2) gait/pace/step" },
		{ "question": "足袋", "answers": [ "たび" ], "comment": "(n) tabi/Japanese socks (with split toe)" },
		{ "question": "足跡", "answers": [ "あしあと" ], "comment": "(n) footprints" },
		{ "question": "跡", "answers": [ "あと" ], "comment": "(n) (1) trace/tracks/mark/sign/(2) remains/ruins/(3) scar" },
		{ "question": "跡継ぎ", "answers": [ "あとつぎ" ], "comment": "(n) heir/successor" },
		{ "question": "跳ねる", "answers": [ "はねる" ], "comment": "(v1) to jump/to leap/to prance/to spring up/to bound/to hop" },
		{ "question": "跳ぶ", "answers": [ "とぶ" ], "comment": "(v5b) to jump/to fly/to leap/to spring/to bound/to hop" },
		{ "question": "踊り", "answers": [ "おどり" ], "comment": "(n) dance" },
		{ "question": "踊る", "answers": [ "おどる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to dance" },
		{ "question": "踏まえる", "answers": [ "ふまえる" ], "comment": "(v1) to be based on/to have origin in" },
		{ "question": "踏み込む", "answers": [ "ふみこむ" ], "comment": "(v5m) to step into (someone else's territory)/to break into/to raid" },
		{ "question": "踏む", "answers": [ "ふむ" ], "comment": "(v5m) to step on/to tread on" },
		{ "question": "踏切", "answers": [ "ふみきり" ], "comment": "(n) railway crossing/level crossing/starting line/scratch/crossover" },
		{ "question": "蹴る", "answers": [ "ける" ], "comment": "(v5r) to kick" },
		{ "question": "蹴飛ばす", "answers": [ "けとばす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to kick away/to kick off/to kick (someone)/to refuse/to reject" },
		{ "question": "身", "answers": [ "み" ], "comment": "(n) body/main part/oneself/sword" },
		{ "question": "身なり", "answers": [ "みなり" ], "comment": "(n) personal appearance" },
		{ "question": "身の上", "answers": [ "みのうえ" ], "comment": "(n) one's future/one's welfare/one's personal history" },
		{ "question": "身の回り", "answers": [ "みのまわり" ], "comment": "(n) one's personal appearance/personal belongings" },
		{ "question": "身体", "answers": [ "しんたい" ], "comment": "(n) the body" },
		{ "question": "身分", "answers": [ "みぶん" ], "comment": "(n) social position/social status" },
		{ "question": "身振り", "answers": [ "みぶり" ], "comment": "(n) gesture" },
		{ "question": "身近", "answers": [ "みぢか" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) near oneself/close to one/familiar" },
		{ "question": "身長", "answers": [ "しんちょう" ], "comment": "(n) height (of body)/stature" },
		{ "question": "躾", "answers": [ "しつけ" ], "comment": "(n) home discipline/training/upbringing/breeding" },
		{ "question": "躾ける", "answers": [ "しつける" ], "comment": "(v1) to train/to discipline/to teach manners" },
		{ "question": "車", "answers": [ "くるま" ], "comment": "(n) car/vehicle/wheel" },
		{ "question": "車庫", "answers": [ "しゃこ" ], "comment": "(n) garage/car shed" },
		{ "question": "車掌", "answers": [ "しゃしょう" ], "comment": "(n) (train) conductor" },
		{ "question": "車輪", "answers": [ "しゃりん" ], "comment": "(n) (car) wheel" },
		{ "question": "軌道", "answers": [ "きどう" ], "comment": "(n) (1) orbit/(2) railroad track" },
		{ "question": "軍", "answers": [ "ぐん" ], "comment": "(n,n-suf) army/force/troops" },
		{ "question": "軍事", "answers": [ "ぐんじ" ], "comment": "(n) military affairs" },
		{ "question": "軍備", "answers": [ "ぐんび" ], "comment": "(n) armaments/military preparations" },
		{ "question": "軍服", "answers": [ "ぐんぷく" ], "comment": "(n) military or naval uniform" },
		{ "question": "軍艦", "answers": [ "ぐんかん" ], "comment": "(n) warship/battleship" },
		{ "question": "軍隊", "answers": [ "ぐんたい" ], "comment": "(n) army/troops" },
		{ "question": "軒", "answers": [ "けん","のき" ], "comment": "(n) eaves" },
		{ "question": "軒並", "answers": [ "のきなみ" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n) row of houses" },
		{ "question": "軟らかい", "answers": [ "やわらかい" ], "comment": "(adj) soft/tender/limp" },
		{ "question": "転がす", "answers": [ "ころがす" ], "comment": "(v5s,vt) to roll" },
		{ "question": "転がる", "answers": [ "ころがる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to roll/to tumble" },
		{ "question": "転じる", "answers": [ "てんじる" ], "comment": "(v1) to turn/to shift/to alter/to distract" },
		{ "question": "転ずる", "answers": [ "てんずる" ], "comment": "(v5z) to turn/to shift/to alter/to distract" },
		{ "question": "転ぶ", "answers": [ "ころぶ" ], "comment": "(v5b) to fall down/to fall over" },
		{ "question": "転任", "answers": [ "てんにん" ], "comment": "(n) change of post" },
		{ "question": "転勤", "answers": [ "てんきん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) transfer/transmission" },
		{ "question": "転回", "answers": [ "てんかい" ], "comment": "(n) revolution/rotation" },
		{ "question": "転寝", "answers": [ "うたたね" ], "comment": "(n) dozing/napping on the floor (in one's clothes)" },
		{ "question": "転居", "answers": [ "てんきょ" ], "comment": "(n) moving/changing residence" },
		{ "question": "転換", "answers": [ "てんかん" ], "comment": "(n) convert/divert" },
		{ "question": "転校", "answers": [ "てんこう" ], "comment": "(n) change schools" },
		{ "question": "転落", "answers": [ "てんらく" ], "comment": "(n,vs) fall/degradation/slump/spill" },
		{ "question": "軸", "answers": [ "じく" ], "comment": "(n,n-suf) axis/stem/shaft/axle" },
		{ "question": "軽い", "answers": [ "かるい" ], "comment": "(adj) light/non-serious/minor" },
		{ "question": "軽快", "answers": [ "けいかい" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) rhythmical (e.g. melody)/casual (e.g. dress)/light/nimble" },
		{ "question": "軽減", "answers": [ "けいげん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) abatement" },
		{ "question": "軽率", "answers": [ "けいそつ" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) rash/thoughtless/careless/hasty" },
		{ "question": "軽蔑", "answers": [ "けいべつ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) scorn/disdain" },
		{ "question": "載せる", "answers": [ "のせる" ], "comment": "(v1) to place on (something)/to take on board/to give a ride/to let (one) take part/to impose on/to record/to mention/to load (luggage)/to publish/to run (an ad)" },
		{ "question": "載る", "answers": [ "のる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to appear (in print)/to be recorded" },
		{ "question": "輝く", "answers": [ "かがやく" ], "comment": "(v5k) to shine/to glitter/to sparkle" },
		{ "question": "輪", "answers": [ "わ" ], "comment": "(n) ring/hoop/circle" },
		{ "question": "輸入", "answers": [ "ゆにゅう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) importation/import/introduction" },
		{ "question": "輸出", "answers": [ "ゆしゅつ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) export" },
		{ "question": "輸血", "answers": [ "ゆけつ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) blood transfusion" },
		{ "question": "輸送", "answers": [ "ゆそう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) transport/transportation" },
		{ "question": "轢く", "answers": [ "ひく" ], "comment": "(v5k) to run somebody over (with vehicle)/to knock someone down" },
		{ "question": "辛い", "answers": [ "からい","つらい" ], "comment": "(adj) painful/heart-breaking" },
		{ "question": "辛抱", "answers": [ "しんぼう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) patience/endurance" },
		{ "question": "辞める", "answers": [ "やめる" ], "comment": "(v1) to retire" },
		{ "question": "辞典", "answers": [ "じてん" ], "comment": "(n) dictionary" },
		{ "question": "辞書", "answers": [ "じしょ" ], "comment": "(n) dictionary/lexicon" },
		{ "question": "辞職", "answers": [ "じしょく" ], "comment": "(n) resignation" },
		{ "question": "辞退", "answers": [ "じたい" ], "comment": "(n) refusal" },
		{ "question": "辟易", "answers": [ "へきえき" ], "comment": "(n,vs) wince/shrink back/succumbing to/being frightened/disconcerted" },
		{ "question": "農地", "answers": [ "のうち" ], "comment": "(n) agricultural land" },
		{ "question": "農場", "answers": [ "のうじょう" ], "comment": "(n) farm (agriculture)" },
		{ "question": "農家", "answers": [ "のうか" ], "comment": "(n) farmer/farm family" },
		{ "question": "農村", "answers": [ "のうそん" ], "comment": "(n) agricultural community/farm village/rural" },
		{ "question": "農業", "answers": [ "のうぎょう" ], "comment": "(n) agriculture" },
		{ "question": "農民", "answers": [ "のうみん" ], "comment": "(n) farmers/peasants" },
		{ "question": "農産物", "answers": [ "のうさんぶつ" ], "comment": "(n) agricultural produce" },
		{ "question": "農耕", "answers": [ "のうこう" ], "comment": "(n) farming/agriculture" },
		{ "question": "農薬", "answers": [ "のうやく" ], "comment": "(n) agricultural chemicals" },
		{ "question": "辺", "answers": [ "へん", "ほとり" ], "comment": "(n) area/vicinity" },
		{ "question": "辺り", "answers": [ "あたり" ], "comment": "(n) (in the) neighbourhood/vicinity/nearby" },
		{ "question": "込む", "answers": [ "こむ" ], "comment": "(v5m) to be crowded" },
		{ "question": "込める", "answers": [ "こめる" ], "comment": "(v1) to include/to put into" },
		{ "question": "辿り着く", "answers": [ "たどりつく" ], "comment": "(v5k) to grope along to/to struggle on to/to arrive somewhere after a struggle" },
		{ "question": "辿る", "answers": [ "たどる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to follow (road)/to pursue (course)/to follow up" },
		{ "question": "迅速", "answers": [ "じんそく" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) quick/fast/rapid/swift/prompt" },
		{ "question": "迎え", "answers": [ "むかえ" ], "comment": "(n) meeting/person sent to pick up an arrival" },
		{ "question": "迎える", "answers": [ "むかえる" ], "comment": "(v1) to go out to meet/to accept as a member of a group or family" },
		{ "question": "近々", "answers": [ "ちかぢか" ], "comment": "(adv) nearness/before long" },
		{ "question": "近い", "answers": [ "ちかい" ], "comment": "(adj,suf) near/close by/short" },
		{ "question": "近く", "answers": [ "ちかく" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n) near/neighbourhood/vicinity" },
		{ "question": "近付ける", "answers": [ "ちかづける" ], "comment": "(v1) to bring near/to put close/to let come near/to associate with" },
		{ "question": "近代", "answers": [ "きんだい" ], "comment": "(n) present day" },
		{ "question": "近寄る", "answers": [ "ちかよる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to approach/to draw near" },
		{ "question": "近所", "answers": [ "きんじょ" ], "comment": "(n) neighbourhood" },
		{ "question": "近眼", "answers": [ "きんがん" ], "comment": "(n) nearsightedness/shortsightedness/myopia" },
		{ "question": "近視", "answers": [ "きんし" ], "comment": "(n) shortsightedness" },
		{ "question": "近郊", "answers": [ "きんこう" ], "comment": "(n) suburbs/outskirts" },
		{ "question": "近頃", "answers": [ "ちかごろ" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n-t) lately/recently/nowadays" },
		{ "question": "返す", "answers": [ "かえす" ], "comment": "(v5s,vt) to return something" },
		{ "question": "返事", "answers": [ "へんじ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) reply/answer" },
		{ "question": "返済", "answers": [ "へんさい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) repayment" },
		{ "question": "返答", "answers": [ "へんとう" ], "comment": "(n) reply" },
		{ "question": "返還", "answers": [ "へんかん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) return/restoration" },
		{ "question": "迫る", "answers": [ "せまる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to draw near/to press" },
		{ "question": "迫害", "answers": [ "はくがい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) persecution" },
		{ "question": "述べる", "answers": [ "のべる" ], "comment": "(v1) to state/to express/to mention" },
		{ "question": "述語", "answers": [ "じゅつご" ], "comment": "(n) predicate" },
		{ "question": "迷う", "answers": [ "まよう" ], "comment": "(v5u) to be puzzled/to be perplexed/to lose one's way" },
		{ "question": "迷信", "answers": [ "めいしん" ], "comment": "(n) superstition" },
		{ "question": "迷子", "answers": [ "まいご" ], "comment": "(n) lost (stray) child" },
		{ "question": "迷惑", "answers": [ "めいわく" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) trouble/bother/annoyance" },
		{ "question": "追い付く", "answers": [ "おいつく" ], "comment": "(v5k) to overtake/to catch up (with)" },
		{ "question": "追い出す", "answers": [ "おいだす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to expel/to drive out" },
		{ "question": "追い掛ける", "answers": [ "おいかける" ], "comment": "(v1) to chase or run after someone/to run down/to pursue" },
		{ "question": "追い越す", "answers": [ "おいこす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to pass (e.g. car)/to outdistance/to outstrip" },
		{ "question": "追い込む", "answers": [ "おいこむ" ], "comment": "(v5m) to herd/to corner/to drive" },
		{ "question": "追う", "answers": [ "おう" ], "comment": "(v5u) to chase/to run after" },
		{ "question": "追加", "answers": [ "ついか" ], "comment": "(n,vs) addition/supplement/appendix" },
		{ "question": "追及", "answers": [ "ついきゅう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) gaining on/carrying out/solving (crime)" },
		{ "question": "追放", "answers": [ "ついほう" ], "comment": "(n) exile/banishment" },
		{ "question": "追跡", "answers": [ "ついせき" ], "comment": "(n) pursuit" },
		{ "question": "退く", "answers": [ "どく" ], "comment": "(v5k,vi) (1) to retreat/to recede/to withdraw" },
		{ "question": "退ける", "answers": [ "どける" ], "comment": "(v1) to remove/to take away/to dislodge/to put something out of the way" },
		{ "question": "退化", "answers": [ "たいか" ], "comment": "(n) degeneration/retrogression" },
		{ "question": "退学", "answers": [ "たいがく" ], "comment": "(n) dropping out of school" },
		{ "question": "退屈", "answers": [ "たいくつ" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n,vs) tedium/boredom" },
		{ "question": "退治", "answers": [ "たいじ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) extermination" },
		{ "question": "退職", "answers": [ "たいしょく" ], "comment": "(n,vs) retirement (from office)" },
		{ "question": "退院", "answers": [ "たいいん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) leaving hospital" },
		{ "question": "送り仮名", "answers": [ "おくりがな" ], "comment": "part of word written in kana" },
		{ "question": "送る", "answers": [ "おくる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to send (a thing)/to dispatch/to take or escort (a person somewhere)/to see off (a person)/to spend a period of time/to live a life" },
		{ "question": "送別", "answers": [ "そうべつ" ], "comment": "(n) farewell/send-off" },
		{ "question": "送料", "answers": [ "そうりょう" ], "comment": "(n) postage/carriage" },
		{ "question": "送金", "answers": [ "そうきん" ], "comment": "(n) remittance/sending money" },
		{ "question": "逃がす", "answers": [ "にがす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to let loose/to set free/to let escape" },
		{ "question": "逃げる", "answers": [ "にげる" ], "comment": "(v1) to escape/to run away" },
		{ "question": "逃げ出す", "answers": [ "にげだす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to run away/to escape from" },
		{ "question": "逃す", "answers": [ "のがす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to let loose/to set free/to let escape" },
		{ "question": "逃れる", "answers": [ "のがれる" ], "comment": "(v1) to escape" },
		{ "question": "逃亡", "answers": [ "とうぼう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) escape" },
		{ "question": "逃走", "answers": [ "とうそう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) flight/desertion/escape" },
		{ "question": "逆", "answers": [ "ぎゃく" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) reverse/opposite" },
		{ "question": "逆さ", "answers": [ "さかさ" ], "comment": "(n) reverse/inversion/upside down" },
		{ "question": "逆らう", "answers": [ "さからう" ], "comment": "(v5u) to go against/to oppose/to disobey/to defy" },
		{ "question": "逆様", "answers": [ "さかさま" ], "comment": "(adj-na,adj-no,n) inversion/upside down" },
		{ "question": "逆立ち", "answers": [ "さかだち" ], "comment": "(n) handstand/headstand" },
		{ "question": "逆転", "answers": [ "ぎゃくてん" ], "comment": "(n) (sudden) change/reversal/turn-around/coming from behind (baseball)" },
		{ "question": "透き通る", "answers": [ "すきとおる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to be(come) transparent" },
		{ "question": "透明", "answers": [ "とうめい" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) transparency/cleanness" },
		{ "question": "途上", "answers": [ "とじょう" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n-t) en route/half way" },
		{ "question": "途中", "answers": [ "とちゅう" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n-t) on the way/en route/midway" },
		{ "question": "途端", "answers": [ "とたん" ], "comment": "(n) just (now, at the moment, etc.)" },
		{ "question": "途絶える", "answers": [ "とだえる" ], "comment": "(v1) to stop/to cease/to come to an end" },
		{ "question": "這う", "answers": [ "はう" ], "comment": "(v5u) to creep/to crawl" },
		{ "question": "通う", "answers": [ "かよう" ], "comment": "(v5u) (1) to go back and forth/to ply between/(2) to commute/to attend (school, church, etc.)" },
		{ "question": "通じる", "answers": [ "つうじる" ], "comment": "(v1) to run to/to lead to/to communicate/to understand/to be well informed" },
		{ "question": "通す", "answers": [ "とおす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to let pass/to overlook/to continue/to keep/to make way for/to persist in" },
		{ "question": "通り", "answers": [ "とおり" ], "comment": "(n-suf) in accordance with ~/following ~/~ Street/~ Avenue" },
		{ "question": "通り掛かる", "answers": [ "とおりかかる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to happen to pass by" },
		{ "question": "通り過ぎる", "answers": [ "とおりすぎる" ], "comment": "(v1) to pass/to pass through" },
		{ "question": "通る", "answers": [ "とおる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to pass (by)/to go through/to walk along/to pass exams" },
		{ "question": "通信", "answers": [ "つうしん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) correspondence/communication/news/signal" },
		{ "question": "通勤", "answers": [ "つうきん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) commuting to work" },
		{ "question": "通学", "answers": [ "つうがく" ], "comment": "(n) commuting to school" },
		{ "question": "通帳", "answers": [ "つうちょう" ], "comment": "(n) passbook" },
		{ "question": "通常", "answers": [ "つうじょう" ], "comment": "(adj-no,n-adv,n-t) common/general/normal/usual" },
		{ "question": "通用", "answers": [ "つうよう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) popular use/circulation" },
		{ "question": "通知", "answers": [ "つうち" ], "comment": "(n,vs) notice/notification" },
		{ "question": "通行", "answers": [ "つうこう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) passage/passing" },
		{ "question": "通訳", "answers": [ "つうやく" ], "comment": "(n,vs) interpretation" },
		{ "question": "通貨", "answers": [ "つうか" ], "comment": "(n) currency" },
		{ "question": "通路", "answers": [ "つうろ" ], "comment": "(n) passage/pathway" },
		{ "question": "通過", "answers": [ "つうか" ], "comment": "(n,vs) passage through/passing" },
		{ "question": "速い", "answers": [ "はやい" ], "comment": "(adj) quick/fast/swift" },
		{ "question": "速力", "answers": [ "そくりょく" ], "comment": "(n) speed" },
		{ "question": "速度", "answers": [ "そくど" ], "comment": "(n) speed/velocity/rate" },
		{ "question": "速達", "answers": [ "そくたつ" ], "comment": "(n) express/special delivery" },
		{ "question": "造り", "answers": [ "つくり" ], "comment": "(n) make up/structure/physique" },
		{ "question": "造る", "answers": [ "つくる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to make/to create/to manufacture/to draw up/to write/to compose/to build/to coin/to cultivate/to organize/to establish/to make up (a face)/to trim (a tree)/to fabricate/to prepare (food)/to commit (sin)/to construct" },
		{ "question": "造船", "answers": [ "ぞうせん" ], "comment": "(n) shipbuilding" },
		{ "question": "連なる", "answers": [ "つらなる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to extend/to stretch out/to stand in a row" },
		{ "question": "連ねる", "answers": [ "つらねる" ], "comment": "(v1) to link/to join/to put together" },
		{ "question": "連れ", "answers": [ "つれ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) companion/company" },
		{ "question": "連れる", "answers": [ "つれる" ], "comment": "(v1) to lead/to take (a person)" },
		{ "question": "連中", "answers": [ "れんちゅう" ], "comment": "(n) colleagues/company/a lot" },
		{ "question": "連休", "answers": [ "れんきゅう" ], "comment": "(n) consecutive holidays" },
		{ "question": "連合", "answers": [ "れんごう" ], "comment": "(n) union/alliance" },
		{ "question": "連帯", "answers": [ "れんたい" ], "comment": "(n) solidarity" },
		{ "question": "連想", "answers": [ "れんそう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) association (of ideas)/suggestion" },
		{ "question": "連日", "answers": [ "れんじつ" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n-t) every day/prolonged" },
		{ "question": "連盟", "answers": [ "れんめい" ], "comment": "(n) league/union/alliance" },
		{ "question": "連絡", "answers": [ "れんらく" ], "comment": "(n,vs) junction/communication/contact/connection/coordination" },
		{ "question": "連続", "answers": [ "れんぞく" ], "comment": "(n,vs) serial/consecutive/continuity/occurring in succession/continuing" },
		{ "question": "連邦", "answers": [ "れんぽう" ], "comment": "(n) commonwealth/federation of states" },
		{ "question": "逮捕", "answers": [ "たいほ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) arrest/apprehension/capture" },
		{ "question": "週", "answers": [ "しゅう" ], "comment": "(n,n-suf) week" },
		{ "question": "週間", "answers": [ "しゅうかん" ], "comment": "(n) week/weekly" },
		{ "question": "進み", "answers": [ "すすみ" ], "comment": "(n) progress" },
		{ "question": "進む", "answers": [ "すすむ" ], "comment": "(v5m,vi) to make progress/to advance/to improve" },
		{ "question": "進める", "answers": [ "すすめる" ], "comment": "(v1,vt) to advance/to promote/to hasten" },
		{ "question": "進出", "answers": [ "しんしゅつ" ], "comment": "(n) advance/step forward" },
		{ "question": "進化", "answers": [ "しんか" ], "comment": "(n) evolution/progress" },
		{ "question": "進呈", "answers": [ "しんてい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) presentation" },
		{ "question": "進学", "answers": [ "しんがく" ], "comment": "(n,vs) going on to university" },
		{ "question": "進展", "answers": [ "しんてん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) progress/development" },
		{ "question": "進度", "answers": [ "しんど" ], "comment": "(n) progress" },
		{ "question": "進歩", "answers": [ "しんぽ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) progress/development" },
		{ "question": "進行", "answers": [ "しんこう" ], "comment": "(n) advance" },
		{ "question": "逸れる", "answers": [ "それる" ], "comment": "(v1) to stray (turn) from subject/to get lost/to go astray" },
		{ "question": "遂げる", "answers": [ "とげる" ], "comment": "(v1) to accomplish/to achieve/to carry out" },
		{ "question": "遂に", "answers": [ "ついに" ], "comment": "(adv) finally/at last" },
		{ "question": "遅い", "answers": [ "おそい" ], "comment": "(adj) late/slow" },
		{ "question": "遅くとも", "answers": [ "おそくとも" ], "comment": "(adv) at the latest" },
		{ "question": "遅らす", "answers": [ "おくらす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to retard/to delay" },
		{ "question": "遅れ", "answers": [ "おくれ" ], "comment": "(n) delay/lag" },
		{ "question": "遅れる", "answers": [ "おくれる" ], "comment": "(v1) to be late/to be delayed/to fall behind schedule" },
		{ "question": "遅刻", "answers": [ "ちこく" ], "comment": "(n,vs) lateness/late coming" },
		{ "question": "遊び", "answers": [ "あそび" ], "comment": "(n,n-suf) playing" },
		{ "question": "遊ぶ", "answers": [ "あそぶ" ], "comment": "(v5b) (1) to play/to make a visit (esp. for pleasure)/(2) to be idle/to do nothing" },
		{ "question": "遊園地", "answers": [ "ゆうえんち" ], "comment": "(n) amusement park" },
		{ "question": "遊牧", "answers": [ "ゆうぼく" ], "comment": "(n) nomadism" },
		{ "question": "運", "answers": [ "うん" ], "comment": "(n) fortune/luck" },
		{ "question": "運ぶ", "answers": [ "はこぶ" ], "comment": "(v5b) to transport" },
		{ "question": "運動", "answers": [ "うんどう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) motion/exercise" },
		{ "question": "運命", "answers": [ "うんめい" ], "comment": "(n) fate" },
		{ "question": "運営", "answers": [ "うんえい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) management/administration/operation" },
		{ "question": "運搬", "answers": [ "うんぱん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) transport/carriage" },
		{ "question": "運河", "answers": [ "うんが" ], "comment": "(n) canal/waterway" },
		{ "question": "運用", "answers": [ "うんよう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) making use of/application/investment/practical use" },
		{ "question": "運賃", "answers": [ "うんちん" ], "comment": "(n) freight rates/shipping expenses/fare" },
		{ "question": "運転", "answers": [ "うんてん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) operation/motion/driving" },
		{ "question": "運転手", "answers": [ "うんてんしゅ" ], "comment": "(n) driver/chauffeur" },
		{ "question": "運輸", "answers": [ "うんゆ" ], "comment": "(n) transportation" },
		{ "question": "運送", "answers": [ "うんそう" ], "comment": "(n) shipping/marine transportation" },
		{ "question": "過ぎる", "answers": [ "すぎる" ], "comment": "(v1,vi) to pass/to go beyond/to elapse/to exceed" },
		{ "question": "過ごす", "answers": [ "すごす" ], "comment": "(v5s,vt) to pass/to spend/to go through/to tide over" },
		{ "question": "過ち", "answers": [ "あやまち" ], "comment": "(n) fault/error/indiscretion" },
		{ "question": "過剰", "answers": [ "かじょう" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) excess/over-" },
		{ "question": "過労", "answers": [ "かろう" ], "comment": "(n) overwork/strain" },
		{ "question": "過半数", "answers": [ "かはんすう" ], "comment": "(n) majority" },
		{ "question": "過去", "answers": [ "かこ" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n) the past/bygone days/the previous" },
		{ "question": "過失", "answers": [ "かしつ" ], "comment": "(n) error/blunder/accident" },
		{ "question": "過密", "answers": [ "かみつ" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) crowded" },
		{ "question": "過疎", "answers": [ "かそ" ], "comment": "(n) depopulation" },
		{ "question": "過程", "answers": [ "かてい" ], "comment": "(n) process" },
		{ "question": "道", "answers": [ "みち" ], "comment": "(n) road/street/way/method" },
		{ "question": "道具", "answers": [ "どうぐ" ], "comment": "(n) implement/tool/means" },
		{ "question": "道場", "answers": [ "どうじょう" ], "comment": "(n) (arch) dojo/hall used for martial arts training/mandala" },
		{ "question": "道徳", "answers": [ "どうとく" ], "comment": "(n) morals" },
		{ "question": "道路", "answers": [ "どうろ" ], "comment": "(n) road/highway" },
		{ "question": "道順", "answers": [ "みちじゅん" ], "comment": "(n) itinerary/route" },
		{ "question": "達する", "answers": [ "たっする" ], "comment": "(vs-s) to reach/to get to" },
		{ "question": "達成", "answers": [ "たっせい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) achievement" },
		{ "question": "達者", "answers": [ "たっしゃ" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) skillful/in good health" },
		{ "question": "違い", "answers": [ "ちがい" ], "comment": "(n,n-suf) difference/discrepancy" },
		{ "question": "違いない", "answers": [ "ちがいない" ], "comment": "(adj,exp) (phrase) sure/no mistaking it/for certain" },
		{ "question": "違う", "answers": [ "ちがう" ], "comment": "(v5u) to differ (from)" },
		{ "question": "違える", "answers": [ "ちがえる" ], "comment": "(v1) to change" },
		{ "question": "違反", "answers": [ "いはん" ], "comment": "(n) violation (of law)/transgression/infringement/breach" },
		{ "question": "遠い", "answers": [ "とおい" ], "comment": "(adj) far/distant" },
		{ "question": "遠く", "answers": [ "とおく" ], "comment": "(adj-no,n-adv,n) far away/distant/at a distance/distant place/by far" },
		{ "question": "遠ざかる", "answers": [ "とおざかる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to go far off" },
		{ "question": "遠回り", "answers": [ "とおまわり" ], "comment": "(n) detour/roundabout way" },
		{ "question": "遠慮", "answers": [ "えんりょ" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n,vs) diffidence/restraint/reserve" },
		{ "question": "遠方", "answers": [ "えんぽう" ], "comment": "(n) long way/distant place" },
		{ "question": "遠足", "answers": [ "えんそく" ], "comment": "(n) trip/hike/picnic" },
		{ "question": "遡る", "answers": [ "さかのぼる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to go back/to go upstream/to make retroactive" },
		{ "question": "遥か", "answers": [ "はるか" ], "comment": "(adj-na,adv,n) far/far-away/distant/remote/far off" },
		{ "question": "適する", "answers": [ "てきする" ], "comment": "(vs-s) to fit/to suit" },
		{ "question": "適切", "answers": [ "てきせつ" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) pertinent/appropriate/adequate/relevance" },
		{ "question": "適宜", "answers": [ "てきぎ" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n-adv) suitability" },
		{ "question": "適度", "answers": [ "てきど" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) moderate" },
		{ "question": "適当", "answers": [ "てきとう" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) fitness/suitability/adequacy/relevance" },
		{ "question": "適応", "answers": [ "てきおう" ], "comment": "(n) adaptation/accommodation/conformity" },
		{ "question": "適性", "answers": [ "てきせい" ], "comment": "(n) aptitude" },
		{ "question": "適用", "answers": [ "てきよう" ], "comment": "(n) applying" },
		{ "question": "適確", "answers": [ "てきかく" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) precise/accurate" },
		{ "question": "遭う", "answers": [ "あう" ], "comment": "(v5u) to meet/to encounter (undesirable nuance)" },
		{ "question": "遭難", "answers": [ "そうなん" ], "comment": "(n) disaster/shipwreck/accident" },
		{ "question": "遮る", "answers": [ "さえぎる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to interrupt/to intercept/to obstruct" },
		{ "question": "選ぶ", "answers": [ "えらぶ" ], "comment": "(v5b) to choose/to select" },
		{ "question": "選手", "answers": [ "せんしゅ" ], "comment": "(n) (1) player (in game)/(2) team" },
		{ "question": "選択", "answers": [ "せんたく" ], "comment": "(n,vs) selection/choice" },
		{ "question": "選挙", "answers": [ "せんきょ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) election" },
		{ "question": "選考", "answers": [ "せんこう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) selection/screening" },
		{ "question": "遺跡", "answers": [ "いせき" ], "comment": "(n) historic ruins (remains, relics)" },
		{ "question": "避ける", "answers": [ "さける","よける" ], "comment": "(v1) (1) to avoid (physical contact with)/(2) to ward off/to avert" },
		{ "question": "避難", "answers": [ "ひなん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) taking refuge/finding shelter" },
		{ "question": "還元", "answers": [ "かんげん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) resolution/reduction/return to origins" },
		{ "question": "還暦", "answers": [ "かんれき" ], "comment": "(n) 60th birthday" },
		{ "question": "邪魔", "answers": [ "じゃま" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n,vs) hindrance/intrusion" },
		{ "question": "邸宅", "answers": [ "ていたく" ], "comment": "(n) mansion/residence" },
		{ "question": "郊外", "answers": [ "こうがい" ], "comment": "(n) suburb/outskirts" },
		{ "question": "郡", "answers": [ "ぐん" ], "comment": "(n) country/district" },
		{ "question": "部下", "answers": [ "ぶか" ], "comment": "(n) subordinate person" },
		{ "question": "部分", "answers": [ "ぶぶん" ], "comment": "(n) portion/section/part" },
		{ "question": "部品", "answers": [ "ぶひん" ], "comment": "(n) parts/accessories" },
		{ "question": "部屋", "answers": [ "へや" ], "comment": "(n) room" },
		{ "question": "部門", "answers": [ "ぶもん" ], "comment": "(n) class/group/category/department/field/branch" },
		{ "question": "部首", "answers": [ "ぶしゅ" ], "comment": "(n) radical (of a kanji character)" },
		{ "question": "郵便", "answers": [ "ゆうびん" ], "comment": "(n) mail/postal service" },
		{ "question": "郵便局", "answers": [ "ゆうびんきょく" ], "comment": "(n) post office" },
		{ "question": "郵送", "answers": [ "ゆうそう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) mailing" },
		{ "question": "郷土", "answers": [ "きょうど" ], "comment": "(n) native place/birth place/one's old home" },
		{ "question": "郷愁", "answers": [ "きょうしゅう" ], "comment": "(n) nostalgia/homesickness" },
		{ "question": "郷里", "answers": [ "きょうり" ], "comment": "(n) birth-place/home town" },
		{ "question": "都", "answers": [ "と","みやこ" ], "comment": "(n) capital" },
		{ "question": "都会", "answers": [ "とかい" ], "comment": "(n) city" },
		{ "question": "都合", "answers": [ "つごう" ], "comment": "(adv,n) circumstances/condition/convenience" },
		{ "question": "都市", "answers": [ "とし" ], "comment": "(n) town/city/municipal/urban" },
		{ "question": "都心", "answers": [ "としん" ], "comment": "(n) heart (of city)" },
		{ "question": "酌む", "answers": [ "くむ" ], "comment": "(v5m) to serve sake" },
		{ "question": "配る", "answers": [ "くばる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to distribute/to deliver" },
		{ "question": "配偶者", "answers": [ "はいぐうしゃ" ], "comment": "(n) spouse/wife/husband" },
		{ "question": "配分", "answers": [ "はいぶん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) distribution/allotment" },
		{ "question": "配列", "answers": [ "はいれつ" ], "comment": "(n) arrangement/array (programming)" },
		{ "question": "配布", "answers": [ "はいふ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) distribution" },
		{ "question": "配慮", "answers": [ "はいりょ" ], "comment": "(n) consideration/concern/forethought" },
		{ "question": "配給", "answers": [ "はいきゅう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) distribution (eg. films, rice)" },
		{ "question": "配置", "answers": [ "はいち" ], "comment": "(n) arrangement (of resources)/disposition" },
		{ "question": "配達", "answers": [ "はいたつ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) delivery/distribution" },
		{ "question": "酒", "answers": [ "さけ" ], "comment": "(n) alcohol/sake" },
		{ "question": "酒場", "answers": [ "さかば" ], "comment": "(n) bar/bar-room" },
		{ "question": "酔う", "answers": [ "よう" ], "comment": "(v5u) to get drunk/to become intoxicated" },
		{ "question": "酔っ払い", "answers": [ "よっぱらい" ], "comment": "(n) drunkard" },
		{ "question": "酢", "answers": [ "す" ], "comment": "(n) vinegar" },
		{ "question": "酪農", "answers": [ "らくのう" ], "comment": "(n) dairy (farm)" },
		{ "question": "酸", "answers": [ "さん" ], "comment": "(n) acid" },
		{ "question": "酸化", "answers": [ "さんか" ], "comment": "(n) oxidation" },
		{ "question": "酸性", "answers": [ "さんせい" ], "comment": "(n) acidity" },
		{ "question": "酸素", "answers": [ "さんそ" ], "comment": "(n) oxygen" },
		{ "question": "醜い", "answers": [ "みにくい" ], "comment": "(adj) ugly" },
		{ "question": "醤油", "answers": [ "しょうゆ" ], "comment": "(n) soy sauce" },
		{ "question": "重い", "answers": [ "おもい" ], "comment": "(adj) (1) heavy/massive/(2) serious/important/severe/oppressed" },
		{ "question": "重たい", "answers": [ "おもたい" ], "comment": "(adj) heavy/massive/serious/important/severe/oppressed" },
		{ "question": "重なる", "answers": [ "かさなる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to be piled up/lie on top of one another/overlap each other" },
		{ "question": "重ねる", "answers": [ "かさねる" ], "comment": "(v1) to pile up/to put something on another/to heap up/to add/to repeat" },
		{ "question": "重んじる", "answers": [ "おもんじる" ], "comment": "(v1) to respect/to honor/to esteem/to prize" },
		{ "question": "重んずる", "answers": [ "おもんずる" ], "comment": "(v5z) to honor/to respect/to esteem/to prize" },
		{ "question": "重体", "answers": [ "じゅうたい" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) seriously ill/serious condition/critical state" },
		{ "question": "重力", "answers": [ "じゅうりょく" ], "comment": "(n) gravity" },
		{ "question": "重大", "answers": [ "じゅうだい" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) serious/important/grave/weighty" },
		{ "question": "重宝", "answers": [ "ちょうほう" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n,vs) priceless treasure/convenience/usefulness" },
		{ "question": "重役", "answers": [ "じゅうやく" ], "comment": "(n) director/high executive" },
		{ "question": "重点", "answers": [ "じゅうてん" ], "comment": "(n) important point/lay stress on/colon/emphasis" },
		{ "question": "重複", "answers": [ "じゅうふく","ちょうふく" ], "comment": "(n,vs) duplication/repetition/overlapping/redundancy/restoration" },
		{ "question": "重要", "answers": [ "じゅうよう" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) important/momentous/essential/principal/major" },
		{ "question": "重視", "answers": [ "じゅうし" ], "comment": "(n,vs) importance/stress/serious consideration" },
		{ "question": "重量", "answers": [ "じゅうりょう" ], "comment": "(n) (1) weight/(2) heavyweight boxer" },
		{ "question": "野", "answers": [ "の" ], "comment": "(n) field" },
		{ "question": "野党", "answers": [ "やとう" ], "comment": "(n) opposition party" },
		{ "question": "野外", "answers": [ "やがい" ], "comment": "(adj-no,n) fields/outskirts/open air/suburbs" },
		{ "question": "野心", "answers": [ "やしん" ], "comment": "(n) ambition/aspiration/designs/treachery" },
		{ "question": "野生", "answers": [ "やせい" ], "comment": "(n) wild" },
		{ "question": "野菜", "answers": [ "やさい" ], "comment": "(n) vegetable" },
		{ "question": "量", "answers": [ "りょう" ], "comment": "(n,n-suf) quantity/amount/volume/portion (of food)" },
		{ "question": "量る", "answers": [ "はかる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to measure/to weigh/to survey/to time (sound, gauge, estimate)" },
		{ "question": "金", "answers": [ "かね","きん" ], "comment": "(n,n-suf) (1) gold/(2) gold general (shogi) (abbr)" },
		{ "question": "金属", "answers": [ "きんぞく" ], "comment": "(n) metal" },
		{ "question": "金庫", "answers": [ "きんこ" ], "comment": "(n) safe/vault/treasury/provider of funds" },
		{ "question": "金持ち", "answers": [ "かねもち" ], "comment": "(n) rich man" },
		{ "question": "金曜", "answers": [ "きんよう" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n-t) (abbr) Friday" },
		{ "question": "金曜日", "answers": [ "きんようび" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n) Friday" },
		{ "question": "金槌", "answers": [ "かなづち" ], "comment": "(n) (iron) hammer" },
		{ "question": "金融", "answers": [ "きんゆう" ], "comment": "(n) monetary circulation/credit situation" },
		{ "question": "金銭", "answers": [ "きんせん" ], "comment": "(n) money/cash" },
		{ "question": "金額", "answers": [ "きんがく" ], "comment": "(n) amount of money" },
		{ "question": "金魚", "answers": [ "きんぎょ" ], "comment": "(n) goldfish" },
		{ "question": "釘", "answers": [ "くぎ" ], "comment": "(n) nail" },
		{ "question": "釜", "answers": [ "かま" ], "comment": "(n) iron pot/kettle" },
		{ "question": "針", "answers": [ "はり" ], "comment": "(n) needle/fish hook/pointer/hand (e.g. clock)" },
		{ "question": "針路", "answers": [ "しんろ" ], "comment": "(n) course/direction/compass bearing" },
		{ "question": "針金", "answers": [ "はりがね" ], "comment": "(n) wire" },
		{ "question": "釣り合う", "answers": [ "つりあう" ], "comment": "(v5u) to balance/to be in harmony/to suit" },
		{ "question": "釣り鐘", "answers": [ "つりがね" ], "comment": "(n) temple bell (for striking)" },
		{ "question": "釣る", "answers": [ "つる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to fish" },
		{ "question": "鈍い", "answers": [ "にぶい","のろい" ], "comment": "(adj) dull (e.g. a knife)/thickheaded/slow (opposite of fast)/stupid" },
		{ "question": "鈍る", "answers": [ "にぶる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to become less capable/to grow dull/to become blunt/to weaken" },
		{ "question": "鈍感", "answers": [ "どんかん" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) thickheadedness/stolidity" },
		{ "question": "鈴", "answers": [ "すず" ], "comment": "(n) bell" },
		{ "question": "鉄", "answers": [ "てつ" ], "comment": "(n) iron" },
		{ "question": "鉄棒", "answers": [ "てつぼう" ], "comment": "(n) iron rod/crowbar/horizontal bar (gymnastics)" },
		{ "question": "鉄橋", "answers": [ "てっきょう" ], "comment": "(n) railway bridge/iron bridge" },
		{ "question": "鉄砲", "answers": [ "てっぽう" ], "comment": "(n) gun" },
		{ "question": "鉄道", "answers": [ "てつどう" ], "comment": "(n) railroad" },
		{ "question": "鉄鋼", "answers": [ "てっこう" ], "comment": "(n) iron and steel" },
		{ "question": "鉛", "answers": [ "なまり" ], "comment": "(n) lead (the metal)" },
		{ "question": "鉛筆", "answers": [ "えんぴつ" ], "comment": "(n) pencil" },
		{ "question": "鉢", "answers": [ "はち" ], "comment": "(n) a bowl/a pot/a basin/a flowerpot/a crown/a brainpan" },
		{ "question": "鉱山", "answers": [ "こうざん" ], "comment": "(n) mine (ore)" },
		{ "question": "鉱業", "answers": [ "こうぎょう" ], "comment": "(n) mining industry" },
		{ "question": "鉱物", "answers": [ "こうぶつ" ], "comment": "(n) mineral" },
		{ "question": "銀", "answers": [ "ぎん" ], "comment": "(n) (1) silver/silver coin/silver paint" },
		{ "question": "銀行", "answers": [ "ぎんこう" ], "comment": "(n) bank" },
		{ "question": "銃", "answers": [ "じゅう" ], "comment": "gun" },
		{ "question": "銅", "answers": [ "どう" ], "comment": "(n) copper" },
		{ "question": "銘々", "answers": [ "めいめい" ], "comment": "(n) each/individual" },
		{ "question": "鋭い", "answers": [ "するどい" ], "comment": "(adj) pointed/sharp" },
		{ "question": "錆", "answers": [ "さび" ], "comment": "(n) rust (colour)" },
		{ "question": "錆びる", "answers": [ "さびる" ], "comment": "(v1,vi) to rust/to become rusty" },
		{ "question": "錯誤", "answers": [ "さくご" ], "comment": "(n) mistake" },
		{ "question": "録音", "answers": [ "ろくおん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) (audio) recording" },
		{ "question": "鍋", "answers": [ "なべ" ], "comment": "(n,n-suf) saucepan/pot" },
		{ "question": "鍛える", "answers": [ "きたえる" ], "comment": "(v1) to forge/to drill/to temper/to train/to discipline" },
		{ "question": "鍵", "answers": [ "かぎ" ], "comment": "(n) key" },
		{ "question": "鎖", "answers": [ "くさり" ], "comment": "(n) chain" },
		{ "question": "鏡", "answers": [ "かがみ" ], "comment": "(n) mirror" },
		{ "question": "鐘", "answers": [ "かね" ], "comment": "(n) bell/chime" },
		{ "question": "鑑賞", "answers": [ "かんしょう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) appreciation" },
		{ "question": "長々", "answers": [ "ながなが" ], "comment": "(adv) long/drawn-out/very long" },
		{ "question": "長い", "answers": [ "ながい" ], "comment": "(adj) long" },
		{ "question": "長女", "answers": [ "ちょうじょ" ], "comment": "(n) eldest daughter" },
		{ "question": "長官", "answers": [ "ちょうかん" ], "comment": "(n) chief/(government) secretary" },
		{ "question": "長引く", "answers": [ "ながびく" ], "comment": "(v5k) to be prolonged/to drag on" },
		{ "question": "長所", "answers": [ "ちょうしょ" ], "comment": "(n) (1) strong point/merit/(2) advantage" },
		{ "question": "長方形", "answers": [ "ちょうほうけい" ], "comment": "(n) rectangle/oblong" },
		{ "question": "長期", "answers": [ "ちょうき" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n-t) long time period" },
		{ "question": "長男", "answers": [ "ちょうなん" ], "comment": "(n) eldest son" },
		{ "question": "長短", "answers": [ "ちょうたん" ], "comment": "(n) length/long and short/+-" },
		{ "question": "長編", "answers": [ "ちょうへん" ], "comment": "(n) long (e.g. novel, film)" },
		{ "question": "門", "answers": [ "もん" ], "comment": "(n,n-suf) gate" },
		{ "question": "閉じる", "answers": [ "とじる" ], "comment": "(v1) to close (e.g. book, eyes, meeting, etc.)/to shut" },
		{ "question": "閉まる", "answers": [ "しまる" ], "comment": "(v5r,vi) to close/to be closed" },
		{ "question": "閉める", "answers": [ "しめる" ], "comment": "(v1,vt) to close/to shut" },
		{ "question": "閉会", "answers": [ "へいかい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) closure" },
		{ "question": "閉口", "answers": [ "へいこう" ], "comment": "(n) shut mouth" },
		{ "question": "閉鎖", "answers": [ "へいさ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) closing/closure/shutdown/lockout/unsociable" },
		{ "question": "開く", "answers": [ "あく","ひらく" ], "comment": "(v5k) to open (e.g. a festival)" },
		{ "question": "開ける", "answers": [ "あける" ], "comment": "(v1) to become civilized/to become opened up/be up-to-date" },
		{ "question": "開会", "answers": [ "かいかい" ], "comment": "(n) opening of a meeting" },
		{ "question": "開催", "answers": [ "かいさい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) holding a meeting/open an exhibition" },
		{ "question": "開始", "answers": [ "かいし" ], "comment": "(n,vs) start/commencement/beginning" },
		{ "question": "開拓", "answers": [ "かいたく" ], "comment": "(n,vs) reclamation (of wasteland)/cultivation/pioneer" },
		{ "question": "開放", "answers": [ "かいほう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) open/throw open/liberalization" },
		{ "question": "開発", "answers": [ "かいはつ" ], "comment": "(n) development/exploitation" },
		{ "question": "開通", "answers": [ "かいつう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) opening/open" },
		{ "question": "間", "answers": [ "あいだ","ま" ], "comment": "(n) space/room/time/pause" },
		{ "question": "間に合う", "answers": [ "まにあう" ], "comment": "(v5u) (1) to be in time for/(2) to serve (suit, meet) the purpose/to be good enough/to be enough" },
		{ "question": "間も無く", "answers": [ "まもなく" ], "comment": "(adv) soon/before long/in a short time" },
		{ "question": "間接", "answers": [ "かんせつ" ], "comment": "(n) indirection/indirectness" },
		{ "question": "間柄", "answers": [ "あいだがら" ], "comment": "(n) relation(ship)" },
		{ "question": "間違い", "answers": [ "まちがい" ], "comment": "(n) mistake" },
		{ "question": "間違える", "answers": [ "まちがえる" ], "comment": "(v1) to err/to make a mistake" },
		{ "question": "間隔", "answers": [ "かんかく" ], "comment": "(n) space/interval/SPC" },
		{ "question": "関する", "answers": [ "かんする" ], "comment": "(vs-s) to concern/to be related" },
		{ "question": "関与", "answers": [ "かんよ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) participation/taking part in/participating in/being concerned in" },
		{ "question": "関係", "answers": [ "かんけい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) relation/connection" },
		{ "question": "関心", "answers": [ "かんしん" ], "comment": "(n) concern/interest" },
		{ "question": "関東", "answers": [ "かんとう" ], "comment": "Kantou (eastern half of Japan, including Tokyo)" },
		{ "question": "関税", "answers": [ "かんぜい" ], "comment": "(n) customs/duty/tariff" },
		{ "question": "関西", "answers": [ "かんさい" ], "comment": "Kansai (south-western half of Japan, including Osaka)" },
		{ "question": "関連", "answers": [ "かんれん" ], "comment": "(n) relation/connection/relevance" },
		{ "question": "閲覧", "answers": [ "えつらん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) inspection/reading" },
		{ "question": "闇", "answers": [ "やみ" ], "comment": "(adj-no,n) darkness/the dark/black-marketeering/dark/shady/illegal" },
		{ "question": "防ぐ", "answers": [ "ふせぐ" ], "comment": "(v5g,vt) to defend (against)/to protect/to prevent" },
		{ "question": "防止", "answers": [ "ぼうし" ], "comment": "(n) prevention/check" },
		{ "question": "防火", "answers": [ "ぼうか" ], "comment": "(n) fire prevention/fire fighting/fire proof" },
		{ "question": "防犯", "answers": [ "ぼうはん" ], "comment": "(n) prevention of crime" },
		{ "question": "防衛", "answers": [ "ぼうえい" ], "comment": "(n) defense/protection/self-defense" },
		{ "question": "阻む", "answers": [ "はばむ" ], "comment": "(v5m) to keep someone from doing/to stop/to prevent/to check/to hinder/to obstruct/to oppose/to thwart" },
		{ "question": "阻止", "answers": [ "そし" ], "comment": "(n,vs) obstruction/check/hindrance/prevention/interdiction" },
		{ "question": "附属", "answers": [ "ふぞく" ], "comment": "(n,vs) attached/belonging/affiliated/annexed/associated/subordinate/incidental/dependent/auxiliary" },
		{ "question": "降りる", "answers": [ "おりる" ], "comment": "(v1) to alight (e.g. from bus)/to get off/to descend (e.g. a mountain)" },
		{ "question": "降る", "answers": [ "ふる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to precipitate/to fall (e.g. rain)" },
		{ "question": "降ろす", "answers": [ "おろす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to take down/to launch/to drop/to lower/to let (a person) off/to unload/to discharge" },
		{ "question": "降伏", "answers": [ "こうふく" ], "comment": "(n) capitulation/surrender/submission" },
		{ "question": "降水", "answers": [ "こうすい" ], "comment": "(n) rainfall/precipitation" },
		{ "question": "限り", "answers": [ "かぎり" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n) limit(s)/as far as possible/as much as possible/to the best of one's ability" },
		{ "question": "限る", "answers": [ "かぎる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to restrict/to limit/to confine" },
		{ "question": "限定", "answers": [ "げんてい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) limit/restriction" },
		{ "question": "限度", "answers": [ "げんど" ], "comment": "(n) limit/bounds" },
		{ "question": "限界", "answers": [ "げんかい" ], "comment": "(n) limit/bound" },
		{ "question": "陣", "answers": [ "じん" ], "comment": "(n) battle formation/camp/encampment" },
		{ "question": "除く", "answers": [ "のぞく" ], "comment": "(v5k) to remove/to exclude/to except" },
		{ "question": "除外", "answers": [ "じょがい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) exception/exclusion" },
		{ "question": "陰", "answers": [ "かげ" ], "comment": "(n) shade/shadow/other side" },
		{ "question": "陰気", "answers": [ "いんき" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) gloom/melancholy" },
		{ "question": "陳列", "answers": [ "ちんれつ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) exhibition/display/show" },
		{ "question": "陶器", "answers": [ "とうき" ], "comment": "(n) pottery/ceramics" },
		{ "question": "陸", "answers": [ "りく" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) six (used in legal documents)" },
		{ "question": "険しい", "answers": [ "けわしい" ], "comment": "(adj) inaccessible place/impregnable position/steep place/sharp eyes" },
		{ "question": "陽射", "answers": [ "ひざし" ], "comment": "(n) sunlight/rays of the sun" },
		{ "question": "陽気", "answers": [ "ようき" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) season/weather/cheerfulness" },
		{ "question": "隅", "answers": [ "すみ" ], "comment": "(n,n-suf) corner/nook" },
		{ "question": "隊", "answers": [ "たい" ], "comment": "(n) party/company/body (of troops)/corps" },
		{ "question": "階層", "answers": [ "かいそう" ], "comment": "(n) class/level/stratum/hierarchy" },
		{ "question": "階段", "answers": [ "かいだん" ], "comment": "(n) stairs" },
		{ "question": "階級", "answers": [ "かいきゅう" ], "comment": "(n) class/rank/grade" },
		{ "question": "随分", "answers": [ "ずいぶん" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n-adv) extremely" },
		{ "question": "随筆", "answers": [ "ずいひつ" ], "comment": "(n) essays/miscellaneous writings" },
		{ "question": "隔たる", "answers": [ "へだたる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to be distant" },
		{ "question": "隔てる", "answers": [ "へだてる" ], "comment": "(v1) to be shut out" },
		{ "question": "隔週", "answers": [ "かくしゅう" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n-t) every other week" },
		{ "question": "隙", "answers": [ "すき" ], "comment": "(n) (1) chance or opportunity/chink (in one's armor)/(2) interval/gap" },
		{ "question": "隙間", "answers": [ "すきま" ], "comment": "(n) crevice/crack/gap/opening" },
		{ "question": "際", "answers": [ "さい" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n) on the occasion of/circumstances" },
		{ "question": "障る", "answers": [ "さわる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to hinder/to interfere with/to affect/to do one harm/to be harmful to" },
		{ "question": "障子", "answers": [ "しょうじ" ], "comment": "(n) paper sliding door" },
		{ "question": "障害", "answers": [ "しょうがい" ], "comment": "(n) obstacle/impediment (fault)/damage" },
		{ "question": "隠す", "answers": [ "かくす" ], "comment": "(v5s,vt) to hide/to conceal" },
		{ "question": "隠れる", "answers": [ "かくれる" ], "comment": "(v1,vi) to hide/to be hidden/to conceal oneself/to disappear" },
		{ "question": "隠居", "answers": [ "いんきょ" ], "comment": "(n) (1) retirement/(2) retired person" },
		{ "question": "隣", "answers": [ "となり" ], "comment": "(n) next to/next door to" },
		{ "question": "雄", "answers": [ "おす" ], "comment": "(n) male (animal)" },
		{ "question": "集まり", "answers": [ "あつまり" ], "comment": "(n) gathering/meeting/assembly/collection" },
		{ "question": "集める", "answers": [ "あつめる" ], "comment": "(v1,vt) to collect/to assemble" },
		{ "question": "集る", "answers": [ "あつまる" ], "comment": "(v5r) (1) to gather/to crowd round/to swarm/to flock/(2) to extort from/to sponge off" },
		{ "question": "集中", "answers": [ "しゅうちゅう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) concentration/focusing the mind" },
		{ "question": "集会", "answers": [ "しゅうかい" ], "comment": "(n) meeting/assembly" },
		{ "question": "集合", "answers": [ "しゅうごう" ], "comment": "(n,vs) gathering/assembly/meeting/set (math)" },
		{ "question": "集団", "answers": [ "しゅうだん" ], "comment": "(n) group/mass" },
		{ "question": "集計", "answers": [ "しゅうけい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) totalization/aggregate" },
		{ "question": "集金", "answers": [ "しゅうきん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) money collection" },
		{ "question": "雇う", "answers": [ "やとう" ], "comment": "(v5u) to employ/to hire" },
		{ "question": "雌", "answers": [ "めす" ], "comment": "(n) female (animal)" },
		{ "question": "雑", "answers": [ "ざつ" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) rough/crude" },
		{ "question": "雑巾", "answers": [ "ぞうきん" ], "comment": "(n) house-cloth/dust cloth" },
		{ "question": "雑木", "answers": [ "ぞうき" ], "comment": "(n) various kinds of small trees/assorted trees" },
		{ "question": "雑誌", "answers": [ "ざっし" ], "comment": "(n) journal/magazine" },
		{ "question": "雑談", "answers": [ "ざつだん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) chatting/idle talk" },
		{ "question": "雑貨", "answers": [ "ざっか" ], "comment": "(n) miscellaneous goods/general goods/sundries" },
		{ "question": "雑音", "answers": [ "ざつおん" ], "comment": "(n) noise (jarring, grating)" },
		{ "question": "雛", "answers": [ "ひな" ], "comment": "(n) young bird/chick/doll" },
		{ "question": "雛祭", "answers": [ "ひなまつり" ], "comment": "(n) Girls' (dolls') Festival" },
		{ "question": "離す", "answers": [ "はなす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to part/divide/separate" },
		{ "question": "離れる", "answers": [ "はなれる" ], "comment": "(v1) to be separated from/to leave/to go away/to be a long way off" },
		{ "question": "離婚", "answers": [ "りこん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) divorce" },
		{ "question": "難", "answers": [ "なん" ], "comment": "(n,n-suf) difficulty/hardships/defect" },
		{ "question": "難しい", "answers": [ "むずかしい" ], "comment": "(adj) difficult" },
		{ "question": "雨", "answers": [ "あめ" ], "comment": "(n) rain" },
		{ "question": "雨具", "answers": [ "あまぐ" ], "comment": "(n) rain gear" },
		{ "question": "雨天", "answers": [ "うてん" ], "comment": "(n) rainy weather" },
		{ "question": "雨戸", "answers": [ "あまど" ], "comment": "(n) sliding storm door" },
		{ "question": "雪", "answers": [ "ゆき" ], "comment": "(n) snow" },
		{ "question": "雪崩", "answers": [ "なだれ" ], "comment": "(n) avalanche" },
		{ "question": "雫", "answers": [ "しずく" ], "comment": "(n) drop (of water)" },
		{ "question": "雰囲気", "answers": [ "ふんいき" ], "comment": "(n) atmosphere (e.g. musical)/mood/ambience" },
		{ "question": "雲", "answers": [ "くも" ], "comment": "(n) cloud" },
		{ "question": "零", "answers": [ "れい" ], "comment": "(n) zero/nought" },
		{ "question": "零点", "answers": [ "れいてん" ], "comment": "(n) zero/no marks" },
		{ "question": "雷", "answers": [ "かみなり" ], "comment": "(n) thunder" },
		{ "question": "電力", "answers": [ "でんりょく" ], "comment": "(n) electric power" },
		{ "question": "電報", "answers": [ "でんぽう" ], "comment": "(n) telegram" },
		{ "question": "電子", "answers": [ "でんし" ], "comment": "(n) electron" },
		{ "question": "電柱", "answers": [ "でんちゅう" ], "comment": "(n) telephone pole/telegraph pole/lightpole" },
		{ "question": "電気", "answers": [ "でんき" ], "comment": "(n) electricity/(electric) light" },
		{ "question": "電池", "answers": [ "でんち" ], "comment": "(n) battery" },
		{ "question": "電波", "answers": [ "でんぱ" ], "comment": "(n) electro-magnetic wave" },
		{ "question": "電流", "answers": [ "でんりゅう" ], "comment": "(n) electric current" },
		{ "question": "電源", "answers": [ "でんげん" ], "comment": "(n) source of electricity/power (button on TV, etc.)" },
		{ "question": "電灯", "answers": [ "でんとう" ], "comment": "(n) electric light" },
		{ "question": "電球", "answers": [ "でんきゅう" ], "comment": "(n) light bulb" },
		{ "question": "電話", "answers": [ "でんわ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) telephone" },
		{ "question": "電車", "answers": [ "でんしゃ" ], "comment": "(n) electric train" },
		{ "question": "需要", "answers": [ "じゅよう" ], "comment": "(n) demand/request" },
		{ "question": "震える", "answers": [ "ふるえる" ], "comment": "(v1) to shiver/to shake/to quake" },
		{ "question": "震わせる", "answers": [ "ふるわせる" ], "comment": "(v1) to be shaking/to be trembling" },
		{ "question": "霜", "answers": [ "しも" ], "comment": "(n) frost" },
		{ "question": "霞む", "answers": [ "かすむ" ], "comment": "(v5m) to grow hazy/to be misty" },
		{ "question": "霧", "answers": [ "きり" ], "comment": "(n) fog/mist" },
		{ "question": "霰", "answers": [ "あられ" ], "comment": "(n) hail (i.e. falling iceballs)" },
		{ "question": "露", "answers": [ "つゆ" ], "comment": "(adv,n) dew" },
		{ "question": "露骨", "answers": [ "ろこつ" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) (1) frank/blunt/plain/outspoken/(2) conspicuous/open/(3) broad/suggestive" },
		{ "question": "青", "answers": [ "あお" ], "comment": "(n) blue/green/green light" },
		{ "question": "青い", "answers": [ "あおい" ], "comment": "(adj) blue/pale/green/unripe/inexperienced" },
		{ "question": "青少年", "answers": [ "せいしょうねん" ], "comment": "(n) youth/young person" },
		{ "question": "青年", "answers": [ "せいねん" ], "comment": "(n) youth/young man" },
		{ "question": "青春", "answers": [ "せいしゅん" ], "comment": "(adj-no,n) youth/springtime of life/adolescent" },
		{ "question": "青白い", "answers": [ "あおじろい" ], "comment": "(adj) pale/pallid" },
		{ "question": "静か", "answers": [ "しずか" ], "comment": "(adj-na) quiet/peaceful" },
		{ "question": "静まる", "answers": [ "しずまる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to quieten down/to calm down/to subside/to die down/to abate/to be suppressed" },
		{ "question": "静止", "answers": [ "せいし" ], "comment": "(n) stillness/repose/standing still" },
		{ "question": "静的", "answers": [ "せいてき" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) static" },
		{ "question": "非常", "answers": [ "ひじょう" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) emergency/extraordinary/unusual" },
		{ "question": "非常に", "answers": [ "ひじょうに" ], "comment": "(adv) very/extremely/exceedingly" },
		{ "question": "非行", "answers": [ "ひこう" ], "comment": "(n) delinquency/misconduct" },
		{ "question": "非難", "answers": [ "ひなん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) blame/attack/criticism" },
		{ "question": "面", "answers": [ "めん" ], "comment": "(n,n-suf) face/mug/surface/facial features/mask/face guard/side or facet/corner/page" },
		{ "question": "面する", "answers": [ "めんする" ], "comment": "(vs-s) to face on/to look out on to" },
		{ "question": "面会", "answers": [ "めんかい" ], "comment": "(n) interview" },
		{ "question": "面倒", "answers": [ "めんどう" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) trouble/difficulty/care/attention" },
		{ "question": "面倒臭い", "answers": [ "めんどうくさい" ], "comment": "(adj) bother to do/tiresome" },
		{ "question": "面接", "answers": [ "めんせつ" ], "comment": "(n) interview" },
		{ "question": "面目", "answers": [ "めんぼく","（めんもく）" ], "comment": "(n) face/honour/reputation/prestige/dignity/credit" },
		{ "question": "面積", "answers": [ "めんせき" ], "comment": "(n) area" },
		{ "question": "革", "answers": [ "かわ" ], "comment": "(n) leather" },
		{ "question": "革命", "answers": [ "かくめい" ], "comment": "(n) revolution" },
		{ "question": "革新", "answers": [ "かくしん" ], "comment": "(n) reform/innovation" },
		{ "question": "靴", "answers": [ "くつ" ], "comment": "(n) shoes/footwear" },
		{ "question": "靴下", "answers": [ "くつした" ], "comment": "(n) socks" },
		{ "question": "鞠", "answers": [ "まり" ], "comment": "(n) ball" },
		{ "question": "音", "answers": [ "おと","おん","ね" ], "comment": "(n,n-suf) sound/note" },
		{ "question": "音楽", "answers": [ "おんがく" ], "comment": "(n) music/musical movement" },
		{ "question": "音色", "answers": [ "ねいろ" ], "comment": "(n) tone color/tone quality/timbre/synthesizer patch" },
		{ "question": "響き", "answers": [ "ひびき" ], "comment": "(n) echo/sound/reverberation/noise" },
		{ "question": "響く", "answers": [ "ひびく" ], "comment": "(v5k) to resound" },
		{ "question": "頂く", "answers": [ "いただく" ], "comment": "(v5k) to receive/to take food or drink (hum)/to be crowned with/to wear/to live under (a ruler)/to install (a president)/to accept/to buy/to take" },
		{ "question": "頂上", "answers": [ "ちょうじょう" ], "comment": "(n) top/summit/peak" },
		{ "question": "頂点", "answers": [ "ちょうてん" ], "comment": "(n) top/summit" },
		{ "question": "頃", "answers": [ "ころ" ], "comment": "(n-adv,n,n-suf) (uk) time/about/toward/approximately (time)" },
		{ "question": "項目", "answers": [ "こうもく" ], "comment": "(n) item" },
		{ "question": "順", "answers": [ "じゅん" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n,n-suf) order/turn" },
		{ "question": "順々", "answers": [ "じゅんじゅん" ], "comment": "(adv,n) in order/in turn" },
		{ "question": "順序", "answers": [ "じゅんじょ" ], "comment": "(n) order/sequence/procedure" },
		{ "question": "順番", "answers": [ "じゅんばん" ], "comment": "(n) turn (in line)/order of things" },
		{ "question": "順調", "answers": [ "じゅんちょう" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) favourable/doing well/O.K./all right" },
		{ "question": "預かる", "answers": [ "あずかる" ], "comment": "(v5r,vt) to keep in custody/to receive on deposit/to take charge of" },
		{ "question": "預ける", "answers": [ "あずける" ], "comment": "(v1,vt) to give into custody/to leave (a child) in the care of/to entrust/to deposit" },
		{ "question": "預金", "answers": [ "よきん" ], "comment": "(n,vs) deposit/bank account" },
		{ "question": "頑丈", "answers": [ "がんじょう" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) solid/firm/stout/burly/strong/sturdy" },
		{ "question": "頑固", "answers": [ "がんこ" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) stubbornness/obstinacy" },
		{ "question": "頑張る", "answers": [ "がんばる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to persist/to insist on/to stand firm/to try one's best" },
		{ "question": "領事", "answers": [ "りょうじ" ], "comment": "(n) consul" },
		{ "question": "領収", "answers": [ "りょうしゅう" ], "comment": "(n) receipt/voucher" },
		{ "question": "領土", "answers": [ "りょうど" ], "comment": "(n) dominion/territory/possession" },
		{ "question": "領地", "answers": [ "りょうち" ], "comment": "(n) territory/dominion" },
		{ "question": "領域", "answers": [ "りょういき" ], "comment": "(n) area/domain/territory/field/region/regime" },
		{ "question": "領海", "answers": [ "りょうかい" ], "comment": "(n) territorial waters" },
		{ "question": "頬", "answers": [ "ほお","ほほ" ], "comment": "(n) cheek (of face)" },
		{ "question": "頭", "answers": [ "あたま","かしら" ], "comment": "counter for large animals" },
		{ "question": "頭痛", "answers": [ "ずつう" ], "comment": "(n) headache" },
		{ "question": "頭脳", "answers": [ "ずのう" ], "comment": "(n) head/brains/intellect" },
		{ "question": "頻繁", "answers": [ "ひんぱん" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) frequency" },
		{ "question": "頼む", "answers": [ "たのむ" ], "comment": "(v5m) to request/to beg/to ask" },
		{ "question": "頼もしい", "answers": [ "たのもしい" ], "comment": "(adj) reliable/trustworthy/hopeful/promising" },
		{ "question": "頼る", "answers": [ "たよる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to rely on/to have recourse to/to depend on" },
		{ "question": "題", "answers": [ "だい" ], "comment": "(n,vs) title/subject/theme/topic" },
		{ "question": "題名", "answers": [ "だいめい" ], "comment": "(n) title" },
		{ "question": "額", "answers": [ "がく","ひたい" ], "comment": "(n) forehead/brow" },
		{ "question": "顎", "answers": [ "あご" ], "comment": "(n) chin" },
		{ "question": "顔", "answers": [ "かお" ], "comment": "(n) face (person)" },
		{ "question": "顔付き", "answers": [ "かおつき" ], "comment": "(n) (outward) looks/features/face/countenance/expression" },
		{ "question": "顕微鏡", "answers": [ "けんびきょう" ], "comment": "(n) microscope" },
		{ "question": "願い", "answers": [ "ねがい" ], "comment": "(n) desire/wish/request/prayer/petition/application" },
		{ "question": "願う", "answers": [ "ねがう" ], "comment": "(v5u) to desire/to wish/to request/to beg/to hope/to implore" },
		{ "question": "願書", "answers": [ "がんしょ" ], "comment": "(n) written application or petition" },
		{ "question": "類", "answers": [ "るい" ], "comment": "(n,n-suf) kind/sort/class/family/genus" },
		{ "question": "類似", "answers": [ "るいじ" ], "comment": "(n) analogous" },
		{ "question": "類推", "answers": [ "るいすい" ], "comment": "(n) analogy" },
		{ "question": "顧みる", "answers": [ "かえりみる" ], "comment": "(v1) to look back/to turn around/to review" },
		{ "question": "風", "answers": [ "かぜ" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n,n-suf) method/manner/way" },
		{ "question": "風俗", "answers": [ "ふうぞく" ], "comment": "(n) (1) manners/customs/(2) sex service/sex industry" },
		{ "question": "風呂", "answers": [ "ふろ" ], "comment": "(n) bath" },
		{ "question": "風呂敷", "answers": [ "ふろしき" ], "comment": "(n) wrapping cloth/cloth wrapper" },
		{ "question": "風土", "answers": [ "ふうど" ], "comment": "(n) natural features/topography/climate/spiritual features" },
		{ "question": "風景", "answers": [ "ふうけい" ], "comment": "(n) scenery" },
		{ "question": "風習", "answers": [ "ふうしゅう" ], "comment": "(n) custom" },
		{ "question": "風船", "answers": [ "ふうせん" ], "comment": "(n) balloon" },
		{ "question": "風車", "answers": [ "ふうしゃ" ], "comment": "(n) (1) windmill" },
		{ "question": "風邪", "answers": [ "かぜ" ], "comment": "(n) cold (illness)/common cold" },
		{ "question": "飛ばす", "answers": [ "とばす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to skip over/to omit" },
		{ "question": "飛び出す", "answers": [ "とびだす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to jump out/to rush out/to fly out/to appear suddenly/to protrude/to project" },
		{ "question": "飛び込む", "answers": [ "とびこむ" ], "comment": "(v5m) to jump in/to leap in/to plunge into/to dive" },
		{ "question": "飛ぶ", "answers": [ "とぶ" ], "comment": "(v5b) to jump/to fly/to leap/to spring/to bound/to hop" },
		{ "question": "飛行", "answers": [ "ひこう" ], "comment": "(n) aviation" },
		{ "question": "飛行場", "answers": [ "ひこうじょう" ], "comment": "(n) airport" },
		{ "question": "飛行機", "answers": [ "ひこうき" ], "comment": "(n) aeroplane" },
		{ "question": "食い違う", "answers": [ "くいちがう" ], "comment": "(v5u) to cross each other/to run counter to/to differ/to clash/to go awry" },
		{ "question": "食う", "answers": [ "くう" ], "comment": "(v5u) (male) (vulg) to eat" },
		{ "question": "食べる", "answers": [ "たべる" ], "comment": "(v1) to eat" },
		{ "question": "食べ物", "answers": [ "たべもの" ], "comment": "(n) food" },
		{ "question": "食事", "answers": [ "しょくじ" ], "comment": "(n,vs) meal" },
		{ "question": "食卓", "answers": [ "しょくたく" ], "comment": "(n) dining table" },
		{ "question": "食品", "answers": [ "しょくひん" ], "comment": "(n) commodity/foodstuff" },
		{ "question": "食器", "answers": [ "しょっき" ], "comment": "(n) tableware" },
		{ "question": "食堂", "answers": [ "しょくどう" ], "comment": "(n) cafeteria/dining hall" },
		{ "question": "食塩", "answers": [ "しょくえん" ], "comment": "(n) table salt" },
		{ "question": "食料", "answers": [ "しょくりょう" ], "comment": "(n) food" },
		{ "question": "食料品", "answers": [ "しょくりょうひん" ], "comment": "(n) foodstuff/groceries" },
		{ "question": "食欲", "answers": [ "しょくよく" ], "comment": "(n) appetite (for food)" },
		{ "question": "食物", "answers": [ "しょくもつ" ], "comment": "(n) food/foodstuff" },
		{ "question": "食糧", "answers": [ "しょくりょう" ], "comment": "(n) provisions/rations" },
		{ "question": "飢える", "answers": [ "うえる" ], "comment": "(v1) to starve" },
		{ "question": "飢饉", "answers": [ "ききん" ], "comment": "(n) famine" },
		{ "question": "飯", "answers": [ "めし" ], "comment": "(n) (sl) meals/food" },
		{ "question": "飲み物", "answers": [ "のみもの" ], "comment": "(n) drink/beverage" },
		{ "question": "飲み込む", "answers": [ "のみこむ" ], "comment": "(v5m) to gulp down/to swallow deeply/to understand/to take in/to catch on to/to learn/to digest" },
		{ "question": "飲む", "answers": [ "のむ" ], "comment": "(v5m) to drink" },
		{ "question": "飴", "answers": [ "あめ" ], "comment": "(n) (hard) candy" },
		{ "question": "飼う", "answers": [ "かう" ], "comment": "(v5u) to keep/to raise/to feed" },
		{ "question": "飼育", "answers": [ "しいく" ], "comment": "(n,vs) breeding/raising/rearing" },
		{ "question": "飽きる", "answers": [ "あきる" ], "comment": "(v1) to get tired of/to lose interest in/to have enough" },
		{ "question": "飽和", "answers": [ "ほうわ" ], "comment": "(n) saturation" },
		{ "question": "飾り", "answers": [ "かざり" ], "comment": "(n,n-suf) decoration" },
		{ "question": "飾る", "answers": [ "かざる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to decorate/to ornament/to adorn" },
		{ "question": "餅", "answers": [ "もち" ], "comment": "(n) (uk) sticky rice cake" },
		{ "question": "養う", "answers": [ "やしなう" ], "comment": "(v5u) to rear/to maintain/to cultivate" },
		{ "question": "養分", "answers": [ "ようぶん" ], "comment": "(n) nourishment/nutrient" },
		{ "question": "養護", "answers": [ "ようご" ], "comment": "(n,vs) protection/nursing/protective care" },
		{ "question": "餌", "answers": [ "えさ" ], "comment": "(n) feed/bait" },
		{ "question": "首", "answers": [ "くび" ], "comment": "(n) neck" },
		{ "question": "首相", "answers": [ "しゅしょう" ], "comment": "(n) Prime Minister" },
		{ "question": "首脳", "answers": [ "しゅのう" ], "comment": "(n) head/brains" },
		{ "question": "首輪", "answers": [ "くびわ" ], "comment": "(n) necklace/choker" },
		{ "question": "首都", "answers": [ "しゅと" ], "comment": "(n) capital city" },
		{ "question": "首飾り", "answers": [ "くびかざり" ], "comment": "(n) necklace" },
		{ "question": "香り", "answers": [ "かおり" ], "comment": "(n) aroma/fragrance/scent/smell" },
		{ "question": "香水", "answers": [ "こうすい" ], "comment": "(n) perfume" },
		{ "question": "香辛料", "answers": [ "こうしんりょう" ], "comment": "(n) spices" },
		{ "question": "馬", "answers": [ "うま" ], "comment": "(n) (1) horse/(2) promoted bishop (shogi)" },
		{ "question": "馬鹿", "answers": [ "ばか" ], "comment": "(adj-na,exp,n) fool/idiot/trivial matter/folly" },
		{ "question": "馴らす", "answers": [ "ならす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to domesticate/to tame" },
		{ "question": "馴れる", "answers": [ "なれる" ], "comment": "(v1) to become domesticated/to become tame/to get too familiar with" },
		{ "question": "駄作", "answers": [ "ださく" ], "comment": "(n) poor work/rubbish" },
		{ "question": "駄目", "answers": [ "だめ" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) useless/no good/hopeless" },
		{ "question": "駅", "answers": [ "えき" ], "comment": "(n) station" },
		{ "question": "駆ける", "answers": [ "かける" ], "comment": "(v1) to run (race, esp. horse)/to gallop/to canter" },
		{ "question": "駆け足", "answers": [ "かけあし" ], "comment": "(n) running fast/double time" },
		{ "question": "駐車", "answers": [ "ちゅうしゃ" ], "comment": "(n) parking (e.g. car)" },
		{ "question": "駐車場", "answers": [ "ちゅうしゃじょう" ], "comment": "(n) parking lot/parking place" },
		{ "question": "騒々しい", "answers": [ "そうぞうしい" ], "comment": "(adj) noisy/boisterous" },
		{ "question": "騒がしい", "answers": [ "さわがしい" ], "comment": "(adj) noisy" },
		{ "question": "騒ぎ", "answers": [ "さわぎ" ], "comment": "(n,n-suf) uproar/disturbance" },
		{ "question": "騒ぐ", "answers": [ "さわぐ" ], "comment": "(v5g) to make noise/to clamor/to be excited/to be alarmed/to kick up a fuss/to make merry/to be annoying/to be troublesome/to make a noise" },
		{ "question": "騒動", "answers": [ "そうどう" ], "comment": "(n) strife/riot/rebellion" },
		{ "question": "騒音", "answers": [ "そうおん" ], "comment": "(n) noise" },
		{ "question": "驚かす", "answers": [ "おどろかす" ], "comment": "(v5s) to surprise/to frighten/to create a stir" },
		{ "question": "驚き", "answers": [ "おどろき" ], "comment": "(n) surprise/astonishment/wonder" },
		{ "question": "驚く", "answers": [ "おどろく" ], "comment": "(v5k) to be surprised/to be astonished" },
		{ "question": "驚異", "answers": [ "きょうい" ], "comment": "(n) wonder/miracle" },
		{ "question": "骨", "answers": [ "ほね" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) bone" },
		{ "question": "骨折", "answers": [ "こっせつ" ], "comment": "(n) bone fracture" },
		{ "question": "骨董品", "answers": [ "こっとうひん" ], "comment": "(n) curio" },
		{ "question": "高い", "answers": [ "たかい" ], "comment": "(adj) tall/high/expensive" },
		{ "question": "高まる", "answers": [ "たかまる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to rise/to swell/to be promoted" },
		{ "question": "高める", "answers": [ "たかめる" ], "comment": "(v1) to raise/to lift/to boost" },
		{ "question": "高価", "answers": [ "こうか" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) high price" },
		{ "question": "高原", "answers": [ "こうげん" ], "comment": "(n) tableland/plateau" },
		{ "question": "高尚", "answers": [ "こうしょう" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) high/noble/refined/advanced" },
		{ "question": "高層", "answers": [ "こうそう" ], "comment": "(n) upper" },
		{ "question": "高度", "answers": [ "こうど" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) altitude/height/advanced" },
		{ "question": "高校", "answers": [ "こうこう" ], "comment": "(n) senior high school" },
		{ "question": "高校生", "answers": [ "こうこうせい" ], "comment": "(n) senior high school student" },
		{ "question": "高等", "answers": [ "こうとう" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) high class/high grade" },
		{ "question": "高等学校", "answers": [ "こうとうがっこう" ], "comment": "senior high school" },
		{ "question": "高級", "answers": [ "こうきゅう" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) high class/high grade" },
		{ "question": "高速", "answers": [ "こうそく" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) high speed/high gear" },
		{ "question": "髪", "answers": [ "かみ" ], "comment": "(n) hair" },
		{ "question": "髪の毛", "answers": [ "かみのけ" ], "comment": "(n) hair (head)" },
		{ "question": "髭", "answers": [ "ひげ" ], "comment": "(n) moustache/beard/whiskers" },
		{ "question": "鬼", "answers": [ "おに" ], "comment": "(n) ogre/demon/'it' (i.e., in a game of tag)" },
		{ "question": "魂", "answers": [ "たましい" ], "comment": "(n) soul/spirit" },
		{ "question": "魅力", "answers": [ "みりょく" ], "comment": "(n) charm/fascination/glamour" },
		{ "question": "魚", "answers": [ "うお","さかな" ], "comment": "(n) fish" },
		{ "question": "鮮やか", "answers": [ "あざやか" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) vivid/clear/brilliant" },
		{ "question": "鳥", "answers": [ "とり" ], "comment": "(n) bird/fowl/poultry" },
		{ "question": "鳥居", "answers": [ "とりい" ], "comment": "(n) torii (Shinto shrine archway)" },
		{ "question": "鳥肉", "answers": [ "とりにく" ], "comment": "(n) chicken meat" },
		{ "question": "鳴く", "answers": [ "なく" ], "comment": "(v5k) to bark/to purr/to make sound (animal)" },
		{ "question": "鳴らす", "answers": [ "ならす" ], "comment": "(v5s,vt) to ring/to sound/to chime/to beat/to snort (nose)" },
		{ "question": "鳴る", "answers": [ "なる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to sound/to ring/to resound/to echo/to roar/to rumble" },
		{ "question": "麓", "answers": [ "ふもと" ], "comment": "(n) the foot/the bottom/the base (of a mountain)" },
		{ "question": "麻", "answers": [ "あさ" ], "comment": "(n) flax/linen/hemp" },
		{ "question": "麻痺", "answers": [ "まひ" ], "comment": "(n) paralysis/palsy/numbness/stupor" },
		{ "question": "麻酔", "answers": [ "ますい" ], "comment": "(n) anaesthesia" },
		{ "question": "黄色", "answers": [ "きいろ" ], "comment": "(adj-na,n) yellow" },
		{ "question": "黄色い", "answers": [ "きいろい" ], "comment": "(adj) yellow" },
		{ "question": "黄金", "answers": [ "おうごん" ], "comment": "(adj-no,n) gold" },
		{ "question": "黒", "answers": [ "くろ" ], "comment": "(n) (1) black/(2) dark" },
		{ "question": "黒い", "answers": [ "くろい" ], "comment": "(adj) (1) black/(2) dark" },
		{ "question": "黒字", "answers": [ "くろじ" ], "comment": "(n) balance (figure) in the black" },
		{ "question": "黒板", "answers": [ "こくばん" ], "comment": "(n) blackboard" },
		{ "question": "黙る", "answers": [ "だまる" ], "comment": "(v5r) to be silent" },
		{ "question": "黴菌", "answers": [ "ばいきん" ], "comment": "(n) bacteria/germ(s)" },
		{ "question": "鼠", "answers": [ "ねずみ" ], "comment": "(n) (1) mouse/rat/(2) dark gray/slate color" },
		{ "question": "鼻", "answers": [ "はな" ], "comment": "(n) nose" }
	]
}
